A24影业
纽约中央影业
九码半
八码半
- 玛丽安太太 - 是九码半的吗？
- Mrs. Mariann. - You have the nine and a half?
- 是的 可给你找到了 - 太好了
- Yeah, you're a lucky lady. - Oh, I'm excited.
最后一双了 来 露个玉足吧
Last pair. Let me see those beautiful feet.
美国 纽约
右脚还可以吧？
The right foot's all right?
来 用力伸进去
There you go. Get it in there.
- 太小了 - 加油 加油
- They're too tight. - It's okay. All right.
- 这真是九码半？ - 对 九码半
- Are these the nine and a half? - These are the nine and a half, yeah.
- 有大一号的吗？ - 唯独这牌子没有
- Do you have the next size? - No, not in a Kerrybrooke.
所以我不推荐凯步轩
But that's why I don't like Kerrybrooke,
穿他们鞋 跟裹小脚一样
because they fit really small. They're made for dolls or something.
- 太不合脚了 - 好吧 脱下来吧 脱下来吧
- They're too tight. - Okay, take 'em off. Don't worry about it.
- 穿过朝阳吗？ - 没有
- You ever try Vitality? - No.
- 这牌子档次更高 更耐穿 - 稍等一下
- It's a much better model if you want durable leather. - I'll be right with you.
- 打扰了 - 拿来试试吧
- Excuse me. Sorry. - I'll try it.
我要找前几天卖我鞋的 戴眼镜的那位
I bought a pair of shoes here the other day from him, with the glasses.
- 马蒂 - 怎么了？
- Marty. - Yeah?
有位顾客找你 前几天是你卖她鞋吗？
This woman said she bought a pair of shoes from you.
哦 对 是买了那双棕色玛丽珍吧
Oh, yeah. You bought the brown Mary Janes, right?
- 没错 鞋挺好的 - 合脚吗？
- Yeah, I did. They're great. - How do they fit you?
- 我当时穿着就走了 - 好
- I wore them out of the store. - Okay.
- 然后旧鞋就落在这里了 - 旧鞋长什么样？
- So I left my old ones here. - Okay. What did they look like?
拼色高跟鞋 带小翅膀图案
They're two-toned pumps, wingtips.
- 洛伊 有见到那鞋吗？ - 没有
- Lloyd, did you see her shoes? - No.
不会被你们装回我没拿走的鞋盒
Is it possible that you maybe put them in one of the boxes of the other shoes
然后又塞回库房了吧？
that I was trying on and restocked them?
- 好吧... - 要是看见鞋盒 我就能认出来
- Okay. All right. Um... - If I saw the boxes, I'd be able to recognize it.
让我同事来帮您选购好吗？
Do you mind if my colleague helps you out for a second?
洛伊 你帮忙接待一下这位行吗？
Lloyd. Can you help with Mariann here?
没问题 等下
Sure. Sure.
- 走 跟我去仓库 - 谢谢 借过
- Yeah, we'll check the basement. Come. - Thank you. Excuse me.
- 洛伊会拿来朝阳的 - 好吧 我得考虑下价格
- Lloyd's gonna help you. Get the Vitalities. - Okay. I'll think about the price.
- 您先坐会儿 我马上就来 - 好的 谢谢
- I'll be right with you. Let me finish up here. - Okay, thank you.
- 怎么了？ - 嘘
- What? - Shh.
- 是马蒂吧？ - 是 真倒霉
- Marty. - Ah, fuck.
给你看个东西 进来一下
I wanna show you something. Come here.
- 什么？ - 蹲下 赶紧蹲下
- What? - Just get low. Go low.
我干嘛非得蹲着啊
Why do I have to get low?
- 忙吗？ - 马蒂 瞧瞧我给你准备的
- How you doing? - Marty, look what I got for ya.
什么东西？
What is this?
仔细瞧瞧
Check it out.
诺金鞋行
家用鞋履
经久耐穿
诺金鞋行
家用鞋履
经久耐穿
诺金鞋行
家用鞋履
经久耐穿
诺金鞋行
家用鞋履
经久耐穿
诺金鞋行
家用鞋履
经久耐穿
诺金鞋行
家用鞋履
经久耐穿
诺金鞋行
家用鞋履
经久耐穿
诺金鞋行
家用鞋履
经久耐穿
诺金鞋行
家用鞋履
经久耐穿
诺金鞋行
家用鞋履
经久耐穿
诺金鞋行
家用鞋履
经久耐穿
诺金鞋行
家用鞋履
经久耐穿
诺金鞋行
家用鞋履
经久耐穿
诺金鞋行
家用鞋履
经久耐穿
诺金鞋行
家用鞋履
经久耐穿
诺金鞋行
家用鞋履
经久耐穿
诺金鞋行
家用鞋履
经久耐穿
诺金鞋行
家用鞋履
经久耐穿
诺金鞋行
家用鞋履
经久耐穿
诺金鞋行
家用鞋履
经久耐穿
诺金鞋行
家用鞋履
经久耐穿
诺金鞋行
家用鞋履
经久耐穿
诺金鞋行
家用鞋履
经久耐穿
诺金鞋行
家用鞋履
经久耐穿
诺金鞋行
家用鞋履
经久耐穿
诺金鞋行
家用鞋履
经久耐穿
有啥特别的？
What am I looking at?
诺金鞋行
家用鞋履
经久耐穿
诺金鞋行
家用鞋履
经久耐穿
诺金鞋行
家用鞋履
经久耐穿
诺金鞋行
家用鞋履
经久耐穿
诺金鞋行
家用鞋履
经久耐穿
诺金鞋行
家用鞋履
经久耐穿
诺金鞋行
家用鞋履
经久耐穿
诺金鞋行
家用鞋履
经久耐穿
诺金鞋行
家用鞋履
经久耐穿
诺金鞋行
家用鞋履
经久耐穿
诺金鞋行
家用鞋履
经久耐穿
看看背面
Turn it over.
马蒂·毛瑟
管事
- 做管事？ - 对 管事
- Manager? - Manager.
马蒂·毛瑟
管事
得了吧 老默
Come on, Murray.
不管怎样 别告诉洛伊就行
Whatever you do, just don't tell Lloyd about this.
我不是不尊重你 但把话讲明白
Look, I've been very clear with you. I'm not...
这店子你经营得确实不错
trying to be disrespectful. You built something very commendable here.
现在别 别谈这些
I don't wanna-- I don't wanna discuss this now.
别打断我 让我说完
Stop. Stop. Let me say something.
这活确实让我学到不少
It's been good for my soul to see this up close and personal.
- 但我不是来卖鞋的 - 我不想听这些
- But I'm not a shoe salesman. - I don't wanna discuss this.
- 我不是这块料 - 别扯这些 行吗？
- I'm not a shoe salesman. - I don't wanna discuss this, okay?
必须谈 等我飞回来 我就不干了
I do wanna discuss it, 'cause when I'm back from my trip, this is over.
我不可能留在这行
I'm not coming back and doing this.
说到这 工钱现在能结吗 我得去买机票
Speaking of which, can we settle up now? I gotta buy my plane ticket.
打烊再结
We'll settle at closing.
我得趁午休去买票
I wanted to see the travel agent on my lunch break.
你拿到钱肯定不回来了
You'll never come back after your lunch break.
你真把我看成那种人？
That's what you think of me?
- 对 - 你真以为我会跑了不回来吗？
- Yes. - You think I would go and not come back?
对 我说了打烊再结 行吗？
Yes. I said settle at closing, okay?
- 就这样？ - 对 就这样 出去吧
- That's it? - Yeah, that's it. Goodbye.
你可真会疼人
I love you.
- 快点 - 等我一下
- Come on. - Wait. Just wait for me.
- 我本来就...正要去你家的 - 啥？
- I was about... I was about to come to you. - What?
不行 艾勒在家病着呢
No, Ira's home sick.
- 喂喂喂 什么病 别传染给我 - 什么？
- Whoa, whoa, whoa. I can't get sick. - What?
我得去打锦标赛 我可不能病
I got the championships.
不是 他是吃坏肚子了 只是吃坏肚子了
No, it's food poisoning. It's food poisoning.
真想把你塞进行李箱带走
I wish I could hide you in my luggage.
我也好想跟你走
I wanna come with you so bad.
♪ 趁还有机会 跳起来吧 ♪
♪ Let's dance in style, let's dance for a while ♪
♪ 别靠天命 活在当下吧 ♪
♪ Heaven can wait, we're only watching the skies ♪
♪ 盼着好事 也做好最坏打算 ♪
♪ Hoping for the best but expecting the worst ♪
♪ 明天会不会就烟消云散？ ♪
♪ Are you gonna drop the bomb or not? ♪
♪ 要么痛快地死 要么好好活下去 ♪
♪ Let us die young or let us live forever ♪
主演
提莫西·查拉梅
♪ 命靠天定 但我们偏要逆流而上 ♪
♪ We don't have the power but we never say never ♪
♪ 潮来潮去 人生苦短啊 ♪
♪ Sitting in a sandpit, life is a short trip ♪
主演
格温妮斯·帕特洛
♪ 能懂这歌的人 也懂我的伤 ♪
♪ The music's for the sad men ♪
主演
敖德萨·阿锡安
♪ 这场竞赛会怎么收场？ ♪
♪ Can you imagine when this race is won? ♪
♪ 是胜利还是灭亡？ ♪
♪ Turn our golden faces into the sun ♪
主演
凯文·奥利里
♪ 我们唱着赞歌 别无选择 ♪
♪ Praising our leaders, we're getting in tune ♪
♪ 魔鬼弹着舞曲 逼我们起舞 ♪
♪ The music's played by the, the mad man ♪
主演
泰勒·奥康马
♪ 永远年轻 ♪
♪ Forever young ♪
原创译制
蒙太奇字幕组
♪ 我想永远年轻 ♪
♪ I want to be forever young ♪
♪ 谁不想永远活着？ ♪
♪ Do you really want to live forever? ♪
l
♪ 永远永远地活着 ♪
♪ Forever and ever ♪
l
♪ 永远年轻 ♪
♪ Forever young ♪
l
♪ 我想永远年轻 ♪
♪ I want to be forever young ♪
l
♪ 谁不想永远活着？ ♪
♪ Do you really want to live forever? ♪
反手 反手 反手
Backhand. Backhand. Backhand.
正手 正手 正手
Forehand. Forehand. Forehand.
演出
法兰·德瑞雪
反手 反手 反手
Backhand. Backhand. Backhand.
演出
阿贝尔·费拉拉
正手 正手
Forehand. Forehand.
反手 反手
Backhand. Backhand.
演出
艾莫里·科恩
放高球
And lob.
正手
Forehand.
演出
盖札·罗里格
- 马蒂 - 干嘛
- Marty! - What!
- 有电话 - 跟他说我20分钟前就走了
- Phone! - Tell him I left 20 minutes ago!
我才不当你的传声筒 自己去接那该死的电话
I'm not your goddamn messenger! Pick up the goddamn phone!
演出
佩恩·吉列特
我跟不上 沃利 把白衬衫脱了
I can't. Wally, take the white shirt off.
白球配白衬衫 看不清
I can't follow the white ball against the white shirt.
别找借口 孬种才这样找借口
Stop it. You're a fucking sun dodger.
演出
桑德拉·伯恩哈德
我孬种？怎么怕了 怕了？
Oh, yeah? I love you. I love you.
喂
Hello?
我是朱迪
It's Judy.
演出
川口功人
怎么了 朱迪
Hi, Judy.
你妈病得很重
Your mother, she's very sick.
- 真的假的？ - 真的
- Okay, really? - Yes.
她脸色苍白 满嘴胡话
She's gray in the face. She's speaking nonsense.
演出
拉瑞·拉索·斯洛曼
她一直喊你 你得赶快回家一趟
She's asking for you. You should come home.
听上去不行了 你们赶紧叫救护车吧
Sounds really bad. You should probably call an ambulance.
演出
卢克·曼利
谁陪她去啊
Who's gonna go with her?
我不知道 你这么上心 你陪她去呗
Uh, I don't know. You should probably go since you're so invested.
等一下 别挂
Hold on a minute.
他不吃这套
He's not buying it.
跟他说我断气了
Just tell him I stopped breathing!
至尊马蒂
美国制造
绝对不行 太严重了 我不能这么说
Absolutely not. That's ridiculous. I'm not saying that.
至尊马蒂
美国制造
跟他说你正急着送我去医院
Tell him you're taking me to the hospital.
好吧 我得赶紧把她送去急诊
Okay, fine. I'll take her to the emergency room
然后在那儿陪着 天知道要陪多久
and sit there and wait for God knows how long.
你来负责伺候我丈夫 给他喂药
And you can come here and give my husband his medicine
“晚上给他翻身做按摩”
and massage his feet all night long.
“跟他说我晕倒了”
Tell him I passed out.
配乐
丹尼尔·洛帕汀
- “天呐 你妈刚刚昏过去了” - 你好啊 小姑娘
- Oh, my God! Your mother, she just lost consciousness. - Hi, sweetheart.
“你现在赶紧回家”
You've gotta come home now.
谁啊
Hello?
是我 饭马上好
Hi. Just give me a second.
“朱迪 别闹了行吗”
I don't know what you want me to say, Judy.
“我正忙着 连午饭都还没吃呢”
I'm busy. I'm on my lunch break.
“我妈就在你旁边指挥 我都听得见”
I can hear her whispering. She's right there standing next to you.
- “我都说她昏过去了” - “别来烦我了”
- I told you she passed out. - It's annoying me now.
跟谁通话呢？
Who are you talking to?
哦 没人
Oh. I'm not talking to anybody.
朱迪一直占着电话好久了
Judy's just been tying up the line for an hour.
我给你买了点热饭
I got you some broth.
剪辑
罗纳德·布隆斯坦
乔什·萨弗迪
都凉透了
It's ice cold.
- 买饭排了好久 买回来都凉了 - 你都不打草稿？
- Yeah, 'cause the line was really long at the shop. - Oh, yeah?
信不信我现在打电话去核实？
So that's what they'll say if I call down and ask?
你要是觉得我骗你
You don't believe me? You calling me a liar?
你就打电话核实去
Pick up the phone and call them.
- 不过看你怎么打 朱迪在占着电话 - 喔 行
- You're gonna have to get Judy off the phone first. - Oh, okay.
喂 朱迪 把电话给我挂掉
Hey, Judy, get off the phone.
摄影
达吕斯·康第
看 这颗是国际乒联标准球
Okay, this is a normal IATT approved ball.
【国际乒乓球联合会:1926年成立 主管国际乒乓球赛事和规则】
盯紧这颗白球
Try to follow the white ball against the white.
在白背景下挺难的吧
Almost impossible, right?
你眼珠都没动
I don't even see your eyes moving.
要是我穿白衬衫 你连球都看不到
If I'm wearing a white shirt, you can't see the ball.
换颗橙球试试 这是我自个儿想出来的
Now, imagine it with an orange ball, which no one's ever thought of.
看吧 你盯得多牢 瞧他那眼神
See? You're already following it way better. Look at his eyes.
- 看见没？ - 嗯 看见了
- See how his eyes are looking? - Yeah, I see it.
你现在盯得更紧了
You're looking more engaged now.
这就是机遇所在 目前桌球界
So that's what we wanna do. Right now in the world of table tennis,
【桌球:英语中乒乓球亦称“桌上网球” 简称桌球】
为了盯住白球都得穿黑衣
you're obliged to wear black, just so you can follow the white ball.
- 看看这个 这是泰德·贝利 - 他是谁？
- Look at this. That's Ted Bailey. - Who's that?
【桌上网球为正式运动称谓 乒乓球偏休闲用语】
他曾是英国冠军 世界第一
That's ex-number one ranked player in the world right now.
已经被我打败了
He's the British champion. I've already beat him, by the way.
再看这个
Now look at this.
网球界第一杰克·克雷默
That's Jack Kramer, number one tennis player.
【杰克·克雷默:40-50年代著名网球手 推动网球精英化】
- 有啥区别？ - 他穿的是全白
- What's the difference there? - He's wearing all white.
对 一身白 很绅士
He's in all white. It's beautiful.
【50年代网球为绅士运动 桌上网球(乒乓球)尚非主流】
这叫品味 这叫格调 这是卖点
To me, that's luxury. To me, that's class. You could sell that.
马蒂 这种定制球得花不少钱
Marty, a custom ball like that is gonna cost a lot of money.
当然得定制 奇人配奇球
Of course it's custom. It's an original ball for an original guy.
这是至尊马蒂牌 不是平庸马蒂牌
It's the Marty Supreme ball, not the Marty Normal ball.
你算过成本吗？
But what's it gonna cost?
钱不重要 咱别抠门
It doesn't matter the cost. We can't cheap out on this.
花不了多少钱的 加拉尼斯先生
It's gonna be nominal, Mr. Galanis.
你不是老说先花钱才能赚钱吗
You always said we gotta spend money to make money, right?
制片人
提莫西·查拉梅
给我端杯咖啡来
Get me a cup of coffee.
没门 让你秘书去弄
No. Get your secretary to get ya a cup of coffee.
南希忙着呢 你去弄吧
Nancy's busy. Just get me a coffee.
才不 我正像大人那样谈生意
Dad, we're talking like men about business here.
- 我才不给你端咖啡 - 赶紧去给老子端咖啡去
- I'm not getting ya a cup of coffee. - Get me the damn coffee!
制片人
安东尼·卡塔格斯
马蒂 也给你来一杯？
Marty, you want a coffee?
谢谢 不用了 我不碰咖啡因
No, I'm all right. I'm not drinking caffeine.
听着
Listen.
我感谢你和我儿子的这份交情
I appreciate you're friends with my son.
但他不成器
He's limited.
30岁还靠爹吃饭
He's 30 years old. He's still living at home.
没啥名堂
He hasn't done much.
他也不懂做生意 就会乱花钱
And he doesn't know business. He doesn't know the costs.
恕我直言 盖拉尼斯先生 我不觉得他不成器
I don't think he's limited, Mr. Galanis, respectfully.
看看您做生意的本事
I mean, look at your business success.
那是刻在骨子里的 迪翁也有
That's in your DNA, and you passed that through to Dion.
- 只是还没显露出来 - 谁知道呢
- It just hasn't been awoken yet. - I don't know.
我要是没把握
I wouldn't be here trying to involve you in something that I
制片人
伊莱·布什
罗纳德·布隆斯坦
乔什·萨弗迪
我也不会拉您入伙的
didn't fully in my bones believe in.
我很尊重您的钱 说来您可能不信
And I have tremendous respect for your money. I know it's hard to believe,
但这门运动在国外是火得不得了
but I'm telling you, this game, it fills stadiums overseas.
在美国火起来也只是时间问题
And it's only a matter of time before it fills stadiums in the United States too,
到时候我的广告会铺天盖地
before I'm staring at you from the cover of a Wheaties box.
我 我对这行一窍不通
I- I don't know nothing about this business.
确实不通 所以更该信我
No, you don't. That's why you gotta trust me.
下周这个时候 我就是首位赢下英国公开赛的美国人
This time next week, I'll be the first American to ever win the British Open.
编剧
罗纳德·布隆斯坦
乔什·萨弗迪
到时候我就能一路杀到世锦赛 然后拿下世界第一
That'll slide me into the number one ranking for the World Championship.
到时候《生活》和《展望》都会报道
Life magazine's gonna cover it. Look magazine's gonna cover it.
这是板上钉钉的事 《展望》就在捧我 他们都会捧我
They have to. The editor of Look magazine, he loves me. They all love me.
到时候我就是这项运动在美国的唯一代言人
I'm uniquely positioned to be the face of the entire sport in the United States.
导演
乔什·萨弗迪
家庭鞋履
洛伊
Lloyd!
我要打样
I'm closing up.
我知道 我来找我舅
Yeah, I can see that. Just here to see my uncle.
他走了
He left.
走了？你什么意思？不回来了？
He left? What do you mean he left? For the day?
他得带你妈去医院
He had to take your mother to the hospital.
别闹了 她根本没病
For crying out loud. She's not sick.
洛伊 他还欠我工钱 说好了今天结清
Hey, Lloyd, he owes me money. We were supposed to settle up today.
要不是你午休了五个钟头
Well, maybe if you didn't take that five-hour lunch,
- 兴许就能见着他 - 闭嘴吧你
- you would have spoke with him. - Oh, shut up.
- 谁呀 - 吃了什么狗皮膏药 好得挺快的啊
- Hello. - You're sounding a lot better, huh? That happened quick.
我会挺过去的 别指望我靠你
I'll live, no thanks to you!
妈 别扯了 默里舅在你那儿吗？别骗我
Enough, Mom. Are you with Murray? Be honest.
没有 但他好像准备出趟远门
No. I think he left for his trip. Okay?
出哪门子的远门？
His trip? What trip?
他带着埃丝特要去库彻度假村过周末
He's taking Esther to Kutchers for the weekend.
- 这算什么啊 - 只要我一句话 他就会留下
- When this... - But he would have stayed if I asked him to.
你根本没病 妈 他答应给我机票钱的
You're not sick, Mom. He was supposed to give me my money for my flight.
孩子 那事我可不知道
Well, I don't know anything about that, sweetie.
别装蒜 否则我干嘛干这活？
Yes, you do! Why do you think I'm working here?
我就是为了挣那笔钱
I literally only accepted this job for that.
我可比窦娥还冤
I have no idea what you are implying.
- 你知道你在干嘛吗？ - 我在干嘛？
- You know what this is? - What, what is this?
你在毁我 你在毁我前程
This is sabotage. You're sabotaging me.
别扯了 你是在自毁前程
Oh, please. You're sabotaging your own life.
- 那是什么？ - 什么？
- What is that? - What?
你竟然觉得我要抢你？
Are you seriously thinking I'm gonna rob you?
职业反应
Just a reflex.
我要真想抢你 你早死在血泊里了
If I wanted to rob you, you'd be dead. You'd be in a pool of blood.
我是来拿西装的 这是我特地为这趟比赛买的
I came to grab my suit. You know I bought this specifically for my trip?
打小乒乓还要穿西装 真长见识了
Didn't know you need a suit to play ping pong.
【乒乓:1950年代“乒乓”在部分场合带有嘲讽意味】
【从事这项运动常被歧视 被视为不务正业】
我就要老默欠我的那700块
I just want the $700 that Murray owes me.
【约合2026年 8,600美元 6万人民币 26万新台币】
不然呢？
Yeah, or what?
- 不然我就往你腿上来一枪 - 你不敢
- Or I'm gonna shoot you in the leg. - No you're not.
你敢赌吗？
You sure about that?
你要是打我腿 你未来几年都得坐牢
You shoot me in the leg, you'll be spending the next few years in jail.
行 那我就朝你脑门开枪
Okay, I'll shoot you in the head instead.
你没那胆子
You're not gonna do that either.
洛伊 听我说 我只拿走我的那700 绝不多拿
Look, Lloyd, I just want what was promised to me, not a penny more.
回来我会带回十倍奖金
I'm gonna be coming home with ten times that amount in prize money.
睁只眼闭只眼吧 让我拿走欠我的
So just turn the other cheek, let me take what I'm owed,
等我回来给你整整100
and I'll give you an even $100 dollars when I get back.
【约1,230美元 8,600人民币 3.7万新台币】
不干
Not interested.
洛伊 别这样 转过来
Lloyd, come on. Look at me, please.
咱俩都清楚 你巴不得看我卷铺盖走人
We both know you'd love nothing more than to see my ass get canned.
你干这行的劲头比我大千万倍
You're a thousand times more motivated than me to do this job,
可你看看吧
and yet look at this, okay?
看看
Look.
老默给我的 看看背面
Murray gave that to me. Flip it over.
管事 我要当你管事了
Manager. I'm gonna be your boss!
公平吗？我能把你扫地出门
How unfair is that? I could fire you whenever I want.
还能叫你跪着扫地
I could tell you to sweep the floor on your hands and knees.
任我差遣
How about that, okay?
洛伊 我真拿枪指着你
Lloyd, I'm actually pointing a gun at you right now.
真的在威胁你
I'm actually threatening to use it.
这是实打实的抢劫 枪上有我的指纹
This is a legit robbery like any other. My fingerprints are all over this thing.
这都是铁证
These are facts.
把钱柜打开 把该我的给我
So open the safe, let me take what I'm owed,
回头你照实跟老默说
and you can call Murray, tell him exactly what happened,
想把我轰走还是告我都随你 行吗？
get me fired, press charges. Whatever you want, okay?
行
Fine.
- 给您 先生 - 谢谢
- Here you go, sir. - Thank you.
♪ 我爱高光时刻 ♪
♪ The time I like is the rush hour ♪
♪ 我爱人群喧嚣 ♪
♪ 'Cause I like the rush ♪
♪ 人群拥挤又吵闹 ♪
♪ The pushing of the people ♪
垃圾
You son of...
♪ 我就沉浸其中 ♪
♪ I like it all so much ♪
♪ 人潮蜂拥涌过来 ♪
♪ Such a mass of motion ♪
♪ 谁晓得要去哪儿 ♪
♪ Do not know where it goes ♪
♪ 我随人群往前走 ♪
♪ I move with the movement ♪
还没有单间吗？
We don't get our own rooms?
英国 伦敦
♪ 尽情享受这感觉 ♪
♪ And I have the touch ♪
这里还冷得要死
It's freezing in here.
现在给我正经点儿 眼睛看这里
I really need you to be serious now. Eyes on me.
巴基斯坦 看这里
Pakistan, I need you to look at me.
日本今年也派队来了？瞧见没？
Wait, Japan brought a team this year? You see that?
是啊 小日本也来了
Yeah. The Japs sent a team.
出境管制呢？
What about the travel ban?
【1952年随盟军移交日本主权 出入境管制开始放宽】
- 肯定解禁了 - 出境管制解除了？
- They must have lifted it. - No more travel ban?
各位 现在把球拍翻过来 露出国旗
Okay, gentlemen, I want you to flip your paddles for me now.
谢谢配合
Thank you very much.
准备 一 二 三
Here we go. One. Two. Three.
♪ 握个手吧 ♪
♪ Shake those hands ♪
别动
Hold it still.
♪ 握个手吧 ♪
♪ Shake those hands ♪
♪ 握手 ♪
♪ Shake hands ♪
第一场
♪ 握手 ♪
♪ Shake hands ♪
马蒂·毛瑟 赛点
Match point, Mauser.
【赛点:率先达到者只需再得一分即可赢下整场比赛】
【1950年代乒乓球普遍采用每局21分制 比赛多为五局三胜】
马蒂·毛瑟 胜出
Match, Mauser.
你给我太多正手机会了 应该逼我打反手
You let me get to my forehand too much. Should've tried to put me in my backhand.
【正手/反手:在乒乓球中正手利于进攻 反手偏防守】
远藤 得分
Point, Endo.
- 几比几了？ - 19比4
- What's the score here? - Nineteen-four.
- 日本人领先？ - 那日本小子在揍烂贝利
- The Japanese guy? - Japanese guy's trashing Bailey.
他手里是什么？那是什么球拍？
What's he using? What's that paddle?
不知道 没人见过
I don't know, mate. No one knows.
没声音
It's silent.
- 静得出奇 - 哇
- Like a ghost! - Wow.
贝利 好好打
Fuck, Bailey.
远藤 得分
Point, Endo.
赛点
Match point.
第三场
还剩两局
Two games.
21比9
21-9.
- 打得好 - 打得好 马蒂
- Great game. - Great game, Marty.
马蒂·毛瑟 胜出
Match, Mauser.
那些在斯德哥尔胜出的人...
The winners of the tournament at Stockholm...
嘿 你是拉姆·塞西吧
Hey. You're Ram Sethi, right?
抱歉 您先等会儿
Sorry, could you hold for a moment?
- 你不介意吧？ - 请说 你有啥事？
- You don't mind? - No. Can I help you with something?
打听个事 你们住在哪家酒店？
I was just curious, where are you staying while you're in town?
- 这关你什么事？ - 没事
- What business is it of yours? - No.
就是随便打听下
I'm just saying, what hotel are you staying at?
国际乒联的官员都住丽兹酒店
All the IATT representatives are stationed at the Ritz.
- 丽兹酒店？别人也这么说 - 对
- At the Ritz? Yeah, that's what I heard. - Yes.
- 就这么定了 你没意见吧？ - 什么就这么定了？
- Do you think that's okay? - I don't know what you're implying.
- 你见过我住的那地方吗？ - 有啥问题吗？
- Have you seen where they put me? - Is it a problem?
客气说 那地方就是个狗窝
Well, with all due respect, sir, it's a dump.
很抱歉没有让你满意
I'm so sorry it doesn't meet your high standards.
我们这儿给所有选手都是统一标准
We offer complimentary housing to all our players, Mr. Mauser.
你是唯一一个来这抱怨的
So far as I know, you're the only one to complain.
你这口气 别把我当普通选手 好吗？
You're talking to me like I'm any player off the street, okay?
我得休息好 才能赢下比赛
I need good rest so I can win the tournament.
你很清楚美国人赢对这项运动的好处
You know perfectly well what an American win will do for the future of the sport.
- 我就是未来桌球的代言人 - 那就向美乒协反映呗
- I'm good for table tennis, Mr. Sethi. - Appeal to the USTTA.
美乒协有用吗？他们整个机构就那俩人
There is no USTTA. The USTTA is two guys and a desk. It doesn't exist.
- 那就不归我管了 - 就归你管
- Well, that's not my problem. - It is your problem.
我要住你住的那家酒店 就这么简单
I wanna stay where you're staying! That's what I need!
您这番言论实在是太失礼了
I am finding this whole exchange really offensive.
- 我失礼？ - 对 您失礼
- You're offended? - I am offended.
你们才失礼呢 让明星选手住狗窝
I'm offended! You're making your star player huddle in a rat's ass!
抱歉刚才被打断了
I'm so sorry for that interruption.
那咱们接着说锡兰和墨西哥的事...
Um, back to Ceylon and Mexico...
- 这酒店真不赖 肯定很贵 - 是啊 确实不错
- This is a nice hotel. Must cost a mint. - Yeah, very nice.
是国际乒联报销的吗？
The IATT covers accommodations?
- 明星选手才有这种待遇 - 是吗？那有多少名啊
- Only for their star players. - Is that right? How many are there?
明星选手？不知道 听说就一个
Star players? I don't know. I haven't seen any others, so one.
进半决赛了 紧张吗？
Any nerves, going into the semis?
紧张？对阵克莱茨基？别闹了
Nerves? Against Kletzki? No. You kidding me?
他曾连续三年夺冠
Well, he's won the tournament for the last three years.
- 他名气可不小 - 我名气也不小
- He's got quite the reputation. - I have quite the reputation.
奥斯维辛集中营都办不到的事 我要办成
Look, I'm gonna do to Kletzki what Auschwitz couldn't.
看我怎么把他灭了
Okay. I'm gonna finish the job.
【奥斯维辛:纳粹设立的集中营 实施种族灭绝】
- 天呐 - 这话有点过了
- Jesus Christ. - A little strong, mate.
没事的 我能说 我也是犹太人
It's all right. I'm Jewish. I can say that.
事实上你想想 我更像是希特勒的大噩梦
In fact, if you think about it, I'm like Hitler's worst nightmare.
此话怎讲？
And why's that?
看看我 我活得好好的
Look at me. I'm here.
还混到了上层 我就是希特勒失败的最终证明
I did it, I'm on top. I'm the ultimate product of Hitler's defeat.
对 把这句话记下来 都记下来
Yeah, write that down. That was good. Write that down.
- 不错 - “希特勒失败的最终证明”
- Nice one. - "Ultimate product of Hitler's defeat."
- 你总是那么自信吗？ -一定把那这句放在我照片下面
- Do you like that confidence? - Put that under a picture of me.
- 来谈谈你的出身吧 - 我的出身？
- Tell us a bit about your background. - My background?
不过说真的 我...我妈死于难产
No, but seriously... My my my mother died in childbirth.
我爸就是个没出息的人 我两岁时他就丢下我走了
My father was a compulsive loser who abandoned me when I was two years old.
我被纽约孤儿院来回折腾
I got stuck in the New York City orphanage system,
到处被赶来赶去
got shuttled from one hellhole to the next.
- 难免有了案底 - 那不是凯·斯通吗？
- Naturally, got in trouble with the law. - Isn't that Kay Stone?
那破事可不能定义我
I don't want any of that to define me.
采访呢 采访呢 看什么呢？
Excuse me. Excuse me. What?
- 看凯·斯通 - 就是她
- It's Kay Stone over there. - That's her.
谁？
Who's that?
三十年代那阵儿的老牌女星
Well, you know, the movie actress. Like, from the 1930s.
- 演《机缘巧合》的那个 - 《机缘巧合》?
- Opportunities. - Opportunities?
- 演得很好 - 是啊 佳片一个
- That was good. - Yeah, yeah. Great movie.
- 还有《黑匣子》 - 我爸特喜欢她
- Black Box. - My dad loved her.
- 是啊 - 没错
- Yeah. - Yeah.
- 她当年很红吗？ - 红透半边天
- She was big? - She was huge.
后来销声匿迹了
Came and went. That's her.
- 好莱坞就是这样 - 真是她
- That's Hollywood, mate. - Yeah. It's her.
确实是她
It is indeed.
还有个什么湖的电影
Something about a lake?
- 《影湖》 - 嗯 那片也不错
- Shadow Lake. - Yeah, that was good.
- 漂亮 - 腿不错
- Pretty. - Great legs.
太漂亮了 太漂亮了
Gorgeous, mate. Gorgeous.
- 她是在看我吗？ - 不是
- Think I have a chance, lads? - No.
她肯定在看毛瑟
I think she's looking Mauser.
好了 下个问题
Next question.
喂
Hello?
- 凯吗？ - 有事吗？
- Kay? - Speaking.
嘿 我是马蒂·毛瑟 我住在皇家套房
Hey, it's Marty Mauser. I'm in the Royal Suite.
我昨天在大堂见过你
I saw you in the lobby yesterday.
怎么了？
Okay.
我们互相看了一眼 当时我在接受采访
Yeah, we made eye contact. I was being interviewed.
- 我不记得了 - 这么说吧
- I don't recall. - Well...
我非常仰慕您
I'm a huge admirer.
那好吧 要是没事我就挂了
Okay. Can I help you with something?
有点事 我刚把客房餐单上每样都点了一份
Maybe. I just ordered one of everything off the room service menu.
我一个人肯定吃不完
There's no way I'll be able to eat it all alone.
我懂了
Ah.
所以你想让我去你房间？
So you'd like me to come up to your room?
- 嗯 没错 - 要不我派我丈夫去吧
- Mm-hmm. Yeah. - Perhaps I should send my husband instead.
好啊 他来这里 我去你那里
Sure. He can come up here, and I'll come down to you.
- 真一套套的 行了 再见 - 等等 我还想再说会儿
- Okay, wonderful. Thank you. Goodbye. - Wait. I wanna keep talking.
说什么？
Why is that?
我从没跟真正的电影明星说过话
Because I've never talked to an actual movie star.
现在你说过了 希望你如愿以偿了
Well, now you have. I hope the experience was all you thought it would be.
我其实也喜欢当焦点
You know, I'm something of a performer too.
- 是吗？ - 是啊 你不信吗？
- Are you? - Yeah. You don't believe me?
我...
I...
你怎么？怎么了嘛？
You... What? What?
你会演戏？
You're a performer?
对 会演 你手边有《每日邮报》吗？
Yeah, I am a performer. You got the Daily Mailin front of you?
还真有 怎么了？
Uh, I do have it. Yes?
好的 那你翻到第12页
Okay. Well, turn to page 12.
等下
Uh...
第12页
Page 12.
好了 看什么？
Okay. What am I looking at here?
看中间 正中间
Down the middle, in the center.
那人是你？
This is you?
对“天选之子” 拍得不错吧？
Yeah, "the chosen one." It's a nice picture, right?
打小乒乓的？
Ping pong?
真是天选之子？
我打的是桌球 来这儿参加英国公开赛
I play table tennis. I'm here competing in the British Open.
真是天选之子？
- 你多大了？ - 我23
- How old are you? - I'm 23.
才23岁
Twenty-three.
嗯
Yeah.
我赌你都说不上来我演过什么吧
I bet you can't name one film I've done.
凭啥这么肯定？
What makes you say that?
因为我在你出生前就不演了
Because I stopped acting before you were born.
- 是吗？有点意思 - 嗯
- Really? That's really interesting. - Mm-hmm.
凯 你拿我的刮胡刀刮腿毛了吗？
Kay, did you use my razor to shave your legs?
- 刀钝了 我都划伤了 - 没拿
- It's dull. I've cut myself. - No.
- 谁在说话？你丈夫？ - 嗯
- Who's that? Your husband? - Mm-hmm.
难不成还有人偷偷溜进来用过它？
I guess someone must've snuck in and chopped wood with it.
- 我正打电话呢 - 天呐
- I'm on the phone. - Holy shit.
- 跟谁打？ - 黛比
- With whom? - Debbie.
- 黛比 - 黛比？
- Debbie. - Debbie?
叫她少管闲事
Tell her to get a life.
- 他走了吗？ - 嗯
- Is he gone? - Mm-hmm.
行
Okay.
那你为啥不演了？说说吧
So, why'd you stop acting? Let's talk about that.
我还有事 我得挂了
You know, I really have to go.
明天来温布利看我打球吧 你肯定会喜欢的
You must miss it, don't you? Come watch me play at Wembley tomorrow.
我...我去不了
I... I can't.
来吧 看看我怎么战胜世界第一
Come on. You can watch me dethrone the number one ranked player in the world.
我没空
I'm not available.
哦哟？你能有什么事？
Oh, yeah? What you got going on?
有个大宣传会 我得陪我丈夫撑场子
Actually, I have a big promotional event to attend to for my husband.
哦 好吧
Oh, okay.
宣传什么？
What's he promoting?
笔
Pens.
- 卖笔？开什么玩笑 - 就是笔
- Pens? Are you serious? - Pens.
- 写字用的笔？ - 对
- Like, writing pens? - Yes.
他就是个卖笔的？
What, like, he's a pen salesman?
你们怎么住得起这种套房？
How can you afford the suite you're in?
他是罗克韦尔墨业的老板
He owns Rockwell Ink.
哦 那好吧...
Oh. Okay. Well...
是的
Yes.
- 我听说过罗克韦尔墨业 - 你肯定知道
- I know Rockwell Ink. - I'm sure you do.
好吧
Okay.
那活动内容是什么？
Well, what's the event?
他请了阿加莎·克里斯蒂去哈查兹书店签名售书
He's hired Agatha Christie to sign books at Hatchards.
【阿加莎·克里斯蒂为英国知名小说家 哈查兹为伦敦老牌书店】
哦 哦
Ooh.
听着就无聊
That sounds really boring.
行了
Okay.
哦 没完没了了
Oh, for God's sake.
- 有完没完？ - 别挂 别挂 问你个事
- What is it? - Don't hang up, don't hang up. Just one question.
你房间是朝街还是朝院子？
Does your room face the street or the courtyard?
不知道
I don't know.
直说 朝街还是院子？
Just answer the question. Is it facing the street or the courtyard?
- 朝院子 - 好
- The courtyard. - Okay.
去窗边看看
I need you to go to the window.
你住几楼？
What floor are you on?
三楼吧
I'm on the third floor, I believe.
三楼 好 正好
Third floor. Okay, perfect.
朝对面看看
Look across the street.
看见对面那开窗 桌上有果盘的屋了吗？
You see the open window with a bowl of fruit on the table?
- 看到了吗？ - 看到了
- You see it? - I do.
看好了 我会让那果盘里凭空多出一个苹果
Here's what's gonna happen. I'm gonna make an apple appear in that bowl.
要是我办到了 你就推掉你那场会
And if I do, you're gonna blow off your little rendezvous
- 不 不 不 - 来看我比赛
- No, no, no. - and come watch me play.
我不会答应任何事
I'm not agreeing to anything, no.
你不用答应 但看好了
You don't have to agree to anything. I'm gonna do it anyway.
看到了 一
Okay? One...
二
two...
三
three.
票我留售票处 你去取
I'll leave a ticket for you at the box office.
半决赛
马蒂·毛瑟 19比5
Mauser. Nineteen to five
马蒂·毛瑟 得分
Point, Mauser.
20比5
Twenty to five.
克莱茨基整场落后两局 零局比二
Kletzki trails Mauser two games to nil.
马蒂·毛瑟 局点兼赛点
Game and match point, Mauser.
【局点兼赛点:表示马蒂再得一分即可赢下整场比赛】
- 咱们找点乐子玩玩 - 好吧
- Let's have a little fun with this one. - Okay.
- 玩出花样来 - 收到
- Have a little fun, all right? - Gotcha.
换克莱茨基发球
Service switches to Kletzki.
克莱茨基 得分
Point, Kletzki.
好的 诸位 谢谢大家 谢谢大家
Very well, gentlemen. Thank you for that. Thank you.
克莱茨基发球 当前局分6比20
Kletzki serves 6-20.
马蒂·毛瑟整场领先两局 两局比零
Mauser leads two games to zero.
又是马蒂·毛瑟的赛点
Match point again for Mr. Mauser.
再次由你发球 克莱茨基
Your service again, Kletzki.
马蒂·毛瑟 得分
Point, Mauser!
马蒂·毛瑟以21比6赢下此局 以三局比零赢下整场比赛
Mauser wins the game and match by 21-6. Three games to nil.
马蒂·毛瑟进入决赛 将对阵日本选手远藤功人
Mauser's on to the finals where he will face Koto Endo of Japan.
菜单
别去看价钱 想吃什么随便点
Get whatever you want. Don't even look at the prices, okay?
菜单
你点什么？
What are you getting?
我就来个威灵顿牛排和鱼子酱拼盘
I'm gonna get the Beef Wellington and the caviar tasting plate
要点就点最贵的
because they're the most expensive items on the menu.
我想再唠叨两句关于巡回表演队的事
Listen, I would like to keep going back a little bit about the Globetrotters.
- 哈林篮球队那事儿？ - 对
- About the Harlem Globetrotters, again? - Yes.
【哈林篮球队:美国巡回表演篮球队 擅长花式竞技与表演】
- 我跟你说过了 我不干 - 为什么？
- I told you, I'm not interested. - Why not?
就是不想干
'Cause I don't wanna do it.
报酬很高
It's great money.
咱们还能环游世界 你不想去威尼斯吗？
And we will travel all over the world. Have you seen Venice?
- 我才不会去当马戏团的中场把戏 - 悉尼呢？
- I don't wanna be doing trick shots for a halftime show - Sydney?
- 观众上厕所时上场 - 巴塞罗那？
- while people are going to the bathroom. - Barcelona?
真丢人 明白吗？
That's beneath me, okay?
- 观众相当捧他们的 - 服务员在哪儿呢？
- They're treated like royalty. - Where's the waiter?
- 我有个熟人干过这行 - 服务员
- Listen, I know people who have done this. - Excuse me.
服务员
Excuse me.
机会难得 咱们得把握住
It's a great opportunity. We should not miss it.
马蒂
Marty.
先生 请问需要帮助吗？
Yes, sir. May I help you, sir?
可以点菜了吗？
Hi. Can we order?
没问题 我马上去叫这桌的服务员来
Of course, sir. Let me fetch your waiter.
- 别走 - 请说
- Hang on. - Yes.
今晚罗克韦尔的账由我来结
Uh, I'll be taking care of the Rockwell tab tonight.
把账记我房间上 皇家套房 马蒂·毛瑟
Put it on my room. The Royal Suite. Marty Mauser.
- 跟他们交代清楚 是我付的账 - 明白 先生
- And make sure they know it's me, too. - I will. Leave it to me, sir.
- 不许被回绝 - 没问题
- Don't take no for an answer. - I won't.
- 马蒂·毛瑟 皇家套房 去告诉他们 - 好的 先生
- Marty Mauser. Royal Suite. Go tell 'em. - Will do, sir.
行了 看着我 别往那儿瞅 看着我
Okay. Look at me. Don't look there. Look at me.
- 罗克韦尔是谁啊 - 就个傻瓜
- Who's Rockwell? - Some bozo.
现在看过去 别太明显 告诉我他在干啥？
Look over now. Be subtle about it. What's he doing?
抱歉先生 他之前没来过我们酒店
He hasn't been here before, sir.
他在看这边
He's looking at us.
- 是吗？ - 嗯
- Really? - Yeah.
好 继续跟我说话 别露馅
Okay, keep talking to me. Be normal.
好吧 听我说 再考虑一下
Okay, fine. I want you to reconsider.
我们会是绝佳组合 我想跟你搭档
We would be a great team. I wanna do this with you.
干嘛老想着哈林篮球队？
Why are you so fixed on the Harlem Globetrotters?
那群人干的真丢人
It's very sad what they do, okay?
本该是顶尖的运动员却成了杂耍的小丑
Some of the premier athletes on the planet reduced to acting like circus clowns.
再看看什么情况
What's he doing now?
- 他正朝这桌走来 - 他来了？
- He's coming towards us. - He's coming?
- 别紧张 表现得自然点 - 行 好的 明白
- Just be normal. Act casual. - Okay, fine. Okay.
劳驾 我认识你吗？
Excuse me. Do I know you?
应该不认识
I don't think so.
你居然想请客？
And you wanna buy dinner for my entire table tonight?
- 对 可以吗？ - 为什么？
- Yeah. Is it okay? - Why?
什么叫为什么？我还需要理由？
What do you mean, why? Do I need a reason?
我换个说法 你图什么？
Let me rephrase that. What do you want?
不 我什么都不图 只是想表示点谢意
No, I don't want anything. It's just my small way of saying thank you.
- 谢我？ - 对
- Thank you? - Yeah.
具体谢我什么？
Thank me for what, specifically?
谢谢您那些产品
For all your products.
没了你们的笔 世界该怎么办？
I mean, where would we be without pens?
你看 我有不少本事 但最得意的就是
You know, I have many talents, but the one I'm most proud of
- 能大老远闻出屁话 - 不
- is the ability to smell bullshit from a mile away. - No,
我说的都是真心话
I'm being completely sincere.
- 你是哪儿人？ - 纽约人 你呢？
- Where are you from? - New York. What about you?
也是纽约 你是做什么的？
New York too. What do you do?
我是个职业运动员
I'm a professional athlete.
- 真的吗 哪项运动？ - 桌上网球
- Really? What sport? - Table tennis.
桌球？这也算运动？
Table tennis? That's a sport?
当然算 我来参加英国公开赛的
Of course it is. I'm here competing in the British Open.
我明天要在温布利打决赛
I'm playing at Wembley tomorrow
对阵日本 明天赛场座无虚席
in front of a sold-out crowd in the finals against Japan.
- 我代表美国出赛 - 等一下
- I'm here representing the United States. - Wait, wait, wait.
日本？日本也来了？
Japan? Japan has a team here?
- 我刚才不是说了吗 - 那出境管制呢？
- That's what I just said. - How'd they get around the travel ban?
因为桌球在亚洲增长最快
Because table tennis is the fastest growing sport in Asia.
在那边火得不行
It's huge over there.
说个有意思的事
Oh, you're gonna like this.
你知道他们怎么握拍的吗？
Do you know what they call their grip? The way they hold their rackets?
- 不知道 - 他们管那叫直笔握拍
- No. - They call it penholder.
【直拍:起源日本 英文含“握笔”之意】
那又怎样？
So what?
你可以拿去用
You can use that.
用来干嘛？
Use it for what?
拿去当宣传素材 我哪知道 我又不是生意人
For an advertisement or something. I don't know, you're the business guy.
刚才有点失礼 这位是我搭档贝拉·克莱茨基
I'm being rude. This is my associate, Béla Kletzki.
幸会 先生
Nice to meet you, sir.
你也是打桌球的？
I assume you're a table tennis player also?
是的 没错 我是1935到39年的世界冠军
I am. I am. Actually, I was the World Champion from '35 to '39.
前世界冠军 我今天把他打败了
He was the World Champion. I beat him today.
他赢了我 他比我年轻得多
He beat me. But he's much younger than me.
也强得多 更有天赋
I'm much better than him, much more talented.
我看到这个纹身 你是不是进过集中营？
I can't help but notice this tattoo. You were in one of the camps, weren't you?
奥斯威辛二号营区 没错 怎么问这个？
Auschwitz-Birkenau. Yeah. Why do you ask?
我儿子为了解放你们付出了生命
My son lost his life liberating you.
我深表遗憾
I'm sorry for your loss.
我还以为是苏联人解放你们的
I thought you were liberated by the Soviets.
- 确实是 是苏联 - 并不是美国人
- We were. It's Soviets. - It wasn't the Americans.
不是字面意思 我儿子在太平洋战场
I didn't mean it literally. He was serving in the South Pacific.
那他后来怎么了？
Well, what happened to him?
还能怎么了 他被杀了
What do you mean? He was killed.
你觉得这好笑吗？
You find that funny?
天呐 不是 我有时一紧张就会笑
Oh, God. No, I just get nervous laughter sometimes.
说句安慰话
If it's any consolation,
我明天会送给他们第三颗原子弹
I'll be dropping a third atom bomb on their heads tomorrow.
你这套安慰话 顶多忽悠你妈
Yeah, I'm sure his mother's gonna get a lot of comfort
让她不反对你去打小乒乓
that you're playing ping pong in his honor.
感谢您操心我家事
It's not that big of a deal, but I appreciate it.
跟他讲讲...他以前给纳粹拆弹
Tell him-- He used to diffuse bombs for the Nazis.
跟他讲讲那故事
Tell him the story you told me about--
- 我那桌还有人等我 我得走了 - 别走 别走
- I've got a whole table of people waiting. - No, no, no, wait, wait.
他会喜欢的 讲给他听
You're gonna love this story. Tell him.
- 你想听吗？ - 不太想 但快说吧
- You wanna hear it? - Not really, but go ahead.
别停 快说 是好故事
No, tell him. It's beautiful.
行 那我长话短说
Okay, I'll make it quick. So...
我进集中营被分配住处的时候
when I first got to the camp, I was put into housing.
幸好有个军官认出我
Lucky for me, there was an officer who recognized me.
他在1935年布拉格世锦赛上见过我
He had seen me in 1935 at the World Championships in Prague.
那人是真心崇拜我 真心的
This guy was a real fan. I mean, a real fan, okay?
他居然因为你会打小乒乓就让你活着？
You're telling me he let you live because you played ping pong?
他们很佩服我的本事 没错
They respected my skills, yeah.
于是他们教我拆圆柱高爆炸弹
So then, they taught me how to dismantle SC bombs.
明白吗？
Okay?
每天早上他们把我和炸弹送到营外的树林里
Each morning, they would send me into the woods with the bombs
就算炸了也伤不到别人
on the outskirts of the camp where I could only do damage to myself.
有一回
So one time,
我尾随一只蜜蜂
I followed a honeybee.
什么蜂？
A bee?
蜜蜂
A honeybee,
一路跟它到了蜂巢
all the way to its hive.
然后我用烟把蜜蜂全都熏跑
And I smoked all the bees out.
接着我把巢掰开
And then broke it open,
我把蜂蜜抹满全身 胸口 胳膊全抹上了
and I smeared the honey all over my chest, my arms, everywhere.
为什么？
Why?
晚上回去后
'Cause later that night,
我就让室友把我身上的蜜舔掉充饥
I let all my bunk mates to lick the honey off of me for nourishment.
皇家套房
押正面
Heads.
【抛硬币猜中者先选“发球”或“场地” 二选一】
- 真倒霉 - 远藤 轮到你选了
- Fuck. - Endo, choice?
（日语）发球
我选那边
I'll go to that side.
决赛
- 右侧... - 加油 马蒂 加油
- On my right... - Come on, Marty! Come on!
是美国选手马蒂·毛瑟 世界排名第二
...Marty Mauser of the United States, ranked second,
对阵日本选手远藤功人 未列排名
versus Koto Endo of Japan, unranked.
比赛为五局三胜
The gentlemen will battle to the best of five
单局21分制
in games to 21 points.
每局须至少领先两分才能取胜
Each game shall be won by at least two points.
祝二位好运
Good luck, gentlemen.
第一局
请保持安静
Quiet, please.
比赛开始
All right!
远藤 得分 1比0
Point, Endo. One-nil.
加油 美国人
Come on, America!
远藤 得分 2比0
Point, Endo. Two-nil.
加油 马蒂
All right, Marty!
加油啊 马蒂
Come on, Marty!
远藤 得分 3比0
Point, Endo. Three-nil.
远藤 得分 4比0
Point, Endo. Four-nil.
加油 马蒂
Come on, Marty!
远藤 得分 5比0
Point, Endo. Five-nil.
换马蒂·毛瑟发球
Service switches to Mauser.
比分
局分
美国
日本
马蒂·毛瑟 得分
Point, Mauser.
9比19 美方发球
Nine serving 19.
第二局
马蒂·毛瑟 得分 10比19
Point, Mauser. 10-19.
好样的 马蒂
Okay, Marty!
远藤 得分 20比10
Point, Endo. 20-10.
局点
Game point.
【局点:率先达到者只需再得一分即可赢此局】
快发球
Go! Serve.
远藤 得分 21比10
Point, Endo. 21-10.
本局远藤胜
Game, Endo.
远藤以两局比零领先
Endo leads two games to zero.
美国
日本
局分
比分
马蒂·毛瑟 得分
Point, Mauser.
18比16
Eighteen-16.
第三局
马蒂·毛瑟 得分 17比18
Point, Mauser. 17-18.
加油 马蒂 加油
Go, Marty! Come on!
换马蒂·毛瑟发球
Service switches to Mauser.
该死
Fuck.
远藤 得分 17比19
Point, Endo. 17-19.
真见鬼了
Oh, fuck.
远藤 得分 17比20
Point, Endo. 17-20.
赛点
And match point.
请安静
Quiet, please.
请坐好 保持安静
Quiet. Settle down.
马蒂·毛瑟发球
Your service, Mauser.
加油啊 马蒂
Come on, Marty!
完了
Fuck.
不行 这是胡闹 不行
No, bullshit! No!
现在就给我重赛 用正规硬拍
I want a rematch right now with a standard-league hard-bat!
【1952年孟买世锦赛 日本选手佐藤博治首次用海绵拍 并赢得男单冠军】
这太不像话了
That is unacceptable!
要是我装了机械臂呢？
What if I had a mechanical arm?
要是我在球上涂胶水呢？这合规吗？
What if I put glue on the ball? Would that be kosher?
他全场都被教练指点 这太不像话
Why, he was getting coached the entire time! That is unacceptable!
我打的可是正经桌球 正经桌球
I play real table tennis! Real table tennis!
胡闹啊
Unbelievable.
本届英国公开赛冠军是...
...British Open champion from Japan...
去死吧你
Fuck you!
...日本选手远藤功人
...Koto Endo!
a
b
（日语）第19届英国桌球公开赛上 日本首次问鼎冠军
（日语）这是自太平洋战争结束以来
（日语）首位日本选手在国际赛场上夺得胜利
（日语）获胜者为远藤功人
（日语）这位无名的日本挑战者 他在决赛中
（日语）以3比0的压倒性优势击败夺冠热门的美国强手
（日语）东京十万民众涌上街头
（日语）宛若庆典游行
（日语）热烈欢庆他的凯旋
（日语）远藤却以谦逊自持 愿以一名普通工匠身份回国
（日语）而非受封为所谓英雄
（日语）远藤16岁遭遇东京大轰炸 失去听觉
（日语）他在无声之中磨砺感官 最终以钢铁般意志征服赛场
（日语）如今 世界桌球的目光聚焦于我邦
c
（日语）本年度世界锦标赛主办地已定为东京
（日语）美国选手必将卷土重来 誓要洗刷败绩
（日语）但远藤并非孤军奋战
（日语）他背靠的是与他一道齐心实现民族愿望
（日语）共怀不屈精神的八千四百万同胞
d
法国 巴黎
（法语）您好先生 有什么需要吗？
Bonjour monsieur, Est‑ce que je peux vous aider?
米尔顿·罗克韦尔订的桌子在哪儿？
Do you have a Milton Rockwell reservation?
- （法语）您说什么？ - 请查下米尔顿·罗克韦尔的订位
- Excusez-moi? - Milton Rockwell reservation, please.
（法语）您是说罗克韦尔吧？
Ah, Rockwell?
听着 马蒂 我得亲自谢谢你
So, listen, Marty, I wanna personally thank you
谢谢你带我接触桌球
for introducing me to table tennis.
我压根儿没想到 这玩意能在亚洲火成那样
I had no idea what a phenomenon it was in the Asias.
- 哦 对 对 - 尤其在日本
- Oh, yeah. I know. - And how big it is in Japan!
我早跟你说了 火得很
That's what I was trying to tell you. It's huge.
所以 我打算把桌球列进
So, I'm thinking of incorporating it into some of the promotional events
秋季在那边的宣传项目里
we're gonna be doing over there in the fall.
你准备怎么安排？
How so? What are you thinking?
我想在世锦赛期间
What I wanna do is stage an exhibition match
安排一场你和远藤的表演赛
around the time of the World Championships between you and Endo.
- 嗯 - 你肯定会喜欢的
- Mmm. - I think you'd like that idea.
我给你开个价
So I'm gonna make you an offer.
1000美金酬劳
I'll pay you a thousand dollars.
【约1.2万美元 8.5万人民币 37万新台币】
还安排你住东京帝国饭店
I'll put you up at the Imperial Hotel in Tokyo.
【东京帝国饭店:建于19世纪末 东京三大顶级酒店之一】
要是你从纽约出发 还可以坐我的私人飞机
And if you're leaving from New York, I'll give you a seat on my private plane,
让你这辈子体验一回什么叫奢华
and you'll fly in luxury for the first time in your life.
钱的事之后再商量
Okay, we can negotiate my price later.
但这安排是在赛前还是赛后？
But this would be before or after the tournament?
- 赛前一周左右 - 不行 必须是赛后
- About a week before the event. - No, it's gotta be after.
我不能在紧要关头前陪他演戏
I can't face off against the guy in public before it actually counts.
好戏要留到关键时候
Drama is very important to me. I can't undercut the drama.
先别纠结细节
Let's not get tied up in minutiae.
- 我只是想知道你有没有兴趣参加 - 有啊
- I just want to find out if you're interested in participating. - Yes.
当然有 凡是能让我露一手的机会我都不会错过
Oh, yeah. Of course. I'm interested in any opportunity to show off my talents.
别担心 这回我一定完胜他
And you don't have to worry either, 'cause this time I'm gonna obliterate him.
主要是球拍的问题
It's really the racket that I'm playing,
但我保证 准能赢
but I can assure you, it's gonna be a victory.
行了 听着 你得明白这是怎么回事
Okay, listen. I need you to understand what this thing's about.
这不是正式比赛
This is not an official match.
连真打都算不上
It's not even a real game.
这是纯粹的宣传 目的就是讨好日本人
This is purely promotional, to entertain the Japanese people,
好让他们多买我的笔 明白吗？
so they buy more of my pens, okay?
你上去打几局 你会很亮眼
You're gonna play a few games. You're gonna be great.
- 但别把远藤的风头给抢了 - 你让我故意输给他？
- But you can't play better than Endo. - You want me to lose?
马蒂 给你看样东西
Marty, let me show you something.
日本头号杂志
Biggest magazine in Japan.
你把远藤捧成了国民英雄
You made Endo a national treasure.
- 听着... - 你什么意思？
- Listen-- - Why are you showing me this?
你觉得这会让我甘心输掉？我只会更想赢
Do you think this makes me wanna lose? This makes me wanna win.
你要以退为进
Sometimes, when you lose you're a winner.
- 听我解释一下 - 我比远藤强上万倍
- Let me explain. Let me explain. - I'm ten trillion times better than Endo.
打败我的不是人 而是那把球拍
You understand that, right? It's the racket that beat me.
- 他水平很一般 - 我不在乎
- He's a mediocre player. - I couldn't care less.
我根本不在乎桌球 这都不算体育
I don't care about table tennis. This is theater.
- 你担心什么？ - 我的名声
- What are you worried about? - My reputation.
- 你的名声？ - 没错 我的名声
- Your reputation? - Yes, my reputation.
我不会为你糟蹋我的名声 没门
I don't wanna throw my reputation in the trash for you. I'm not doing it.
你现在不就在当小丑吗？
Aren't you playing in a vaudeville circus act right now?
什么小丑？把话说清楚
What do you mean, vaudeville? Finish that sentence.
- 你什么意思？ - 你不过是人家中场休息时的把戏
- What are you implying? - You're the halftime show, Marty.
那可是哈林篮球队 都是世上最顶尖的运动员
Of the Harlem Globetrotters! The finest athletes on the planet.
从一月到现在 至少有八万观众看过我的表演
I've probably played in front of 80,000 people since January.
这好笑吗？
That's funny to you?
不是 你很可笑
No. You're funny to me.
我可笑？你知道什么最可笑吗？
I'm funny to you? You know what's funny to me?
你这么低三下四去讨好日本人
That you want to entertain the Japanese so badly,
而他们杀了你儿子 这才叫可笑
and they murdered your son. That's funny to me.
听着 咱俩互揭伤疤 扯平了 行吗？
Look, you struck a nerve, I struck a nerve. Okay? Now we're even.
滚出去
Get out.
不行 你还欠我一顿饭
Nah, I think you owe me a meal first.
有请:哈林篮球队
（塞克语）让我们热烈欢迎小乒乓登场
（塞克语）他们将上演“一闪一闪亮晶晶”
南斯拉夫 萨拉热窝
♪ 人人终将长大 ♪
♪ And everybody's gotta learn sometime ♪
希腊 雅典
♪ 人人终会领悟 ♪
♪ Everybody's gotta learn sometime ♪
摩洛哥北部 丹吉尔
♪ 人人终会领悟 ♪
♪ Everybody's gotta learn sometime ♪
快来 教练
Yeah, Coach, yeah!
埃及 开罗
三 二 一 说茄子
Three, two, one. Say cheese.
茄子
Cheese!
西德 慕尼黑
比利时 布鲁塞尔
（法语）接下来毛瑟 对阵 海豹
♪ 人人终将长大 ♪
♪ 'Cause everybody's Gotta learn sometime ♪
♪ 人人终会领悟 ♪
♪ Everybody's gotta learn sometime ♪
【1950年代种族隔离限制黑人入NBA 许多顶级球员改入表演球队】
♪ 人人终会领悟 ♪
♪ Everybody's gotta learn sometime ♪
美国 纽约
借过
Excuse me.
也不打招呼
Hello.
别在我房间吃喝 会生虫子
Please don't eat or drink in my room. It attracts bugs.
我只是进去打扫卫生 别多想
I just go in there to clean. That's it.
见到我你一点都不高兴啊
Well, you don't seem happy to see me.
是啊 你不也不高兴吗
Yeah, and you don't seem happy to see me.
要留这儿住吗？
So, now are you going to be staying here?
怎么 不行吗？
What, is that not okay?
别担心 我过几周就走 不烦你
Don't worry. I'll be out of your hair in a few weeks.
懂点事吧
Don't be stupid.
- 走去哪儿？过几周有什么事？ - 世锦赛
- Why? What's in a few weeks? - World Championship.
- 在哪儿办？ - 东京
- So, where's that gonna be? - Tokyo.
日本的东京？
Tokyo, Japan?
还有其他东京吗？
Are you asking me if Tokyo's in Japan?
你没正经问题吗？
Is that a serious question?
你看起来累坏了
You look very tired to me.
是啊 我刚跑了大半个地球 能不累吗
Yeah, 'cause I just traveled halfway around the world. I'm tired.
我很忙 忙着工作 忙着挣钱
I was busy. I was working. I was making money.
趁着这会儿楼里没人用热水
You know, while everybody is at work in the building,
去好好洗个热水澡吧
it would be a good time for you to take a nice, long, hot shower.
- 给你 - 这是什么？
- Here. - What's this?
专门带给你的
I got you something.
这可是从真金字塔上敲下来的
It's from an original Egyptian pyramid.
还记得小时候吗？
We built that.
嗯
Okay.
嘿 利维 又长高了
Hey, Levi. You got a lot taller.
- 我没有 - 有啊
- No, I didn't. - Yeah, you did.
- 你是哪位 有事吗？ - 有 跟我走
- Excuse me. Can I help you? - Yeah. Let's go.
- 走 赶紧的 - 你干嘛？
- Come on, come on. - Hey! What are you doing?
- 跟我走 快走 - 不 你搞什么鬼？
- Let's go, let's go. Let's go. - No! What the fuck are you doing?
- 你被捕了 - 我没有
- You're under arrest. - No, I'm not!
- 被捕了 过来 别乱动 - 凭什么逮捕我？
- Yes, you are. Come here. Stop moving! - What am I under arrest for?
- 那是我的洗漱用品 哎呦 - 你被捕了
- That's my toiletries! Ow! - You're under arrest.
- 犯了什么事？ - 持械抢劫 走吧
- For what? - Armed robbery. Come on.
持械？你胡说什么呢？
Armed rob-- What are you talking about?
不想受伤就别动了
You're gonna hurt yourself if you keep moving!
- 到底怎么回事？ - 走
- What is going on? - Come on.
- 老默 我妈在哪？ - 我叫她先走开一下
- Murray, where's my mother? Murray. - I asked her to leave for a bit.
你什么？到底搞什么鬼？抓我？帮帮我！
You told her-- What the fuck is going on? I'm getting arrested! Help me!
萨尔 萨尔 我跟他单独谈谈 你先回避下
Sal, Sal. I wanna talk to him in private. Excuse us. Just go.
- 去哪儿？ - 萨尔？ 你认识这人？
- What do you want me to do? - Sal? You know this guy?
- 先去屋里待会儿 - 好
- Just go in the back for a while. - Yeah.
关上门
Close the door.
行 情况不对就喊我
All right, if it gets crazy just holler.
搞什么鬼 我拿的那钱是你欠我的
What the fuck is going on, Murray? That money I took, you owed me.
不 别胡扯 那钱是你持枪抢的
No, no, no, no. It was money you stole at gunpoint.
- 不 你答应过我的 听我说 - 不 你根本没...
- No, you promised me... Excuse me. - No, you didn't...
那钱本来就该给我的
That was my money and you took--
你答应过要给我的 我没胡扯
You promised me that money. I'm not... Why would I make this up?
- 那是去英国的路费 - 哦 比赛怎么样？
- It was money for my trip to England. - What happened on your trip?
你什么意思？
What do you mean, what happened on my trip?
- 你输了 - 我没输
- You lost! - No, I didn't!
- 你就是输了 - 听谁说的？
- You did! - Where did you hear that?
- 不 对手作弊了 - 你知不知道我多少次
- No, I got cheated against. - Do you know how many times
- 半夜得替你... - 行了 别扯了
- in the middle of the night... - No, no. Stop with that.
- 闭嘴 好好听着 - 少教训我
- Shut up and listen to me! - Don't lecture me.
闭嘴
Shut up!
你不知道我多少次半夜被叫醒
You don't know how many times I had to get woken up
- 替你擦屁股 - 谁让你管的？
- and bail you out. - When did I ask you to do that?
- 我求过你吗？ - 你确实没求过我
- When have I ever asked for your help? - You never asked me to do that.
- 没错 - 但我还是帮了
- Exactly! - But I did.
你都多大了 你该懂事了
And now, you're gonna be a big boy.
- 你得成器了 - 成器？
- It's your turn. - A big boy?
- 你竟然教育我？ - 没错 听好了
- Did you really just say that to me? - Yeah. Yeah, you know, look...
我不能永远供着你妈
I can't support your mother for the rest of my life.
- 谁让你操心了 - 哦 那谁操心？
- You're not gonna have to. - Oh, yeah? Why not?
- 我来承担 - 你承担？怎么承担？
- Because I'm gonna step up. - You're gonna step up? How?
我会让我妈妈荣华富贵
In a way you can't imagine. She's gonna be living on Fifth Avenue
住进有电梯的豪宅
in an apartment and building with a elevator,
还有门童 还有专人伺候
and a man who works in the elevator that takes her every time she needs to use it.
得了得了 听好了
Sure, sure, sure. All right, look.
我给你两个选择 你自己选
I'm gonna give you two options, okay?
你应该能接受第一个
I think you'll like the first one.
回鞋店干活
You come back to the shop.
这回别再不务正业了
This time, no more bullshit.
别再耍你那小乒乓了 明白吗？
None of this ping-pong mishegoss, okay?
我会给你更大的权责
I'm gonna give you much more responsibility,
说实话 你卖鞋挺有一手的
because truth be told, you're an amazing salesman.
是啊 我都能卖鞋给蛇
I could sell shoes to an amputee.
那又怎样 我偏不干 第二个选择呢？
So what? What's the other option?
- 那我就控告你 - 你才不会
- I press charges. - You're not doing that.
- 洛伊是证人... - 你不会那么干的
- Lloyd is a witness... - You're not doing that.
...然后你去蹲大牢
...and you go to jail!
真的？对你亲外甥这么狠？你疯了吗？
Really? You'd do that to your own kin? Are you out of your mind?
- 得让你尝尝教训 - 萨尔 出来 萨尔
- We'll see... You took it upon yourself. - Hey, Sal! Sal!
- 干嘛？ - 他给你多少钱来吓我？
- What? - How much is he paying you right now?
胡说什么 什么钱？
What are you talking about, paying me?
我舅给你多少钱来吓我？
How much is my uncle paying for you to scare me?
不管多少 我出双倍 快来跪下给我舔吧
'Cause whatever it is, I'll double it for you to suck my dick.
- 什么？ - 给我舔
- What? - Suck my dick.
- 你口臭真难闻 - 嘴放干净点 你这...
- You have terrible breath. - Watch your mouth, you--
- 噢 该死 - 走 现在就走
- Ow! Fuck! - Let's go. We're going now.
- 他刚打了我 - 住手 行了行了
- He just hit me! - Stop. Please stop.
- 老默 他打我 - 停下
- Murray, he hit me. - Stop.
我们都商量好了
We worked everything out.
听见没 我们商量好了
You were in the other room. You didn't hear. We already worked it out.
- 他会补偿一切 - 粗鲁
- He's paying back everything. - Animal.
他把钱给我了 都没事了
He gave me the money, and everything's okay.
- 你从哪儿拿的钱？ - 你行李箱里
- Where did you get that? - I got it from your luggage.
你疯了吗 那是我去日本的钱
Are you out of your mind? That's my money for Japan!
- 你是不是傻了？ - 走 赶紧走
- Are you out of your fucking mind? - Let's go. Let's go.
押到局里 把他押走
Just take him downtown, damn it! Take him downtown!
- 好 好 我听你的 停下 - 你玩完了 彻底完了
- Okay. All right! Okay! I'll stop! - You're done. You're done.
- 拜托 停下 停下 - 跟我走
- Please. Stop. Stop. - Let's go.
- 好 放开他 放开他 - 放开他？
- All right. Let him go. Let him go. - Let him go?
- 放开他 放开他 - 坐好
- Let him go. Let him go. - Sit up.
听着 道个歉
Listen, apologize.
行 对不起 我错了
Okay, I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
给他解开手铐
Take his cuffs off.
- 接下来这样安排 听好 - 好
- This is what's gonna happen, okay? - Okay.
咱们去花园咖啡馆见你妈
We're gonna meet your mom at the Garden Café.
咱们好好吃顿饭
We're gonna have a really nice dinner.
之前的破事儿就翻篇了 行吗？
And let's just put all this shit behind us, okay?
行 没问题
Okay. All right.
- 我错了 我错了 真错了 - 你知错了？
- I'm sorry, I'm sorry. I'm sorry. - You're sorry?
剩下的事慢慢解决 赶紧穿衣服
We'll take care of everything. Just get dressed.
- 好了 舅舅爱你 - 行 我也爱你
- Come on. I love you. - All right. I love you too.
你外甥真是个废物
Your nephew's a piece of shit, you know that?
哎 天呐 实在对不住
Oh, Jesus. I'm so sorry.
再给你十块
Here another ten.
好 行吧
Yeah, all right.
花园咖啡馆啊 点什么馅三明治？
Garden Café, huh? What do you get?
烟熏肉啊 还能什么？
The pastrami, what else?
【烟熏肉三明治:东欧犹太移民特色食物】
- 噢 烟熏肉 - 你点什么馅？
- Ah, pastrami. - What do you get?
英式烤牛肉
Roast beef.
【英式烧牛肉:传统英式料理】
- 英式烧牛肉？ - 嗯
- Roast beef? - Yeah.
（意第绪语）你这吃洋饭的条子
Goyishecop!
嘿
Hey.
开门 别磨蹭
Open up. Come on.
- 把门撞开 - 你确定？
- Break it down. - Break it in?
见鬼
Fuck!
嘿 你往哪儿跑？
Hey! Where you going?
糟了
Shit.
- 怎么回事？ - 他从窗户跑了
- What happened? - He went out the window.
- 什么？怎么回事？ - 弗兰基
- What? Wait! - Frankie!
- 怎么了？ - 他沿着消防梯下去了
- What? - He's coming down the escape right now.
就在那儿 别让他跑了
There he goes! Down the escape!
- 该死 - 快追 快追 快追
- Oh, shit. - Go, go, go!
纽约警察
埃塞克斯街
宠物店
- 来 摸摸它 - 我去后头打个电话
- You hold it. - I'm just gonna use the phone in the back.
这兔子多喜欢你啊
See how much he likes you?
- 喂 - 嘿 沃利 最近怎样 我是马蒂
- Hello? - Hey, Wally. How you doing? It's Marty.
- 今晚出车吗？ - 废话 当然出
- Are you working tonight? - Of course I'm working.
行 好 开着车 多带现金
Okay, great. Bring your cab and as much cash as you can.
到28街的哈尔西碰头 明白吗？
I want you to meet me at The Halsey on 28th Street, okay?
什么？你又想去骗局子？
What? You wanna go hustling again?
对 没错
Yeah, exactly.
不 不 不 还记得上次多惨吗？
No, no, no. I got my ass kicked last time.
咱们跑去史坦顿岛
We went all the way to Staten Island,
十分钟你就被认出了 你还想回去？
and within ten minutes, they recognized you, and now you want to go back?
不去 这次去新泽西那边 奎因提过的那个地方
No, It's fine. We're gonna go to that place that Quinn was talking about in Jersey.
坏主意
That's a bad idea.
- 这就是你的新宠物了 - 不 妈妈 我想要个犰狳
- That's your new pet. - No, Mom, I want the armadillo.
我们商量过...
No, I already--
这样吧 我给你拿个犰狳
You know what? I'm just gonna get you the armadillo.
你抱好 你自己挑
I'm gonna give him to you, and then you can make a decision. Okay?
这也是哺乳动物啊
They're not reptiles. They're mammals.
行 太好了 你真是个大好人 一个半小时后见
Okay, great. You're a beautiful man. I'll see you in an hour and a half.
- 哪儿？ - 哈尔西见 就这样 好哥们
- Where? - At the Halsey. Okay. I love you.
谢了 再见
Thank you. Bye.
很好 你来了
Okay, good. Here you are.
有没有后门可以出去？
Is there a way I can go out the back or something, please?
干嘛 你那眼神啥意思？
What? Why are you looking at me like that?
你不打算说点什么吗？
Aren't you gonna say something to me?
哦 恭喜是吧？
What, congratulations?
- 恭喜？ - 对
- Congratulations? - Yes.
- 你傻吗？ - 你想让我说什么？
- Are you kidding me? - What do you want me to say?
这八个月我一直在找你
I've been trying to get in contact with you for eight months.
行了 这招没用的
Okay, I see what you're trying to do. It's not gonna work.
- 什么意思？ - 那孩子跟我没关系
- Excuse me? - That's not mine.
- 绝对是你的 - 不可能 我都拔出来了
- It is absolutely yours. - No, it's not. I pull out.
- 就是你的 - 你丈夫艾勒也拔出来吗？
- Yes it is. - Does Ira pull out?
- 你要我怎么说？ - 如实回答
- What do you want me to say to that? - It's a simple question.
他和你上床时会拔出来吗？
Does he pull out when he has sex with you?
- 回答我 - 你竟然要我答这个？
- Answer it. - You want me to answer that?
对 快回答 他拔不拔出来
Yes! Answer it. Does he pull out when he...
对不起 对不起 不哭 不哭
I'm sorry. I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
我陷入麻烦了 瑞秋 到处麻烦缠身
I'm a mess right now. I'm really a mess, Rachel.
我在伦敦输了后...
I lost in London, by the way--
嘿
Hey!
见鬼
God.
你们干嘛呢？
What's this?
他爸爸过世了
His father died.
- 放屁 - 她是我从八岁起的朋友
- Bullshit! - This is my friend since I was eight.
我问你了吗？
Am I talking to you?
艾勒 我从八岁就认识她了
Ira, I've known her since I was eight years old.
我爸刚走 她在安慰我
My father just died. She was consoling me.
亲爱的 没事的
Honey, it's okay.
- 闭嘴 别碰我 - 你跟老婆就这样说话吗？
- Shut up! Don't touch me! - That's how you talk to your wife?
对 有意见吗？
Yeah, that's how I talk to her.
- 行 - 有意见吗？
- Okay. - Huh?
来 来 来 把意见大声说出来
No, no, no! Come on. Keep going.
- 说出来 - 马蒂 别说了
- Keep going. - Marty, just stop.
看我不撕烂你的臭脸
I'll rip that unibrow right off his fucking forehead!
你想动手吗？跟个禽兽一样？
You wanna get physical? Like an ape?
艾勒
Ira.
艾勒 回来 快进来 你要干嘛？
Ira! Come back inside. What are you doing?
谁去把条子叫来 快点
Somebody get the fucking cops over here, huh?
- 你要干嘛？ - 该死 我得赶紧溜
- What did you do? - Fuck! I gotta get out of here.
为什么要躲警察
Why are you running from the cops?
他就在这儿 快去抓
Come on, he's right here!
有后门吗？
There's no way out the back?
- 后什么？ - 瑞秋 专心点 有没有？
- What? What-- - Please! Come on. Rachel! Focus.
从这出去 走吧
It leads out the back. Go.
行 行 谢谢 谢谢
Okay. Okay. Thank you, thank you.
- 别走 我上哪找你？ - 回头再说 回头再说
- Where do we meet? Where? - I'll tell you later. I'll tell you later.
有没有看到一个戴眼镜的白小子从这儿出来？
Guys, you see a white kid with glasses come through here?
没人看见？
Nobody saw him?
听不懂英语？
No English, huh?
如需继续通话 请投币五分
Please insert a nickel if you'd like to continue the conversation.
要五分？电话要断了
A nickel? They're gonna cut us off.
- 你有五分吗？ - 没
- Do you have a nickel? - No.
妈 真没骗你 我保证这次是最后一次了
Mom, I'm not lying. I promise you this will be the last time.
难道我眼花了 这不是我的小毛毛吗？
Are my eyes broke, or is that motherfucking Mouse?
- 谢谢 - 近来怎样？
- Thank you. - What's up, baby?
太谢谢了 你要帮大忙了 谢谢
Thank you so much. I really appreciate it. Thank you.
- 你一身臭味 - 我知道
- You smell like a fish, Marty. - I know, that's why
所以咱们得开个房 我得洗个澡
we gotta get a hotel room. I need to get a shower.
你好 麻烦开一间房
How you doing? Hey, can we get a hotel room, please?
- 四块 - 你刚还说三块呢
- Four dollars. - You said it was three dollars.
- 那是刚才那间价格 现在四块 - 怎么现在变四块了？
- That was for the last room. It's four. - Why is it four dollars now?
先借我四块 我保证还你
Let me get four bucks. I'll pay you back, I promise.
我跟你说 我们只有十块本钱可以赌
I'm telling you right now, we only got ten to play with.
【10美元 约120美元 820人民币 3,750新台币】
就带了十块？搞什么鬼？
You brought ten dollars? What's wrong with you?
- 你一小时前才通知我 - 那咱们怎么赢钱？
- You gave me a hour notice. - How are we supposed to make money?
老兄 我得养娃呢 我就是个开出租的
Nigger, I got kids! I'm a fucking taxi driver.
有便宜点的房吗？不用讲究
Do you have a cheaper room? It doesn't have to be nice.
五楼还有间 但不准洗澡
There's a room on the fifth floor, but you can't use the shower.
- 那好 多少钱？ - 两块五
- Okay, how much is that? - Two fifty.
【2.5美元 约30美元 210人民币 960新台币】
- 借我三块 谢谢 - 别赖账
- Let me get three dollars. Thank you. - You better pay me back.
- 放心 放心 - 多亏你还有我这个哥们
- Yeah, I will I will. - You lucky I love you.
- 吉米 吉米 - 待会从赢的钱里扣
- Jimmy. Jimmy. - It's coming out your winnings.
把钥匙递来
Give me the keys.
这啥味儿？
What's that smell?
哎呦 我去
Oh, my God! Fuck.
- 我去 怎么那么臭 - 天呐
- Wow! What is that? - Oh, my God!
出了点小意外
He had a little accident.
这哪是小意外啊
God! He had an enormous accident.
难闻死了
That's horrible.
- 跟掉粪坑里一样 - 我去
- Smells like shit! - Fuck!
吉米 你才掉进过粪坑
Jimmy, you smell like shit.
- 你嘴比你那狗还臭 - 能把钥匙给我了吗？
- Is that your breath or the dog? - Can I get my key, please?
不许带那狗上电梯 走楼梯
Do not go in the elevator with that dog. Take the stairs.
- 别闹 - 赶紧洗狗
- Are you kidding me? - Wash that dog.
晚安 吉米
Goodbye, Jimmy.
- 她肚子有多大了 - 非常大 大得吓人
- How big is she, Marty? - Very big. Big.
大到明天就生吗？
Is she popping out tomorrow?
我哪知道什么时候生 我只知道孩子不是我的
I don't know when she's popping out. Look, all I know is it's not mine.
我太了解她了 她有她的小算盘
She has an agenda. You don't know her like I do.
她婚姻不幸 生活惨淡
She's stuck in a miserable marriage. She has a horrible life.
她想借我逃避
She's trying to pin it down on me.
从八岁起 她就想把我套牢
Since we were eight years old, she's trying to get me stuck.
- 套你这穷光蛋？ - 没错
- Your bummy ass? - Yes.
那她真有毛病
Yeah, she is crazy.
从生理上讲那孩子绝不可能是我的
It's a biological impossibility that that kid is mine, okay?
- 你戴套了？ - 没 我不需要
- So, you using raincoats? - No, I don't need to.
那你多半是废了
So you must be shooting blanks.
你知道“定海锁脉功”吗？
Do you know what continence is, Wally? No?
每次尿一半我就憋着
Every time I take a piss, I pull back,
然后默唱首生日歌
I hold my urine in, and I count to ten Mississippi.
- 专练那块肌肉 - 我去
- That's how you build up the muscle. - Oh, my God!
你这是专练膀胱炎的
That's how you get a fuckin' bladder infection.
你干嘛呢？那是我的信
What are you doing? That's my mail.
瞎看什么
Are you out of your mind?
我看你得用尿布了
You need to grab them goddamn diapers.
不用
No.
你得理智点
And get a fucking grip.
我才不当什么爹
I'm not a father.
国际乒联
- 哟 马蒂 - 干嘛？
- Yo, Marty. - What?
丽兹酒店是哪出？
What's the Ritz?
干嘛问这个？
Why?
你被国际乒联
You got a $1,500 fine
罚了1500美金
from the International Table Tennis...
【约1.2万美元 8.5万人民币 37万新台币】
- 什么？ - ...他们说...
- What? - ...Association and...
- 他们还... - 快拿给我
- And they... - Bring it in here!
- 他们还把你给禁赛了 - 给我
- And they banned your scrawny ass. - Give me that.
- 你没事吧？ - 你他妈从哪冒出来的？
- Are you okay? - Who the fuck are you?
快来帮我 快抬起来
God! Help me! Get this fucking thing off of me!
我的狗
My dog!
- 天呐 - 见鬼 出啥事了
- Holy shit! - Shit! What happened?
快点 从浴缸滚出来帮我
Come on! Get outta that fuckin' tub and help me!
我狗要淹死了 赶紧 帮我
My dog's drowning, man. Come on! Help me!
好 我要抬了 准备抽手
Okay, I'm flipping it. Take your arm out.
- 一 二 - 快抬
- One. Two. - Lift it off!
三
Three.
- 快把手抽出来 - 疼死了 疼死了
- Take your arm out! - Oh, my God! Oh, my God!
操 操
Fuck! Fuck!
哎呦 你的胳膊
Oh, fuck, your arm.
坐好 坐好 别看伤口
Lean back. Lean back. Don't look at it.
- 我得弄个止血带 - 噢 操
- I need to make a tourniquet. - Oh, fuck!
- 过来 把手给我 - 你要干嘛？
- Come here. Give me your arm. - What are you doing?
- 要干嘛？ - 手给我
- What are you doing? - Give me your arm.
- 该死 - 我的狗呢？
- Fuck. - Where's my dog?
别管那狗了 手给我
Don't worry about the dog! Give me your arm.
- 摩西 - 别乱动 别乱动
- Moses. - Do nothing. Do nothing.
有我在呢 别担心
I got you. Don't worry.
沃利 快叫救护车
Wally, call an ambulance!
- 你还好吧？ - 不 我一点也不好
- Are you good? - No, I'm not good.
我的眼镜呢？
Where are my glasses?
我是说 你受伤没？你刚从楼板掉下去了
I mean, are you hurt? You just fell through the floor.
真见鬼 我得把房钱要回来
Fucking horseshit. I'm getting our money back.
马蒂 咱们闯大祸了 得赶紧溜
Marty, we gotta get the fuck out of here.
才两块五 你别傻了
It's $2.50. What are you talking about?
我要的可不止两块五 你没懂吗？
I'm asking for way more than $2.50. You see what just happened?
在这等着 等着
Wait here. Wait.
- 等多久? - 十秒钟
- For how long? - Ten seconds.
我的鞋 我的衣服
My shoes, my clothes.
全湿透了 你们怎么搞的
Everything's soaking wet. It's a mess in there.
- 闭嘴吧 - 你得感谢没砸到你屋
- Why don't you put a sock in it? - You wanna switch?
- 嘿 - 是你 我跟你说过不能洗澡
- Hey. - You! I... I told you not to use the fucking shower.
你才没说 是你把房租给我的 懂吗？
No, you didn't. You're the one that rented me the room, okay?
我差点摔死
I could have broken my neck falling out of that ceiling.
再闹你现在也能死
That can fucking still happen too.
- 你在威胁我吗？ - 对 对
- Are you threatening me right now? - Yeah. Yeah.
- 居然敢威胁我？ - 对
- Rellay? You want to threaten me? - Yeah.
- 地下室锁了 - 谁拿了钥匙？
- Basement is locked! - Who's got the fucking key?
给我听好了 听好了 把房钱还给我
Listen, man! Listen! I want my money for my room...
- 救护车来了 - ...我还要赔偿
- Ambulance. - ...and I want a reimbursement
- 我的东西都毁了 - 你当真？
- for my shit that got ruined. - Are you serious?
- 废话 - 一分都不会给你
- Yes! - You're not gonna get your shit back.
- 一共七块五 - 一分钱也不给
- $7.50! - You'll get nothing.
【约90美元 630人民币 2,900新台币】
- 快点帮我 - 医护来了
- Come on. Help me! - Paramedics.
- 你们可来了 - 病人在哪儿？
- Good, you're here. - Where's the patient at?
就在那儿 手臂受伤了 流了好多血
He's in here. It's his arm. He's lost a lot of blood.
怎么回事?
What happened?
- 浴缸砸他身上了 - 浴缸砸他身上了？
- Bathtub fell on him. - Bathtub fell on him?
我胳膊没知觉了
I can't feel my arm.
吉米 你得替我照看好摩西
Yo, Jimmy. Come on, you gotta help me with this dog.
- 我这儿没人手 - 那就送他去兽医那儿
- I don't got nobody free. - We gotta get him to the vet.
- 真腾不出人手 - 他是我的家人
- I got nobody free right now. - He's my family, man.
听着 把两块五还我 我就走 七块五不要了
Listen, now. Just give me the $2.50, and I'll get outta here. Forget the $7.50.
- 把两块五给我就行 - 我做不了主
- Just give me $2.50. - I can't help you.
明天找老板要
See the owner tomorrow.
- 小子 - 都怪你的
- Kid. - It's your shitty ceiling
- 烂地板 - 小子 小子
- in this crummy hotel. - Kid. Oh!
- 什么都不给 - 什么？
- I ain't giving you nothing. - What?
小子 帮我把狗送到兽医那儿
Kid. Come on. Just bring the dog to the vet.
不行 我得工作 有活要干
I can't. I got work. I got a job.
- 我不能被开除 - 你有工作？
- I can't get fired. - You got a job?
- 我出双倍工钱 - 不 行不通 不行
- I'll give you double what you're getting. - No, I can't. I can't.
那就三倍 来吧
I'll give you triple. Come on.
- 别乱动 别乱动 - 行吧
- Take it easy. Calm down. - Okay.
好 打开那个包 椅子上的包
Okay, look in that bag. See the bag on the chair?
对 把包打开
Yeah, go in that bag, okay? Open it up.
我得给你上个止血带
I'm gonna apply a tourniquet to you.
换掉原来的
I'm gonna remove the other tourniquet right now.
拿50给你自己
Take 50 for yourself. Yeah.
【约600美元 4,100人民币 1.8万新台币】
再拿50给兽医 明白吗？
Bring 50 for the vet, okay?
有血喷出来
We got blood squirting out.
兽医在13街和1大道交口
He's on 13th and 1st.
告诉他我一完事就赶过去 懂吗？
And tell him I'll be there as soon as I can get there, okay?
你居然要给他钱？
You're gonna give this motherfucker money?
是这混蛋砸的你
He's the one who fuckin' dropped the tub on ya.
我警告过他别洗澡了
I told him not to get in the fuckin' bath.
小子 你一看就靠谱
Fucking mensch, kid.
准备抬 送他去贝尔维尤医院
Stretcher ready? We'll take him to Bellevue.
一看就靠谱
Fucking mensch.
现在掉头送他去兽医还来得及
We can still turn around and take him to the vet.
不用 不用
No. No.
- 50块绰绰有余了 - 什么比50大？是100块
- Fifty dollars is more than enough. - You know what's better than 50? 100.
100本钱能让咱大赚一笔
We can clean house with a hundred.
你个贪心的犹太鬼
Don't be greedy, you fucking Jew.
- 有1500美元罚款 你亲自拿给我的 别忘了 - 别叫了
- No, no. It's a $1,500 fine. You're the one that showed it to me. - Shut your mouth!
- 而且我们还得连赌两周夜场 - 我们？
- By the way, we gotta do this every night for two weeks, - "We"?
- 否则我就去不了日本了 - 不 不 不
- or else I can't go to Japan. - Oh, no, no, no.
我才不会因为你的错 为你耽误两周工作
I'm not taking two weeks off work 'cause you fucked up.
来 吃点这个 吃点这个
Hey. Take this, boy. Take this.
吃吧 好孩子
There you go. Good boy.
把这狗的项圈解开
Loosen up the collar on this motherfucker, man.
- 好 - 他都喘不过气了
- All right. - He sound like a radiator.
咱们先去赌
We're gonna go play,
回来顺路再送他去兽医
we'll drop him off at the vet on the way back.
- 这也就几个小时 - 马蒂 我有接送安排 别忘了
- What's a couple of hours to this guy? - Marty, I got rides set up, man.
叫摩西
Huh. Moses.
到你了 三号球道
Lane three. That's you.
- 你好 - 要点什么？
- Hi, how you doing? - Could I help?
还有球道吗？
Can I get a lane?
大概得等三四十分钟样子
Probably gonna be a half hour, 40 minutes.
- 没问题 - 你确定能等？
- That's okay. - You all right with that?
- 现在拿鞋吗？ - 我待会儿再拿
- You want shoes? - I'll just grab 'em later.
结束 输了
Done. Over.
弱得可怜 给钱
Fucking pathetic. Pay up.
谁来下一局？
Who wants next?
我来一局 嘿 怎么玩？
Can I play? Hey! Can I play?
- 一块钱一局 - 行吧
- It's a dollar a game. - Okay.
- 你叫什么？ - 塞思
- What's your name? - Seth.
先来几回热热身吧
Let's get a warm-up rally going.
不行 要打就押钱 否则滚蛋 我不白陪打
Nah. Put up or shut up. I don't play for free.
行吧 没听过这规矩
All right. Never heard of that.
- 我管账 - 钱给他
- I'm holding. - He's holding.
你管账？凭什么让他管？
You're holding? Why is he holding?
- 你带钱了吗？ - 不许耍赖
- Have you got yours? - Can I trust you?
相信我 没问题
Trust me, you can.
- 这句谁对谁？ - 塞思对阵罗杰
- Where are we at? - All right, Seth vs. Roger.
一块钱一局
Dollar game.
【约12美元 85人民币 375新台币】
我发球
I serve.
你干嘛呢？我还没准备好
What are you doing? I'm not even looking.
- 1比0 - 我刚才都没看
- One-zip. - I wasn't even looking.
- 不行 不能用手接球 - 什么？
- No, you can't do that. - What?
你要是接不到球
You gotta let the ball hit the other side.
就得让球自己落地 我得分
You can't catch it with your paddle. My point.
- 你在扯什么？ - 手接球不算
- What are you talking about? - You can't do that.
拍子接不住就得让球落地
You gotta let the ball fall off the table.
- 胡说八道 - 你犯规了
- That's ridiculous. - You're cheating.
- 我犯规了？ - 对 这就叫犯规
- I'm cheating? - Yeah, that's called cheating.
- 你没按规矩来 - 行吧 分给你
- You're not following the rules. - Fine. Take the point.
- 谢谢 把球给我 - 1比1
- Thank you. Give me the ball. - One-one.
见鬼
Fuck!
- 好险 - 打得好 打得好
- That was close. - That was good. That was good.
噢 不 不 不
Oh. No, no, no, no, no.
收着吧 收着吧
No, no. Take it.
我本该让你五分的 伙计
I should have spotted you, like, five points, man.
你今天够倒霉了 留着吧
You've had a rough enough day already. Keep it.
谢谢 伙计 谢谢
Thank you, brother. Thank you.
没事儿
It's all good.
打得不错
Good game.
好了 亚当 亚当 该你了
All right, Adam. Adam, let's go.
- 你想押多少？ - 五毛
- What do you want to put on? - I can go 50 cents.
你手里有球吗？
You got a ball?
你鼻子怎么回事？
What happened to your nose?
我有球 我有球
I got one, I got one.
有人赖账跑了
Fare ran out on me.
赖什么账？怎么回事？
Fare from what? What happened?
我开出租的 曼哈顿来的
I'm a taxi driver. From Manhattan.
- 曼哈顿？ - 对
- Manhattan? - Yeah.
那路费可不便宜 伙计
That's an expensive trip, man.
可不是 大概20块到25块呢
Oh, yeah. $20, $25.
碰上有钱的主儿
Well, the high rollers tip five,
还能再给5块小费
so that's five in tips. And...
我刚把他送到 那人从后面掐住我脖子
I fucking get to the spot, the guy chokes me out,
- 朝我后脑勺猛揍 - 不会吧
- punching me in the back of the head. - No.
然后抢了钱就跑
Takes my money and run the fuck off.
后来我追上那混蛋 你猜怎么着
Caught up to the motherfucker, and, boy...
我把他揍得眼冒金星
I beat the brights off that motherfucker, man.
我把他搜刮了个遍
And I took what he had.
你把他搜刮了？
You took what he had?
那当然 谁他妈的会放过
Hell, yeah! You fucking damn right.
- 你把钱踹你兜里？ - 当然了
- You added that to your roll? - Sure did.
就是那厚厚一大摞钞票
To that fat roll I've seen you pulling out.
这是原则问题 他妈的原则
It's principle. It's fucking principle!
我懂 但是建议你把钱藏好
I understand that. I would keep it hidden.
在这儿这种地方 最好别显摆
I would keep that down, if I were you, in this place.
可不是谁都像他那么面善
Not everybody's as nice as Christian is, I'm telling you.
这分是我的
That's my point.
那打球的臭小子是谁？
What about that asshole right there?
我哪知道那是谁
I don't know who the fuck that guy is.
- 你不能这么发球 - 为什么不能？
- You can't serve like that. - What do you mean?
我这么发球都好几年了
I've been serving like that for years.
- 嘿 罗杰 罗杰 给你说话呢 - 你们的规则真荒唐
- Hey, Roger. Roger. Hello. - That's ridiculous.
- 再打一分钟 - 球道轮到我们了
- Give me one more minute. - Our lane is open.
- 回来再打保龄球 - 不行 现在就得去
- The lane can wait. It's fine. - No, we gotta go now.
- 要不然就让给别人了 - 我正打乒乓呢
- They're gonna give it away. - I'm playing now.
为了打保龄球我都等一晚上了 赶紧的 快走
I have been waiting all night to bowl. Let's go. Come on.
罗杰
Roger.
- 我得分 - 瞎喊什么的
- My point. - Look what you made me do.
我不玩了
I gotta go.
- 什么意思？ - 把那一块钱还我
- What do you mean you gotta go? - Give me my dollar back.
比赛还没打完呢
We're in the middle of a game.
你走就算弃权 把我的钱也给我
You forfeit the game, then. Give me my dollar.
- 把我的钱也给我 - 别激动 退后点
- Give me my dollar back! - Relax. Back up, back up.
- 他弃权了 - 打完再给
- He's gonna leave the game? - You didn't finish the game.
行啊 那你接着打 你来打
All right, then you play. Then you play.
我没钱了 最后十块都给他了
I'm broke, man. I gave him my last ten.
我跟你打
I'll play you.
喔 喔 喔
Whoa, whoa, whoa.
哇塞 你们这种人也会玩桌球了
Oh, wow. I didn't know you guys played table tennis.
一块一局 你玩得起吗？
Put up a dollar. Do you have a dollar?
- 去你的 我押五块 - 你哪来的五块钱
- Fuck you. Put up five. - You don't have five dollars.
【约60美元 400人民币 1,900新台币】
哇塞 你肯定是抢来的吧
Oh, wow. You must have robbed someone.
有种你也把钱亮出来
Put your money where your mouth is.
不如我亮出家伙 教你做人
Why don't I put my penis where your mouth is?
计分的 沃利对阵这个混蛋
Red shirt, Wally and whatever the fuck his name is.
先别计分 回来再打
Mark it blank, baby. I'll be right back.
你去哪？
Where are you going?
那我先不计分
I will mark it blank!
看什么热闹呢？
What's going on here?
这黑小子要把钱输光了
The colored boy is about to lose all his money.
是啊 都输给这混蛋了
Yeah, to this asshole right here.
- 该死 - 赛点
- Fuck! - Match point.
- 赛点 来了 - 沃利 加油
- Match point. Here we go. - Wally! Come on!
沃利 加油别泄气
Don't get upset though, Wally. Let's go.
赢了
Yeah!
球擦边了 都他妈看见了吧
It grazed the edge. You fucking saw that.
没擦边
It didn't graze the edge.
- 球变向了 这看见了吧 - 没擦边
- It changed. You saw that. - It didn't graze the edge.
- 把钱给我 - 搞什么鬼?
- No, give me my money. - What the fuck?
- 把钱给我 - 这简直...
- Give me my money. - This is b--
把钱给我 钱给我
Give me the money. Give me the money.
- 钱给我 - 求你了
- Pay me. - Come on.
留我五块油钱行吗？
Let me hold five for gas money.
不行 你没钱还赌
No. You shouldn't bet with money you don't have.
- 车没油了 我怎么回家？ - 用脚
- How the fuck am I gonna get home? - Walk.
就给他留五块吧
Just let him keep five.
- 不行 - 你今晚够混蛋了
- No. - You've been a dick all night.
- 给钱 - 别再贪这点钱了
- Give me my money. - Just stop being greedy.
- 留他五块回家钱吧 - 太坑人了
- Just give him five to get home! - This is bullshit!
- 真是厚颜无耻 - 去死吧你
- And you're fucking smiling. - Fuck you!
把钱给我 把钱给我
Give me the money. Give me the money.
去死吧
Fuck you.
- 喂 给他留五块吧 - 不给
- Yo, give him his five. - I don't want to.
我怎么回家啊
How the fuck am I gonna get home?
这就是你吹牛的下场
That's what happens when you talk shit.
- 滋味不好受吧？ - 混蛋
- It stinks, doesn't it? - Fuck!
- 罗杰在哪儿 快出来？ - 该死
- Where's-- Where's Roger? - Shit.
- 我来了 - 快来 罗杰
- Yeah, I got it. - Yeah, Rog!
跟这混蛋打一局 把他油钱赢回来
Play this numbnuts for his gas money.
现在你得跟罗杰打 明白吗？
You're gonna play Roger now, okay?
- 加油 罗杰 - 加油
- Let's go, Roger. - Let's go.
- 快点 别磨蹭 - 你？
- Let's go right now. - You?
我不跟你打 你太厉害了
I won't play you. You're too good.
我让你4分
I'll spot you four points.
行 赌40块
Fine. Forty dollars.
【约490美元 3,300人民币 1.5万新台币】
40块？我没这么多钱
Forty dollars? I don't have forty dollars.
爱打就打 不打拉倒 我得走了
You want it? Take it or leave it. I gotta go.
- 40块 - 一 二 三...
- Forty dollars. - One, two, three...
谁还有钱 谁还有钱？
Come on, who's got cash? Who's got cash?
- 我帮你 - 都帮沃利出点
- I got you. - It's Team Wally. Come on.
来 来 来 都凑一凑 凑一凑 送他回家
Pitch in, pitch in. Let's get him home. Come on, come on.
谢谢大家 真谢谢大家
Thank you, everybody. Thank you.
一定给你赚出回家钱 一定
We're gonna get you home. We're gonna get you home.
谢谢 谢谢 你们不出钱吗？
All right. Great. Great. Nothing? This whole row?
嘿 我跟你单下一注
Yo, I'll put a side bet.
赌多少？
How much?
- 五块 - 你就这点钱？
- Five dollars. - You don't got more than that?
十块 哟 还有点钱嘛
Ten. Ooh, you got a little bit of money.
谢了 非常感谢
Thank you. Thanks so much.
♪ 你是我此生唯一的爱 ♪
♪ You're the only one ♪
174 175 176
One seventy-four, 175, 176,
♪ 他们老叫我胖子 ♪
♪ They call, they call me the fat man ♪
177 178 179 180 181...
177, 178, 179, 180, 181...
♪ 因为我体重两百斤 ♪
♪ 'Cause I weight two hundred pounds ♪
181 182 183...
181, 182, 183...
♪ 所有姑娘都爱我 ♪
♪ All the girls, they love me ♪
- 小毛毛回来了 宝贝 - ...184 185...
- The Mouse is back, baby. - ...184, 185...
- 太好了 - ...186
- Yeah! - ...186
♪ 因为我懂逗她们开心 ♪
♪ 'Cause I know my way around ♪
- 小毛毛回来了 宝贝 - ...187 192...
- The Mouse is back, baby! - ...187, 192...
- 噢 我最爱这段 - ...197 202 207...
- Oh, this is my part. - ...197, 202, 207...
♪ 哇 哇 哇 ♪
♪ Wah wah wah ♪
你要干什么？
What the fuck are you doing?
♪ 哇 哇 ♪
♪ Wah wah ♪
你疯了吗？
Are you out of your mind?
♪ 哇 哇 哇 哇 哇 哇 ♪
♪ Wah wah wah, wah wah wah ♪
♪ 哇 哇 哇 ♪
♪ Wah wah wah ♪
♪ 哇 哇 哇 哇 哇 哇 ♪
♪ Wah wah wah, wah wah wah ♪
♪ 哇 哇 哇 ♪
♪ Wah, wah, wah ♪
白跑了 关门了
Fuck. It's closed.
- 去下个镇子吧 - 下个镇子？马上就没油了
- Let's just go to the next town. - Next town? That shit is 20 minutes away.
真是乖孩子 真是乖孩子
You see what we do? Who's a good boy? Who's a good boy?
- 400... - 过来 宝贝
- 400... - Come over here, baby.
...401 402 403...
...401, 402, 403...
他呼吸顺畅多了
His breathing's a lot better.
咱们也许不用给兽医送钱了
We might not have to give the vet any money.
...407 408
...407, 408.
408块 每人204块 咱俩平分
408. That's 204 each. That's 50-50.
【408美元 约5,000美元 3.4万人民币 15.7万新台币】
给 拿着
Here, here. Okay.
沃利 要不你先把钱都给我
Wally, I was thinking. If you give me the full amount now,
我从日本回来给你十倍
I can give you ten times that when I get back from Japan.
- 别闹 小毛毛 - 你什么意思？
- Stop, stop. Stop, Mouse. - No, no, what do you mean?
别想拿坑别人的那套来坑我
You're not gonna fuck me like you do everybody else.
- 你看到罚单了 别忘了 - 毛毛
- You saw the fine. You saw it. - Mouse.
我回来还你十倍
I'm gonna be coming home with ten times that.
- 我给你买个出租车牌照 - 别拿牌照忽悠我 毛毛
- I'll buy you a medallion. - I don't want no fucking medallion, Mouse.
那给你买辆新车 别难为我
I'll buy you a new cab. Don't give me a hard time about this.
他在那儿
There he is!
逮到你了 王八蛋
Hey, motherfucker!
完了 马蒂 马蒂 快上车 快上车
Oh, fuck. Marty. Marty, let's go. Get in the car.
- 别慌 别慌 - 快上车
- Okay, just let me do the talking. - Get in the car!
逮到他了 搞死这王八蛋
Look who it is! Let's get this motherfucker!
几位 晚上好
Gentlemen.
怎么了？哥几个还好吧？
What's going on? How are we doing?
- 把钱还我们 - 你们在说什么？
- Give us our money! - What are you talking about?
- 我正给这哥们加油呢 - 看看这是谁
- I'm giving this guy some gas. - Look who it is.
别玩这套!
Don't pull that shit!
- 你他妈设局坑我们 - 我没设局
- You fucking hustled us! - I didn't hustle anyone.
我认出你了 你是他妈的马蒂·毛瑟
I know who you are! You're fuckin' Marty Mauser!
- 冷静点 - 我就没听说过这个名字
- Relax! - I don't know who that is!
罗杰 住手 住手
Roger! Stop it! Stop!
别 别冲动 有话好说
No, relax. Relax. Relax. Relax.
滚出这破车
Out of the fucking car!
滚出这破车 你这黑鬼
Get out of the fucking car, nigger!
- 凭什么要我... - 滚出来
- Why I gotta be-- - Get the fuck out!
去你们的
Fuck!
- 马蒂 赶快上车 - 去你们的
- Marty, let's fucking go! - Fuck yourself!
走 走 走 走 快走
Go, go, go, go, go.
沃利 注意 注意 电线杆
Wally, watch out! Watch out! The pole!
不 不
No! No!
沃利 狗掉了 狗掉下去了 沃利
Wally, the dog. The dog, Wally.
- 管他的狗 - 不能丢下那狗
- Fuck that dog! - I need the dog!
去他的狗
Fuck the dog,
- 天呐 不 不 - 也去你的 去你的
- Oh, no. No! - and fuck you, man! Fuck you, man!
我这回赔大了
They'll take this out of my paycheck!
车都废了 得从我工资里扣 我要丢工作了
My car's fucked up, man! I'm gonna lose my fucking job!
这是我全部生计 我还有家要养呢
This is all I got! I got people depending on me!
- 我有一大堆担子要扛 - 我也有啊
- I got real responsibilities! - I got responsibilities too.
- 你有个屁 - 你他妈觉得...
- No, you don't! - What the fuck you think--
♪ ...也许还能融化 ♪
♪ ...may melt again ♪
♪ 像冬雪被四月的雨 ♪
♪ Like winter snow that melts ♪
♪ 一点点 ♪
♪ With ♪
♪ 冲散 ♪
♪ April rain ♪
♪ 亲爱的 亲爱的 ♪
♪ For darling, in my heart ♪
♪ 你永远住在我心里 ♪
♪ You always will remain ♪
♪ 即便夏去秋来 ♪
♪ As summer turns to fall ♪
太感谢你了 太感谢了
Thank you so much. Thank you.
我会补偿你的
I'm gonna make it up to you. All right?
别生我气 行吗?
Don't be mad at me. Okay?
我会给你买辆新出租 真的
I'm gonna get you a new cab. All right?
别担心 沃利 我的好兄弟
Don't worry about it. Wally, I love you.
关门好吗
Close my door.
嘿 马蒂
Hey, Marty.
（劳伦斯百老汇球场）
- 嘿 泰德 - 嘿 马蒂 近来怎样？
- Hey, Ted. - Hey, Marty. How you doing, man?
- 劳伦斯在吗？ - 听说令尊的事情了 请节哀
- Is Lawrence here? - Sorry about your loss.
没事的 劳伦斯来了吗？
It's all right. Is Lawrence here tonight?
来了 应该就在里边吧
Uh, yeah. He's around here somewhere.
- 好的 我去找下 谢了 - 行 行
- Okay. All right. Thank you. - Yeah, yeah.
- 欢迎回来伙计 - 嗯
- Good to see you, man. - Yep.
- 马蒂 - 近来可好？
- Hi, Marty. - How you been?
- 好久不见 - 你好 你好
- Nice to see you. - Hello, Marty.
今晚能借住你后屋吗 求你了
Hey, can I stay in your back room tonight, please?
嘿 嘿 你的小妞在后头呢 知道吗？
Hey, hey. Got your girl in the back, okay?
她怀孕了 现在心情挺糟的
She pregnant. She real upset.
天呐 好吧 知道了
Oh, God. Okay. All right.
我去看看她
Uh, let me go talk to her,
但你千万别走开 我马上回来
but then please don't leave without finding me.
- 放心 我就在这儿 - 好 很高兴见到你
- Yeah, I'll be here. Okay. - All right. Nice to see you.
- 也很高兴见到你 - 嗯
- All right, good to see you. - Okay.
嘿 你来这干嘛啊？
Hey. What are you doing here?
我不想麻烦你 我知道你很忙
I don't mean to bother you. I know you're really busy.
- 你这脸怎么回事 谁干的？ - 我真没地方落脚了
- What the hell happened to your face? - I didn't really have anywhere else to go.
- 让我看看 - 他突然就开始...
- Let me see. - He just started...
他突然就开始朝我大吼
he just started yelling at me.
跟疯了一样 还扯我的衣服不撒手
And he was really mad and he was ripping my clothes.
- 他打的？ - 他把我吓坏了
- He did this to you? - He was really scaring me.
我真没别处可去了
I just didn't know where else to go.
你会怪我吗？
Are you mad at me?
瑞秋？
Rachel?
不 不是瑞秋 是马蒂 开门
No, it's not Rachel. It's Marty. Open the door.
等下
Okay. Hang on.
你怎么来...
What are you doing here?
活该
Shame on you.
嘿 迪翁 你好啊 真是打扰了
Hey, Dion. How you doing, man? I really appreciate this.
这是我妹妹 瑞秋
This is my sister Rachel, by the way.
瑞秋 这是我朋友 也是我生意伙伴迪翁
Rachel, this is my buddy, my business partner, Dion.
- 嘿 - 嘿
- Hey. - Hey.
她家被水淹了
Her place flooded.
她得借宿一晚 不麻烦吧？
She needs a place to crash for the night. That's okay, right?
我说不好
I don't know, man, it's...
我懂 但我不能让她住在都发霉有毒的地方啊
I know, but I can't have her exposed to mold and spores and shit.
迪翁 帮个忙 她都怀孕八个月了 懂吗？
D, come on, she's eight months pregnant, all right?
帮个忙
Come on...
那孩子是我外甥
That's my nephew.
我家规矩不让带别人回来的
I'm not supposed to have people over.
她家真没法住了 我不能让她回去 求你了
She's got a bad situation at home. I can't have her going back there. Please.
好吧 好吧 那就住一晚
All right. Come on. You can spend the night.
但明天我爸妈回来前就得离开
You just gotta be out of here by tomorrow before my parents get back.
没问题
Okay. No problem.
咱们得趁碰这次碰面好好商量下
We should take advantage of the time we have together.
把生意计划好好商量一下
You know, really firm up our business plan.
这样你爸一回来 肯定对你另眼相看
That way, when your dad gets back, he sees how organized we are.
是啊 他挺失望的
Yeah, he's pretty upset.
这堆货丢这儿 你八个月都没管
You left us with all of this inventory for eight months.
没关系 几周后我拿下世界冠军
That's fine. In a few weeks I'll take the championship.
一切都会重回正轨
We'll be right back on track.
- 球就都在这儿 - 真的？哪儿？
- Balls are right in here. - Really? Where?
最上头的箱子
The top box.
谢谢
Thanks.
- 哇 你做出橙球了？ - 是
- Whoa. You did the orange? - Yep.
怎么做的？
How'd you do the orange?
我联系了哈克斯公司
I contacted someone at Halex.
他们给塑料上的色
They colored the celluloid for me.
- 怎么办到的？ - 花钱 宝贝
- How? - Money, baby.
我和我老爸都看好你
Me and my pop, we believe in you.
我们投了钱的 你消失了 所以他挺生气的
We're invested. That's why he's been so mad.
瞧瞧这个 瑞秋
Check it out, Rachel.
来 看看这包装
Here, check out the packaging.
e
“至尊马蒂牌 马蒂·毛瑟冠军赛官方用球”
"Marty Supreme. The official Marty Mauser championship table tennis ball.
e
f
“精心打造 橙球...”
Professionally made. Orange..."
f
这宣传词 你想出来了？
Orange spheres? You came up with that?
是啊 不错吧
Yeah. Pretty good, right?
不错吧？迪翁 这让我刮目相看
Pretty good? Dion, this is... I'm stunned.
刮目相看
I'm stunned.
- 而且还是手绘的 - 你画的？
- Hand-drawn too. - You drew this?
- 对 - 真是神来之笔
- Yeah. - It's inspired.
多谢夸奖
I appreciate it.
你都不知道自己多有能耐
I don't think you know what you're capable of.
g
- 你瞧瞧 - 过奖
- Check it out. - Thanks a lot.
哇
Wow.
确实很漂亮
it's really nice.
- 这是你房间？ - 不是 是我弟弟的
- This is your room? - No, it's my brother's.
你还有弟弟？你怎么没跟我说过
You have a brother? You never told me you had a brother.
他已经毕业了 搬出去住了
It's a younger brother. He moved out.
那这房间空着？
So his room is free?
- 嗯 对 - 我先去安顿一下我妹
- Uh, yeah. - Let me get my sister situated.
- 五分钟后去找你 - 行
- I'll come find you in five minutes. - Okay.
马上见
Five minutes.
迪翁 你真让我刮目相看
I'm really impressed, D.
- 过奖 - 真佩服你
- Thank you. - Seriously.
这家伙真不一般
Special guy.
我去把床弄好 你就安心躺着吧
Let me get the bed comfortable for you, all right?
现在就要走了吗？
So are you gonna go out there now?
对 我得琢磨下明天的计划
Yeah, I gotta figure my plan out for tomorrow.
什么？什么计划？
Why? Plan for what?
我得把心态收拾好
Well, I need to get my head together.
怎么个收拾法儿？
How so?
有个有钱佬找我干活 我打算联系他
This rich guy hit me up for a job. I think I'm gonna get in touch with him.
- 真的？ - 是啊
- Really? - Yeah.
- 什么活？干什么？ - 不重要 能去日本就行
- A job for what? What job? - It doesn't matter. Just to get to Japan.
- 去打世锦赛吗？ - 对
- For the championship? - Yeah.
哇
Wow.
生活一团糟 我会找到出路的
Everything in my life is falling apart, but I'm gonna figure it out.
要帮忙吗？我可以帮你
Do you need any help? I could help you.
- 没事 不用了 - 要帮忙吗？
- No, it's all right. It's all right. - Can I do anything?
你饿吗？
Are you hungry?
- 不饿 - 确定？
- No. - You sure?
你休息吧 我就在隔壁
Uh, I'll just be in the other room, all right?
- 迪翁 这球是绝无仅有的 - 我就说吧 老兄
- Dion, I've never seen anything like this. - I told you, man.
老兄 咱们得好好叙叙旧
Man, we have to have a big catch-up
这是八个月来我经历的最好的事
'cause this is the greatest thing that's happened to me in the last eight months.
找哈克斯 真天才啊
Who would've thought? Halex?
早上好 罗克韦尔墨业公司
Good morning. Rockwell Ink.
喂 你好 麻烦帮我接米尔顿·罗克韦尔先生
Yes, hi, can I speak to Milton Rockwell, please?
他暂时不在 需要留个言吗？
He's not in at the moment. Can I take a message?
好吧 他什么时候回来？
Okay, when are you expecting him?
他今天外出
Well, he's working off-site today.
- 要不要留言？ - 小心烫
- Again, can I take a message? - It's hot.
太感谢了
Thank you so much.
等我妹醒了 能给她也弄份吗？
Can you make some for my sister for when she wakes up?
- 她肯定饿得要命 - 喂？
- She'll be really hungry. - Hello?
你刚说他外出 具体在哪儿？
You said off-site where?
抱歉 这个信息我不能透露
I'm sorry, I can't give you that information.
- 您到底要不要留言？ - 要
- Would you like to leave a message or not? - Yes.
能替我向他道个歉吗？
Can you apologize to him on my behalf?
我是原本今早要和他一起吃早饭的
I was the young gentleman that was supposed to have breakfast
那个年轻人
with him this morning.
- 我对这事不熟 - 就是他儿子那个营的
- I'm not familiar. - From his son's battalion.
抱歉 我 我对此一无所知
I'm sorry, I-- I don't know anything about that.
我手上有他儿子的遗物 要交给他
I have some personal belongings of his son's I was supposed to give to him.
信件啊纪念品什么的 但我睡过头来不及了
Letters and mementos and such, but I messed up and I overslept.
我今天就要走了 要不我回头寄给他？
I'm leaving town today, but I could mail it to him if that's easier.
- 不 不 不 不行 - 不行？好的
- No, no, no. - No? Okay.
这样吧 你给莫罗斯科剧院打个电话问问
How about this, why don't you try giving a call over to the Morosco Theatre.
好 莫罗斯科剧院
The Morosco Theatre.
所以我算什么？我这是干嘛啊
So, I'm like what? What am I doing?
真不该来 好好晚上被你毁了
Coming up here to wreck my night.
说真的 妈 你怎么会在这种地方
Honest, Mama, I didn't even know you were coming here.
我受够了你这套把戏
I'm through with you playing games.
我只是来找点乐子
I was just coming for a good time.
听说应召女郎都在这儿
I heard this was where all the call girls gather.
我在努力攒钱重建生活 你不明白吗？
I'm trying to rebuild my life here. Don't you understand that?
你这是出卖自己吧
More like selling out to the highest bidder.
你没资格评判我 小杰
You've got no right to judge me, Jed.
我拼尽全力才换来那么一点幸福
I fought tooth and nail for every shred of happiness
- 我拼尽全力... - 那你给过我什么？
- I've ever found while you... - Right, and what did you give to me?
你从没相信过我 一次都没有
You never believed in me. Not once!
少装可怜 你自生自灭吧
You wanna wallow in self-pity? Well, here's an oven, Jed!
阿尔玛 别
Alma!
我没事 亨利
I'm all right, Henry.
- 给我们点时间 - 我妈就是个婊子
- Just give us a minute, please. - My mama is a dirty bird.
嘴放干净点 杰迪代亚
Be careful now, Jedidiah.
你给她的那身花衣服 只是掩盖她的耻辱
And that fancy dress you put her in is the only thing keeping in the stench!
别打我儿子
Don't you lay a hand on my child.
我...抱歉
I-I'm sorry, uh...
妈 完蛋了
Mama, what did I do?
走 快跑
Go! Run!
- 谁把门锁了 - 真会打断
- The door is locked. - Oh, my God.
谁锁的啊
You've gotta be kidding me!
正演戏呢？谁干的 谁给锁的啊
For Christ's sake, did somebody put a latch on the door?
- 噢天呐 - 我们刚进入节奏
- Oh, God. - I thought we had a good rhythm going.
进入节奏？演成这样叫节奏？还我们？
A good rhythm going? On what planet is that a good rhythm
- 你不顾其他人吗？ - 我入戏了
- if you're alone in a room? - I was in it.
搞得跟我不在场一样 入戏？独角戏？
It's like I wasn't even there. In it? In what?
- 格伦 我连句台词都插不进去 - 我懂 咱们会解决的
- Glenn, I couldn't get a word out. - I understand. We're gonna fix it.
- 排练就是为了解决这些 - 真绝了
- That's what a rehearsal process is for. - Fuck's sake.
先停一下吧 大家休息五分钟
Let's lose this, by the way. Everybody take five.
帮个忙 各位...
Do me a favor, everybody...
得有人跟他说说这事
Somebody needs to tell him something.
- 真离谱 - 真离谱
- It's impossible. - Impossible.
- 喝水吗？ - 喝
- Do you want some water? - Yes.
- 我去给你拿点 - 天呐
- Let me bring you some. - God.
嘿 凯
Hey, Kay.
是我 马蒂
Hey, it's Marty.
伦敦那个
From London.
你怎么跑这了？
What are you doing here?
来见个朋友 他搞舞台的
Well, I got a friend in the stagehands union.
我过来给他送点东西
I was dropping something off for him.
- 你刚才看了吧 - 看了 没关系吧
- You watched that? - Yeah, I hope that's okay.
噢 天呐
Oh, God.
没想到你又开始演戏了
Hey, I can't believe you're acting again.
那不叫演戏 他老抢我戏
That wasn't acting. He won't let me act.
挺气人的 那家伙什么来头？
Yeah, no, that looked frustrating. What's the deal with that guy?
别提了
Don't get me started.
即便被抢戏 你也比他演得好
Yeah, you were running circles around him.
那还用说
Of course I am.
对 演得真好
Yeah. It was unbelievable.
他连续三天不睡觉
He stays up for three days in a row
就是为了要演得累
because his character is supposed to be tired.
- 真是疯了 - 对啊
- It's obnoxious. - Oh, God.
他要真投入 怎么会因为那锁打断？
If he's so committed, why'd he stop the scene?
干嘛不一脚踹开？
Why didn't he punch his hand through the screen,
接着演呢？
unlock it from the other side?
- 对吧？换我会这么干 - 格伦
- Right? That's what I would've done. - Glenn!
- 这就来 - 格伦
- Yeah. - Glenn!
- 好的 来了 - 我跟你说句话
- Yes. Thank you. Yes. - I need to talk to you.
- 怎么了？ - 你说怎么了
- Yes, what? - What? What? What?
这小子比他更懂这个角色
This kid understands the character better than he does.
你说什么？
Excuse me?
- 把你刚说的话告诉他 - 不 我不想说
- Tell him what you just told me. - No, I don't want to.
说吧 告诉他
No, tell him.
我说你不像是真入戏了
I was just saying you didn't really seem like you were in the scene is all.
- 他懂不懂戏？ - 当局者迷
- Uh, who is this? - He's nobody.
- 旁观者清 - 而且 在我看来
- That's the point. - Also, you know, in my experience,
只有玩过家家才这样拿刀
only children hold a knife like this.
要是真打 刀该这样拿
If it's a serious fight, you hold your knife like this,
- 刀要在上面 - 这又不是街头斗殴
- with the blade square to your wrist. - This is not a street fight.
好吧 既然你们不求真的话
Okay, well, if you're not going for realistic,
还得再加点花样
you might as well add a little flair.
就像这样
Like that.
- 别闹了 - 对吧 凯？
- Cut it out. - Right, Kay?
行了 行了 谢了你的教程 谢谢
Yeah, okay. Thanks for the tutorial. Thank you very much.
真是太感谢了 抓紧走吧 谢谢
Thank you very much indeed. That's all we need today. Thank you.
- 加油 凯 - 送他出去
- Best of luck, Kay. Best of luck. - Get him out!
这里不需要你了 谢谢 抓紧走吧
We no longer require your presence. Thank you very much.
恕我直言...
Well, with all due respect...
每套布景竟然都要5000多块
And yet every set cost more than $5,000.
要让您太太高兴又少花钱 真办不到啊
I can't just snap my fingers and get your money and your wife into alignment.
那我花钱雇你干嘛
I pay you to say no.
让她感觉有主导权 又要控制她开销
She seems to think that this is carte blanche.
这根本做不到啊
I can't just perform the impossible here.
要是你做不到 我就另请他人
If you can't control her, I will find someone else who can.
混蛋
Asshole.
罗克韦尔先生 请等一下
Mr. Rockwell. Mr. Rockwell.
- 干什么？ - 是我 马蒂·毛瑟 又见面了
- What? - Hey. Marty Mauser. Nice to see you.
是不是你冒充我儿子战友给我办公室打的电话？
Did you call my office and say you're friends with my son?
- 是的 但是... - 混蛋
- Yes. But... - Goddamn it!
我没别的办法联络您了 请您听我说
I had no other way to get in touch with you. Please.
我想再谈谈去日本的事
I wanna revisit our conversation about Japan.
我重新考虑过了 我想去 我觉得主意不错
I reconsidered it and I wanna do it. I think it's a great idea.
比赛就在下周 我已经有别的计划了
The event's next week. I've made alternate plans.
别的计划？这最初可是您的主意
What other plans? Okay, it was your idea.
这主意棒极了 求您给我两分钟谈谈
It's a fantastic idea. Let's just have a conversation about this for two seconds.
你干什么呢？嘿 嘿 罗克韦尔先生
What are you doing? Hey. Hey. Mr. Rockwell.
求您了 咱们务实些
Please, let's both be pragmatists about this.
把私人感情放一边
Put your personal feelings about me aside for a second.
您也知道 我和远藤合作能带来多少好处
You and I both know how much value I would add with Endo.
在他的主场打表演赛？
In an exhibition on his home turf?
势必会引爆全场
Imagine it. I'd be like a stick of dynamite.
不管您的备选计划是什么
Whatever you have planned, the alternative,
都比不上这个
it's gonna pale in comparison.
请给我两分钟
Please give me two minutes.
我们还能达成共识 求您了
We have enough common ground to figure this out. Please!
- 行吧 上车说 - 真的？谢谢
- All right, get in the car. - Really? Thank you.
汤米 开车
Tommy, let's go.
嘿 嘿 嘿 嘿
Hey. Hey! Hey! Hey!
你这王八蛋 桌球还是我给你引荐的
You son of a bitch. I gave you the idea!
不好意思 凯·斯通女士让我转告你
I'm sorry. Ms. Stone wanted to let you know
她想与您共进午餐
that she'd love to have lunch with you.
- 凯·斯通？ - 是的
- Ms. Stone? - Yes.
天呐 我迟到太久了
My God, I'm so late.
在意这些干嘛
Come on. What do you care?
你可是主角 心里应该爽才对
You're the star. Gotta feel pretty good, right?
话说 你当初为啥退出演艺圈？
I mean, why'd you even stop in the first place?
我想要个保障 结果怀孕了
I wanted security, and I got pregnant,
他又给我压力 我就答应了
and he pressured me, and I settled.
眼下你是走对路了
Well, I mean, clearly, you're doing the right thing now
而且他看起来正加倍补偿你
and it sounds like he's paying you back with interest.
- 谁补偿？ - 你丈夫
- Who is? - Your husband.
你的演出都是他出钱吧？
I mean, he's funding your whole show, right?
哪来的这种想法？
Where'd you get that idea?
我在走廊无意听到他嘟囔这些
I overheard him complaining about it in the lobby.
- 嘟囔？ - 是的 抱怨开销太大
- Complaining? - Yeah, about the costs.
让他滚一边去吧
He can go fuck himself.
没错 彻底滚蛋
Completely. You know what you should do,
你应该把他榨干
you should leech him for every penny he's worth,
把自己捧成最红的星
assume your place as the biggest star on the planet,
然后狠狠打他那张自大嘴脸
and then you rub it in his smug little face.
谢谢 我可不想听你的人生建议
Thank you, but I'm really not looking for life advice from you.
不 我只是说 你根本不用靠他
No, I'm just saying you clearly never needed him in the first place.
就像我 绝不靠谁帮忙
Like with me, I'm never accepting anyone's help.
我只靠我自己 靠我的手艺
I gotta do it completely on my own. Purely on the basis of my own talent.
不然的话 奖杯都被玷污了
Otherwise it's, like, the success won't even count.
这只是我自己的观念
But that's just me.
说起来倒是容易
Yes, well, that's very easy to say.
说起来容易 做起来可真难
Well, it's easy to say but it's sure not easy to do.
你懂的 所以你才拿钱退圈了
I mean, you know that. That's why you cashed out.
我问你个事
Let me ask you something.
你靠这门小桌球挣到钱了吗？
Do you make money at this little table tennis thing?
- 还没呢 - 你有工作吗？
- Not yet. - Do you have a job?
没有 我是说 桌球就是我的工作
No. I mean, table tennis is my job.
那你靠什么糊口？
How do you live?
我靠信念
I live with the confidence
只要我相信自己 钱自然会来的
that if I believe in myself, the money will follow.
归根结底 我奋斗的重点不是钱
Ultimately, my struggle isn't even about money.
- 你怎么交房租？ - 不交
- How do you pay rent? - I don't.
- 你是在回避问题 - 不 我没回避
- You're avoiding the question. - No, I'm not avoiding anything.
那今天你打算怎么吃饭？
How do you plan on eating food today?
说实话 我打算你一走就叫客房送饭来
Honestly, I was gonna order room service the second you leave.
- 真行啊 - 是啊 是啊
- Nice. - Yeah. Nice.
要是你这梦想行不通 你有什么打算？
And what do you plan to do if this whole dream of yours doesn't work out?
我压根不会想这种事情
That doesn't even enter my consciousness.
好吧 也许你得考虑一下现实了
Okay. Well, maybe it should.
哇
Wow.
你这口气真像我妈 随便说说
You sound like my mom. No offense.
你倒像个小屁孩
And you sound like a child.
是吗？我可够成熟的
Oh, yeah? Clearly I'm old enough.
你什么意思？
And what is that supposed to mean?
成熟到能在你东山再起的时候
That I'm old enough to fuck you in your hotel room
在酒店干你一场 还是你的酒店
in the middle of your big comeback.
你真下流
You're disgusting.
祝演出顺利
Break a leg.
我明白 不过我在外地
No, I know, but I was out of town
这信我昨天才刚收着
so I only just received it yesterday for the first time.
去日本行程已经订好了 改不了了
Well, look, not coming to Japan is not an option.
麻烦跟拉姆·塞西说 全额的
Okay, well, just let Mr. Sethi know that a cashier's check in the full amount
银行担保的赔付支票已经寄出
is already on the way to him. It's in the mail.
不介意 只是...
No, that's fine, but just...
别在现场一见到我就惊讶
I don't want any confusion about my attendance.
我一定到场 开赛时肯定见得着我
I'm gonna be there. I'm gonna be there when the tournament starts.
- 找到了 - 太好了 太好了 太好了
- I got it! - Yes! Yes! Yes!
能值多少钱？
How much do you think?
- 这是假货 - 假货？你什么意思？
- This is not real. - What do you mean it's not real?
- 完全赝品 - 这可是从大富婆脖子上摘下来的
- Total fake. - It came from the neck of a millionaire.
我亲眼看着摘下来的
I saw it come off her neck.
我不管来路 这玩意不值钱
I don't care where it came from. It's total garbage.
- 装饰用的仿制品 - 装饰用的？
- Costume jewelry. - Costume jewelry?
- 嗯 - 该死
- Yeah. - Oh, fuck.
想卖的话 我最多给你两块钱
If you want, I can give you two bucks for it.
- 喂 - 喂 迪翁 是我
- Hello. - Hey, Dion. It's me.
忙不忙啊
How are you doing?
你跑哪去了？你答应过要准备经销商名单的
Hey, where have you been? You promised me we'd have a list of distributors.
我爸今晚就回来了
My dad lands tonight.
我这就回去 全力做这件事
I'll come back now and give you my undivided attention.
先让我跟我妹说句话
Let me just talk to my sister for a second.
瑞秋 马蒂来电话了
Rachel, Marty's on the phone.
- 喂 你在哪儿？ - 喂 瑞秋 听好了
- Hi. Where are you? - Hi, Rachel, listen.
我夹克里有个狗项圈
There's a dog collar in my jacket, okay?
有个人狗在新泽西丢了
I know a guy who lost a dog out in New Jersey.
他会付大笔赏金
He'll pay a big reward.
还有 他家车钥匙在门口小碗里
Also, there's a set of car keys in a bowl by the front door.
- 看见了吗？ - 看见了
- You see them? - Yeah.
拿上钥匙 把车开来 别让迪翁瞧见
Grab the keys, and make sure Dion doesn't see you do it.
嘿 迪翁
Hey, Dion.
能去商店帮我买点生姜吗？
Can you go to the store and grab me some ginger?
我晨吐反应特别厉害
I'm having really bad morning sickness.
嗨
Hi.
抱歉 加油站打样了
Sorry, station's closed.
没事 我们不是来加油的
That's okay. We're not looking for service.
你们附近有看到跑丢的狗吗？
Did you see a dog come around here?
没 没见着 你瞧见狗了吗？
Nah, I ain't seen nothing. You seen a dog?
- 差不多这么高 - 什么时候丢的？
- He's this tall. - When did you lose it?
几天前
A few days ago.
克兰伯里有个收容所 往那走大概八公里
There's a pound down in Cranberry. About five miles that way.
- 问问他们 - 我打过电话了
- Maybe try there. - I called there.
- 抱歉 帮不上忙 - 好吧
- Sorry, can't help you. - Okay.
谢谢
Thank you.
没人看到狗
They didn't see anything.
咱们去那里试试
Let's go try that place.
有人在家吗？
Hello.
有人吗?
Hello?
- 你去哪？ - 我去后面瞧瞧
- Where are you going? - Just gonna check out back.
我去 摩西
Oh, shit. Moses.
“我们非常感谢全国各地的唱片商和艺术家们”
"We're grateful to the record manufacturers and artists
“全国各地的艺术家们”
all over the country."
嘿 狗狗 嘿 嘿 摩西
Hey, buddy. Hey. Hey, Moses.
是我 马蒂 乖狗狗
It's Marty. Hey, buddy.
该死
Oh, fuck.
乖狗狗
Hey, buddy.
摩西 摩西
Moses. Moses!
冷静 冷静 我来带你回家
Hey, buddy. Calm down. Let's get you home.
想不想回家？走 咱们回家
You wanna go home, right? Let's go home.
好了 别 别 别
Okay. Hey. No, no, no, no, no.
“刚才为您播放的是佩珀敏特·哈里斯”
"And that was Peppermint Harris
“以及他的那首金曲...”
"and that great record of his...
“不过现在是时候暂别这档节目了”
"But it's time to hang up the old blunderbuss for now.
“记住 如果你想...”
"Remember, if you want any..."
- 你好？ - 有事吗？
- Hi, how are you? - Can I help you?
我们狗丢了 正在找狗
We were just searching the area for a lost dog.
- 你们？ - 我和我丈夫
- "We"? - My husband and I.
我们的狗几天前在加油站附近丢了
We lost our dog a couple of days ago out near the gas station
他们叫我们来这边瞧瞧...
and they told us to come and check over here...
- 因为你是最近的一户人家 - 谁？
- seeing that you're the closest house. - Who?
谁让你来的？哪个加油站？
Who? Which gas station?
- 我说不上来 - 嘿
- I don't know. - Hey!
是加油站伙计说的
It was one of the guys that work there.
- 老兄 你终于来了 - 我丈夫
- Oh, man, I'm so excited you're back. - There he is!
- 看来你捡到了我们的狗 - 你们在私闯民宅
- I think you might've found our dog. - You're trespassing.
别误会 抱歉打扰了 我们听到后院有狗叫
No. I'm sorry, that's not our intention. We heard barking in the back.
我不懂你在说啥
I have no idea what you're talking about.
我的狗 被你捡到了
My dog. You found it.
我没捡过狗
I didn't find any dog.
你确定？
Are you sure?
我当然确定 你呢？
Yeah, I'm sure. Are you sure?
是啊...
Yeah...
我趴着你那窗户
I looked through your window.
- 看到了我的狗 - 你竟然偷看我窗户？
- I saw my dog. - You were looking through my window?
是啊 不看怎么找到的
Yeah, It was a good thing I did, right?
趁我报警前 赶紧滚出我的地盘
Get the hell off my property before I call the police.
该叫警察的是我才对
You call? I should call the police.
行啊 要不要再核实下看清楚？
Okay. You wanna get a closer look at him?
- 近距离看清楚？ - 是的 麻烦了
- You wanna closer look? - Yes, please.
行 我就让你看清楚
Okay, good, good. I'll give you a closer look.
嘿
Hey!
冷静点
Calm down.
我很冷静
I am calm.
- 你这张犹太脸... - 你认真的？
- If I see your kike face... - Are you serious?
- ...再敢偷瞄我窗户 - 马蒂 快上车
- ...looking through my window again... - Marty, get in the car!
- 你疯了吗？ - ...我我就把你脸打烂
- Are you out of your mind? - ...I'm gonna shoot it off.
别把事搞大 我们这就走 马蒂 快上车
There's no need for that. We're leaving. Marty, get in!
你疯了吗？
What are you doing?
- 马蒂 快上车 - 不行 必须得拿到狗
- Get in the car, Marty! - No! I need the dog!
- 快上车 - 看我不打爆你的脸
- Get in the car! - Next one's going to your face.
马蒂 快...
Marty, get...
哦 不 不 不 别开枪 别开枪
No, no, no, no! Don't shoot! Don't shoot!
瑞秋 快帮我
Rachel! Help me!
马蒂 快上车
Marty, get in the car!
快点 快点 快跑 快跑
Come on, come on, come on. Hurry! Hurry!
上车 上车 上车
Get in! Get in! Get in!
开车 开车 开车 快开 瑞秋 快
Go, go, go straight, Rachel. Go, go!
超前开 快 开进玉米地
Straight! Go! Go in the corn!
- 快开 快开 快开 - 天呐 天呐 天呐
- Go, go, go, go, go, go, go. - Oh, my god! Oh, my god! Oh, my god!
天呐
Oh, no!
- 喂 - 喂
- Hello? - Hi.
你是不是...
Hi, did you...
你是不是丢了一只叫摩西的狗？
Did you by any chance lose a dog named Moses?
丢了 怎么了？
Yeah, I did. Why?
真的？太好了 我们刚好捡到他
Oh, you did? Amazing! 'Cause we just found him.
- 真的假的？ - 真的
- For real? - I did, yeah.
- 他怎么样 还喘不喘？ - 实话跟你说
- How is he? How's his breathing? - You know what?
刚开始他呼吸挺虚的
When we got him, his breathing was a little shallow.
- 赶紧谈钱 - 把你地址给我
- The money. - Give me your address.
我马上到
I'm gonna come right now.
事情没那么简单
Well, that's the thing.
你什么意思？
The thing? What do you mean?
这事儿按惯例
'Cause you know in situations like these it's...
应该给点赏钱吧？
it's kind of customary to give the person a reward, no?
好吧 那你想要多少？
Yeah, fine. How much you have in mind?
- 开价太高了吧？ - 不高 他有的是钱
- It's too much money. It's too much. - No, say it. He's fucking loaded.
- 喂 - 快说
- Hello? - Tell him.
要我说2000挺合适的
I was thinking maybe $2,000 seems fair for this kind of a thing.
挺公道的
That seems pretty fair to me.
- 只要2000 - 你开玩笑吧？
- Two thousand. - You're joking, right?
- 没开玩笑 - 你他妈在耍我吧
- No, no. No. - That's fucking ridiculous.
听着 听着...
Look, look...
我知道这跟你没关系 但...
I know it's really not your problem, but...
但我快生了 而且我一个人 没丈夫
I'm about to have a baby, and, look, I got no husband right now.
也没工作 这钱就算行善积德了
I got no job, and this money would really, really help me.
咱们行善吧
And, you know, let's be good people and...
那狗是我在收容所白领的 知道吗？
You realize I got that dog for free at the pound, right?
这么想就错了
Well, that's kind of the wrong way to look at it.
- 错了？ - 对 错了
- Oh, really? - Yeah, really.
那我该怎么想？
How am I supposed to look at it?
比方说我不是在谈狗
'Cause let's just say that I'm not calling about a dog.
比方说我是在说你母亲
Let's say that I'm calling about your mother,
我是医生 要做急救手术
and I'm a doctor, and I gotta perform emergency surgery on her
不然她会死 你该怎么办？
or she's gonna die. What are you gonna do?
你能因她不是买来的就不救吗？
Refuse the surgery because you got your mother for free?
不会的 你会救你母亲
No! That's crazy. You're gonna take the surgery
- 因为你爱她 - 这是什么胡扯比喻
- because you love your mother. - That's the stupidest thing I ever heard.
那就说明你不懂爱
Well, then I guess you don't know anything about love.
行了 别扯了 把地址给我 我现在就来
All right, forget it. Give me your address, okay? I'll come now.
- 带钱来 - 抱歉 但不行
- I'll bring you the cash. - I'm sorry, but no.
- 不行？ - 不行
- No? - No.
别误会 你听着也像好人
it's really not your fault, and you sound like a very nice person.
但我以前被坑过太多次了
It's just I've been ripped off one too many times in the past,
这回不能冒险
and I'm just not willing to let that happen to me again.
所以 这次必须先拿到钱
So, we're just gonna need to find a way to get me the money first.
- 你懂吗？ - 懂
- You know? Yeah. - Yeah?
给我听好了 你这蠢娘们
Listen to me, you fucking dumb bitch.
- 你一分钱都别想拿到 - 你嘴怎么那么脏？
- You're not getting one red cent... - What is wrong with you?
....除非我亲眼见到狗
...without me laying eyes on him.
- 你真不在乎的话... - 听明白了吗 妹子？
- If you really don't give a shit about... - You understand, sister?
...既然狗是白领的 我就把他送去做实验
...your dog that you got for free, how about I donate him to medical science?
- 你想那样吗？ - 我就说这行不通
- Would that be something you want? - I told you this wasn't gonna work.
旧车行
我早该料到 我到底在想啥
I should have known better. What am I doing?
旧车行
- 真是个烂主意 - 马蒂
- It was a terrible idea. - Marty!
旧车行
- 烂透了 - 抱歉 我...
- It was moronic. - I'm sorry, I was--
旧车行
抱歉 我只是想碰碰运气
I'm sorry. I was trying to give it a shot.
旧车行
- 不怪你 是这事就不对头 - 好了 别慌
- It's not your fault. It was stupid. - All right. Calm down.
那狗是什么颜色的？
What color is the dog?
问这干嘛？棕色的
Why? Who cares? It's brown.
是这样 我老板认识所有狗贩
Okay, because my boss knows all of the local breeders,
没准能找只长差不多的
and maybe we can get one that looks the same,
他不一定看得出来
and the owner won't be able to tell the difference.
他能认不出他心爱的狗？
You don't think he's gonna recognize his own dog that he loves?
- 我是说不会立马发现 - 我现在该练球的
- But I'm saying maybe not at first. - I should be working on my game right now.
结果跑到这个旧车场
Instead, I'm in a used car lot
丢人现眼 整这些没用的电话
making a mockery of my life, doing prank calls.
- 你们从哪来的？ - 老兄 你怎么还没睡？
- What are you guys doing? - Hey, pal. What are you still doing up?
小点声 我爸妈在睡觉
Keep your voice down. My parents are sleeping.
- 他们回来了？ - 我告诉过你了
- I didn't know they were back. - I told you they were back.
- 我爸的车呢？ - 就在车库
- Where's my dad's car? - It's in the garage.
我们今天经历的 绝对让你惊掉下巴
You're not gonna believe, Dion, when I tell you the day that we had.
- 你骗了我 - 没有啊 你瞎说什么
- You tricked me. - No, I didn't. What are you talking about?
- 你确实骗了 你这骗人的死丫头 - 喔
- Yes, you did, you lying bitch. - Whoa.
嘴放干净点 你这死肥猪
Hey, you watch your mouth, you fat piece of shit.
- 不许你骂我 - 别骂他
- Don't talk to me like that. - Don't talk to him like that.
他可是我最铁的朋友
He's one of my favorite people on the planet.
- 叫他别骂我 - 你也别骂她
- Tell him not to talk to me like that. - Don't talk to her like that.
- 别骂他 - 小声点
- Don't talk to him like that. - Keep it down.
别怪她 是我让她干的
I'm the one that told her to do it. She wouldn't have if I didn't.
- 把车钥匙给我 - 行 就在这儿 给你
- Give me the car keys. - Okay, they're right here. Okay?
- 有点小剐蹭... - 什么？
- We got into a little fender bender... - What?
...但没大碍
...but it's gonna be okay.
- 就是小伤 我会赔的 - 拿什么赔？什么时候赔？
- It's minor damage. I can pay for it. - How? When?
迪翁 这么晚了 咱们都该歇歇了
Dion, it's very late right now. We should all get a little bit of rest.
明天早饭时我来跟你爸解释
I'll smooth it over with your father at breakfast.
- 有我在你别... - 你们不能在这过夜
- I know your father-- - You're not staying here!
- 我们没别的地方可去了 - 你们必须得走
- We got no other place to stay. - You guys gotta go.
不 迪翁 我们必须得留下
No. Dion. We have to stay.
- 没别的地方... 迪翁 别这样 - 不行 嘘
- We have nowhere-- Dion. Stop it. - No. Shh.
她都怀孕八个月了 你疯了吗？
She's eight months pregnant. Are you out of your mind?
- 我们坐下来谈谈好不好 - 声音小点
- Please can we just talk about it? - Keep your voice down.
深更半夜把我们赶出去是吧
Gonna throw us out in the street in the dead of night?
- 没错 进去收拾东西 - 我们真没地方去了
- Yeah, yeah. Get in. - We've got nowhere to go.
收拾东西赶紧走
Get your shit and leave.
知道我们今天经历了什么吗？
Do you have any idea what we've been through today?
我不理你
I'm not talking to you.
你不理我？
You're not talking to me?
你彻底不打算理我了？
Now you're not talking to me, period?
这啥事啊
Unbelievable.
含金汤匙的人
Must be nice being born with a silver spoon in your mouth.
体会不到谋生的苦
Meanwhile, some of us have to work for a living.
你懂什么叫谋生吗？
You ever heard that word, "work"?
整天在房里瞎玩
Instead of doodling in your room all day?
竟然把朋友往街上赶...
Throwing your friends out on the street...
别盯着我们看 看墙去
Can you not stare at us? Can you look at the wall?
别像监狱看守那样
You're creeping me out.
我们能去哪儿？
Where are we gonna go? Because...
- 对不住 这儿明明有床... - 没事的
- I'm sorry. You have a bed right here... - It's okay.
- ...我本来能睡这的 - 没事的
- ...and I could be sleeping on it. - It's okay.
而且我怀着孩子 我怀着孩子
And I got a baby in me. I got a baby in me.
没事的 看你干的好事
It's okay. See what you're doing?
大半夜的把孕妇赶到街上
You're throwing a pregnant woman out on the street in the dead of the night.
这事会让你一辈子良心不安
It's gonna live on your conscience forever.
- 干嘛要自找苦吃？ - 对不起
- Why would you do this to yourself? - I'm sorry.
给我几分钟行吗？我得安抚下她
Can I have a moment with her, please? Just to comfort her,
让我跟我妹单独呆会儿
in privacy with my sister, please?
- 让她小声点 - 我尽量 我尽量 我先把她安抚好
- Keep her voice down. - I'm gonna try, but I gotta calm her down.
抱歉
Sorry.
这怎么办啊 这怎么办啊
I don't know what to do. I don't know what to do.
演得真好
That was really good.
- 瑞秋 演得太好了 - 谢谢
- That was amazing, Rachel. - Thank you.
太好了 这招也许行得通
That was so good, it might work.
- 要是被赶了 下一步去哪？ - 他估计不会赶咱们了
- Where are we gonna go if he kicks us out? - He might actually let us stay now.
多亏你这套苦肉计
That acting was so brilliant.
- 你还真哭出来了？ - 不要 马蒂 你干嘛
- Are you actually crying? - No. Marty, what are you doing?
- 这是什么？ - 怎么了？
- What is that? - What?
这是化妆吗？
Is this makeup?
别急
Hold on.
别急 听我解释 这不怪我 好吗？
Just wait. Because I can explain. It's not my fault. Okay?
别说话
No talking.
- 我也是被逼无奈 你懂吗？ - 够了 求你别说了 住嘴
- I didn't have a choice, you know? - Stop. Stop, please. Stop.
- 瑞秋 别说了 - 我必须得逃出来
- Rachel, stop. - I needed to get out.
- 我冷静吗？但快到头了 - 嗯
- See how calm I am? It's not gonna last. - Yeah.
给我滚出去
Get the fuck out of here.
- 不 要走... - 赶快滚出去
- No. What I think-- - Get the fuck out of here.
- 要走一起走 因为... - 闭嘴
- I think that we should both go because... - Stop.
跟我妈一个套路
This is the kinda shit my mother would do to me.
我对你这么好 你怎么下得了手
How could you of all people do this to me, the way I treat you?
- 我下得了手？ - 对 你怎么下得了手？
- How could I do this to you? - Yes, knowing what I'm going through?
- 那你怎么忍心对我下手 - 别吵 嘘 你在干嘛
- How about what you're doing to me? - Stop. Shh. What are you doing...
你有认真想过自己在做啥吗？
Have you ever for one second thought about what you're doing--
- 闭嘴 - 你才闭嘴 你这自私自大的王八蛋
- Stop. - Shush yourself, you narcissistic prick.
- 别闹了 你在干什么？ - 别碰我
- Stop. What are you doing? - Don't touch me!
- 要把我爸妈吵醒了 闭嘴 - 去他妈的爸妈
- You're gonna wake my parents up. Shut up. - Enough about your fucking parents.
30了还爸妈？
Aren't you, like, 30 years old?
知道吗？我还有四周就要生了
You realize I'm due in four weeks?
- 四周就要生了 - 孩子又不是我的
- I am due in four weeks! - It's not my baby.
就是他的孩子 这王八蛋的孩子
And it's his baby, by the way. It's his fucking baby.
他连这种事都骗了你
He's lying about that too.
- 在我家闹什么呢？ - 爸 我只是请了几个朋友来
- What's going on in my house? - I was just having some friends over, Dad.
晚上好
Buddy, how are you?
嘿 明早咱们得和斯伯丁开个会
Hey, we have a meeting with Spalding first thing in the morning
【斯伯丁:知名美国运动器材公司】
- 谈至尊球的事 - 迪翁 醒醒吧
- for the Supreme samples. - Dion, come on. Give me a break.
别做白日梦了
That's never gonna happen.
- 你已经骗了我儿子的钱了 - 您在说什么呢？
- You've taken my son's money. - What are you talking about?
迪翁 你看不出来吗？
I don't believe it. D, don't you see what's happening?
- 我受不了了... - 你一直在骗我儿子
- Unbelievable. Un-fucking... - You're conning my son all along.
- 我没骗你儿子 - 你卷走了他所有的钱
- I am not conning your son. - You're taking all his money.
不对 我让他有追求 你用钱来敷衍
No, I give him meaning. All you do is give him money.
- 我给了他奋斗目标 - 你给我听好
- I give him purpose. - You listen to me!
- 给我滚蛋 - 你天天骂他 看看他被你吓得
- Get out of here right now! - He won't even fucking look at you, he's so petrified of you.
我们怎么办？我们能去哪？
What are we gonna do, huh? Where do you expect us to go?
你真想让我睡大街？我怀孕了
You really want me to sleep on the street? I'm pregnant.
别 别 别 迪翁 迪翁
No, no, no. Dion! Dion!
行吧 瑞秋 我开门见山说吧 没别的意思
All right, I gotta tell you something, Rachel. It's not intended to be mean.
我有人生目标 而你没有
I have a purpose. You don't.
别以为这是好事
If you think that's some sort of blessing, it's not.
你反倒在拖累我
It puts me at a huge life disadvantage.
我有个非常明确的目标
It means I have an obligation to see a very specific thing through.
我得为它放弃一切 明白吗？
And with that obligation comes sacrifice, okay?
我是一步步才走到今天的
My life is the product of all the choices I've had to make.
而你那人生...
Your life is the product of...
我实在不知道咋形容
I don't even know what your life is the product of.
你是走一步算一步的人
You're making it up as you go. That's the kind of person you are.
我可不是这种人 明白吗？
That's not the kind of person I am, okay?
你得为自己的烂决定承担后果
You're responsible for the shitty decisions you've made.
我可没逼你嫁人
I never told you to get married, not once.
- 别把你的烂摊子丢给我 - 我知道了
- You cannot pawn them off onto me. - I understand.
你在宠物店一年挣多少？
How much do you make a year at the pet store?
差不多1200块钱
About $1200.
别忘了 我一周内得弄到1500块
Okay, in case you forgot, I have a week to make $1500,
还没算机票呢
not including air fare.
现在必须专心 别让我分心
I need to focus right now, no distractions.
- 真的很抱歉 - 没事
- I'm really sorry. - No, it's okay.
我不会和你安定下来的
It goes without saying, I'm in no position to settle down right now.
我现在没法跟你过日子 打消这个念头 明白吗？
Get that out of your mind. I will not settle down right now. Okay?
要是你真打算离开艾勒 我不会丢下你
If you're serious about leaving Ira, I will not abandon you.
作为朋友 我会帮你
As your friend, I will help you.
咱们打听打听 找个靠谱的产院收你
We'll do the research, we'll find a great maternity home.
孩子生了再找个好人家送走
They'll take you in, they'll ensure the baby's got a good family.
我们还能...不行吗？不行吗？
We could do a-- No? No?
那就回家去吧 瑞秋 回家去吧
Then go home, Rachel. Just go home.
- 我该怎么跟他解释啊 - 自己想办法 快回去吧
- What am I gonna say? - You'll figure it out. Go home, Rachel.
艾勒 醒醒
Ira, wake up.
孩子不是你的
It's not your baby.
死贱人 不许抬头
Stupid bitch, look at the fucking ground,
臭婊子
like a dumb fucking whore.
去死吧
Fuck.
真他妈的 滚那边去
Fucking bullshit. Fucking go over there.
给我面壁去
Stand in the fucking corner.
我要抽死你...想试试吗？
I'm gonna smack... You wanna do this?
那野种肯定长成像他死爹那样的无赖
That baby's gonna be a pimple-faced bum just like its fucking father.
或者像她娘一样下贱
Or it's gonna be a whore like its fucking whore mother.
- 快开门 - 又怎么了
- Open up the door right now! - What?
大半夜的还让不让人睡觉了
There are people trying to sleep!
- 够了 别闹了 - 瑞秋 快看 你的新婆婆来了
- Stop this! Quiet! - Hey, Rachel. It's your new mother-in-law.
- 艾勒 别那样说她 - 恭喜你了 马蒂他妈
- Ira! Don't say that to her! - Hey, congratulations, Mrs. Mauser.
- 你快要当奶奶了 - 什么？
- You're gonna be a grandmother. - What?
来 瑞秋现在是你的累赘了 拿好她的破烂
Here, she's your problem now. Here, take her shit.
瑞秋 需要帮忙吗？
Rachel, do you need help?
- 别闹了 要帮忙吗？ - 对不起
- That's enough. Do you need help, honey? - I'm sorry.
- 我没事 大家都回去休息吧 - 她可会装可怜了
- No, I'm okay. Everyone, go back to bed. - Yeah, great. She's so sorry.
【劳伦斯球场:20世纪中叶纽约著名乒乓球俱乐部】
劳伦斯
百老汇球场
- 你就是瑞秋吧 - 你是伊兹拉？
- Are you Rachel? - You're Ezra?
- 狗在哪儿？ - 先交钱 再交狗
- Where is he? - Give me the money and I'll bring him out.
先交钱？见不到狗 你一分钱也得不到
Money? You ain't getting a nickel unless I see my dog.
先说清楚 我有后援 一帮人看着呢
Just so you know, I'm not alone, okay? I got people watching all around me.
我才他妈不管谁看着
I don't give a shit who's watching.
我被保护着 你别耍花样
I'm letting you know I'm very protected right now in case you try anything.
- 什么？ - 好了 要狗吗？
- What? - Okay, do you want your dog?
狗在我这里
I have your dog.
- 抢什么？ - 我不在乎项圈
- What are you doing? - I don't want that collar.
- 我要的是狗 - 把钱亮出来
- I want what's inside the collar. - Show me the money.
要是我没你的狗 我哪会有这项圈？
Would I have this if I didn't have your dog? No.
把钱拿出来 我就去领狗
So show me the money, and I'll go and get him for you.
快点 快点
Come on. Come on!
妹子 你知不知道你惹的是谁？
You don't know who you're playing with, girl. Okay?
- 这是钱 - 我才不管你是谁
- Here's the money. - I don't fucking care.
把信封打开
Show me what's inside the envelope.
我怎么知道里面是不是钱
How am I supposed to know there's anything in there?
- 想看是吧？看清楚没？看清楚没？ - 行 挺好
- Here, you wanna see? Here, look. Okay? - Yes. Great.
- 你往哪儿去？ - 她到底带没带狗来？
- Where you going, girl? - Does she have the dog or what?
谁他妈知道
Who the fuck knows?
好
Okay.
- 喂 布拉尼斯通酒吧 - 喂 是我
- Yeah, Blarney Stone. - Hi, it's me.
你是谁？
Who's "me"?
好了 可以把狗牵出来了 谢谢
Yeah, thank you. You can bring the dog out now.
刚才把狗留这的是你？你说马上回来 这叫马上？
You're the one that left the dog? What happened to "coming right back"?
都准备好了 牵出来吧
We're ready, so you can walk him outside.
- 那畜生尿了一地 - 好的 待会儿见
- The thing's pissed all over the floor. - Okay. I'll see you soon.
- 怎么回事？ - 别急 听我说
- What is going on? - Listen to me for a second, okay?
看 那边 瞧见没？
Look. Right over there. Okay?
那个绿篷
The green awning.
我朋友马上会牵狗出来
My friend's gonna come out in a second with the dog.
你先把钱给我 我打电话通报
Once you give me the money, I'm gonna call and say we're squared up, okay?
瞧 牵着狗出来了 没骗你吧
Look, there he is right now with the dog. I told you.
把钱给我吧
So hand me the money.
去你的
Fuck you.
嘿 嘿 把钱给我
Hey! Hey, give me my money.
那我的钱呢 喂
What about... Hey!
抓贼 拦住那两个人
Thief! Stop those two.
- 他们抢了我的钱包 - 嘿
- They took my wallet. - Hey.
拦住他们
Stop them!
喂 别走
Where you going? Hey.
- 滚开 松手 - 别跑了
- Get off of me. - Come on.
嘿 还有那个 那个打石膏的
Hey, him too! Him with the cast!
那个打石膏的
With the cast.
竟然抢孕妇
What are you doing trying to steal from a pregnant woman?
- 该死 - 快喊警察
- Shit. - Hey, police!
这他妈什么玩意儿？
What the fuck is this, man?
这不是摩西
That not Moses. Hey.
这不是我的狗
That's not my dog.
- 摩西在哪儿？有个女的叫我牵狗出来的
- Where's my Moses? - Yo, I'm out here. The lady said to come here.
- 他妈的耍我是吧 - 别过来 喂
- Fucking playing games with me? - Stay away. Hey!
他妈的耍我是吧
Fucking playing games with me? Huh?
什么鬼把戏
What kind of fucking shit you playing with me?
- 放手 滚开 退后 - 嘿 别激动 该死
- Hey, get the fuck off me. Back up, man. - Hey, calm down. Shit.
- 糟了 - 站住
- Shit. - Stop there.
快救她
Someone help her!
- 救命 救命啊 - 抓到你了 你这混蛋
- Somebody! Help! - I got you, you fucking bitch!
嘿 住手
Hey! Stop!
有事吗？
What is it?
- 嘿 你好吗 - 你来这儿干什么？
- Hey, how are you doing? - What are you doing here?
都12点半了 要不要一起去吃个午饭？
It's 12:30. I was wondering if you wanted to get lunch.
不可能 今晚要首演
It's out of the question. I have a show opening tonight.
- 能借你一小时吗？ - 不行
- Well, can I steal you away for an hour? - No.
- 能跟你说句话吗？拜托 - 我很忙
- Can I talk to you for a second? Please. - I'm very busy.
就几句话 拜托了
Please, it'll just take a second.
- 说实话我真的有点羞愧 - 怎么了？
- I feel kind of nervous telling you this. - What?
好吧 我承认 这是我偷的
All right, uh, I stole this from you, okay?
我想还给你
And I want to return it. All right?
对不起 我本打算把它卖了 再也不见你
I'm sorry. My plan was to sell it and never see you again.
你住进我心里了 偷你的东西是不对的
But I can't stop thinking about you, and I can't steal from you.
哦
Mmm.
你知道那是假首饰吧？
You know that's costume jewelry, right?
- 假的？我真傻 - 演出道具
- This is costume jewelry? I'm an idiot. - From the production.
你不是常说要靠自己吗 那话去哪儿了？
What happened to doing it all on your own? Where did that speech go?
那是装腔作势行了吧
I know, I'm completely full of shit, okay?
我走投无路才偷了你的东西
I was in a tight spot, and I stole from you cause I needed some money,
我错了
and it was wrong.
我穷得叮当响
I'm broke.
我没门路
Look, I got no resources.
下周要去日本打比赛 我连路费都没有
I got the championship next week in Japan. I got no way to get there.
我没招了 没人能帮我 凯
I got no options. I got no one looking out for me, Kay.
当然 这不关你的事 我只是来还东西的
Which isn't your problem. Which is why I'm returning it, okay?
- 你猜我怎么想吗？ - 怎么想？
- You know what I think? - What?
- 你知道这是假货 卖不出去跑来装可怜 - 不是的
- I think you went to sell that and discovered it was junk. - No.
还用这种蹩脚的把戏
And now you've shown up here with this ridiculous strategy
想让我心软掏钱
to get me to have some sympathy and open my wallet.
太荒唐了 我会这样侮辱你的智商吗？
That's absurd. You think I would insult your intelligence like that?
- 还没演够？ - 演什么？
- Are you gonna keep going? - Keep going what?
- 继续演这出戏 - 我在说实说啊
- Are you gonna keep on with this? - Just being myself.
- 你满嘴谎话 - 才没有
- You're lying through your teeth. - No, I'm not.
- 我的诚实写在脸上 - 你到底还有没有脸？
- It's me being me. - This is pathetic. You're being you?
我说的可是实话
I am telling you the truth.
我偷了 然后很后悔很内疚
I stole from you and then I feel bad about it,
- 所以我来弥补 - 省省吧 我才不在乎
- so I'm trying to make amends. - You're wasting your energy. I don't care.
换成我也会偷的
I would have stolen from me too.
凯
Kay.
- 嗨 - 打断你们了吧
- Hi. - Looks like I'm interrupting something.
没事 没事
No, no. Not at all.
这是马丁 我朋友卡萝的儿子 他正要走
This is Martin, my friend Carol's son. He was just leaving.
- 这位是默尔 我的宣传人 - 你好
- This is Merle, my publicist. - Hello.
马丁想当演员 可惜演技不怎么样
Martin would like to be an actor, but unfortunately he's not very good.
在百老汇当个门童也挺好的
Ah, well, you know, Broadway needs ushers too.
座位安排的怎么样了？
So what's happening with the seating?
我跟米尔顿谈过了 他会派全体职工来
I spoke to Milton. He's sending all of his employees.
算是公司总动员了
It's like a mandate. Like, a company mandate.
就这样糊弄我吗？
This is supposed to make me happy?
不是说要座无虚席吗？
Well, I mean, it's a full house. Isn't that the point?
全是不识货的 - 不 不是的
Full of fucking morons. - No, no. You got some--
- 弗雷德·阿斯泰尔也会来 - 我先走了 不打扰你们了
- Fred Astaire is coming. - Okay, I'm gonna get out your hair...
【弗雷德·阿斯泰尔:20世纪美国著名舞者和演员】
别急着走 记得给他留张今晚的票
No. Make sure you give him a ticket for tonight.
- 给我？ - 对
- Really? - Yeah.
小伙子 你这下有福了
Oh. You are in for such a treat, young man.
你看她演一回就知道
When you see this lady act,
什么叫千秋难得一见 吸引四海八荒了
you're gonna feel like you got your cock sucked by a vacuum cleaner.
- 默尔 - 她脸红了 看见没？
- Merle! - She's blushing. See her?
说什么呢
What?
莫罗斯科剧院票 持票人马蒂·毛瑟
h
坐好别乱动
Take your stinking seat.
怎么回事？
What the hell?
你发什么神经？
Have you lost your damned mind?
小杰 我在跟你说话呢
Jed. I'm talking to you.
妈 我只是练练枪法
I was just practicing my aim, Mama.
你不一直催我找准目标吗？
You always said to shoot for the stars.
嘿
Hey.
跟我走
Come.
抱歉我来晚了 脱不开身
I'm sorry I'm late. I couldn't get away.
- 呵 我信你 - 他一直缠着我
- Oh, I bet. - He was all over me.
你今晚演得棒极了 太精彩了
You were incredible tonight. That was unbelievable.
- 我有样东西给你 - 给我？
- I have something for you. - For me?
转过去
Turn around.
每周年我丈夫都会送我一件首饰
Every year my husband gives me a piece of jewelry for our anniversary.
我有25件了 每件都代表受了一年的苦
I have 25 of them. One for each year of misery.
这条够你那趟路费了 没准还能剩
That should cover your trip and then some.
戴着让我浑身不自在
Wearing it makes me feel like shit.
完了 停下 停下 停下
Oh, shit. Stop, stop, stop.
停
Stop.
喂 喂 你们在干什么呢？
Hey! Hey, what are you doing?
- 完了 天呐 - 站起来
- Shit. Oh, God. - Get up!
- 躺着别动 - 我看见你们了 站起来
- Lay still. - Stand up, I see you.
我数到三就跑 一 二 三 起来
When I tell you, run. One, two, three. Get up.
- 快走 走 - 嘿
- Come on. Go. - Hey!
乔伊 拦住他们
Joey, stop them!
快走 快走 快走
Come on. Come on. Come on.
嘿 你们往哪儿去？跑这儿干嘛呢？
Hey. Hey. Where are you guys going? What are you guys doing here?
- 没干嘛 - 不 不 不
- Nothing. - No, no, no.
- 把手举起来 - 铐上那小子
- Let me see both of your hands. - Cuff him.
- 天呐 我们只是... - 我们什么都没干
- Oh, my God. We were just... - We didn't do anything.
饶了我们吧 我们只是在草地上找她的耳环
Give us a break. We were looking for her earrings in the grass.
我的耳环掉了 只是在耳环
My earring came off. We were looking for my earring.
你耳朵上不是戴了两只耳环吗
It looks like you've got two earrings in your ears there.
不是这只 不是刚才掉的 还有一只
Not this earring. There was... From before. There was another earring.
白天还丢过另一对耳环
There's another pair of earrings from earlier in the day.
我认出你了
I recognize you.
- 天呐 天呐 - 你是凯·斯通
- Oh, God. Oh, God. - You're Kay Stone.
- 没错 我太清楚你是谁了 - 见鬼了
- Yes. I know exactly who you are. - This is not happening.
- 把手给我 - 你认真的吗？
- Let see your hands. - Are you serious?
这样吧 我回家取个钱包
You know, I will go home,
给你们些钱赔偿
and I'll get my wallet, and I will get you some cash
毕竟给你们添麻烦了
because we've put you out.
请你行行好 警官 她这就回家拿钱包 给你们现金
Please, officer. She's gonna go home and get her wallet. And give you cash.
- 有证件吗？ - 没 没证件
- Got ID? - No. No ID.
- 把她也铐上 - 不要 求你了
- Cuff her. - No, please.
- 没证是吧？让我搜搜 - 求你了 求你了
- No ID, huh? Let's see. - Please, please. No, no, no.
- 求你了 让我回家拿钱包吧 - 求你了
- Please, will you just let me go home? - Come on.
我向你保证
I'll give you my word.
哇 瞧瞧 这项链可真漂亮啊
Wow, lookie here. That's a really nice necklace.
拿去 拿去吧 归你了
Take it. Take it. It's yours.
那我就不客气了
Thank you very much.
真不敢相信
I can't believe this.
能再拿条项链给我吗？
Do you think you could grab me another necklace?
你是认真的吗？
Are you serious?
你不是说这项链对你没价值吗 就几分钟的事
You said them mean nothing to you. It'd just take you a couple of minutes.
我都消失了半小时 不能进去又立刻出来
I was just gone for half an hour. I can't go up and come right back down.
- 你给警察倒是挺爽快的啊 - 我妈就在屋里
- You'd do that for the police officers. - My mother is up there.
- 天呐 我的头发都乱了 - 我在走廊等你
- Oh, my God. My hair. - I'll wait in the hall.
不 不准跟来
No, you will not.
等等 等等
Wait. Wait.
好了
There.
你真漂亮
You look beautiful.
求你了 你有25条呢
Please, you have 25 of them.
好
Fine!
- 待在这儿 明白吗？ - 好 我就在这里等
- Stay here. Do you understand me? - I'll stay here. Okay.
- 别乱跑 - 好
- Do not move. - Okay.
倒霉
Shit.
你好 很高兴见到你们
Hello. Lovely to see you.
- 大卫 你好吗？ - 挺好 你呢？
- David, how are you? - Good. How are you?
你死哪去了？
Where the fuck have you been?
我出去透透气 有意见吗？
I needed a moment to myself. Is that a problem?
出门还得请示吗？
I didn't realize I needed a permission slip.
我为你操办了这一切 你现在却让我丢面子
I put this whole thing on for you and you're making me look like an idiot.
天呐
God.
听着 默尔已经跟《纽约时报》那边联系上了
Look. Merle's on the phone right now with The New York Times.
- 真的假的？ - 他找到个能念出明天剧评的人
- What? - He's got a printer who's gonna read the review.
天呐
My God.
- 你在乎不在乎？ - 找着他了 我找着他了
- Or do you not care? - I got him! I have him!
- 天呐 来了 - 快来 快来
- Oh, my God. Okay. - Come, come, come!
来了
Coming!
- 快点 拿到剧评了 - 来了
- Hurry, he has the review! - I'm coming.
剧评出来了
The review!
快点 快点 快点
Come on, come on, come on, come on.
- 快来 - 来了
- Come on, come on. - Okay.
这是拉乌尔 她是凯
Raoul, Kay.
好 标题是《凯·斯通复出》 作者罗伯特...
Okay. Title, "Kay Stone Returns" by Robert...
- 晚安 - 别关门 大家都要下来了
- Have a good night. - Leave it open. Everyone's coming down.
- 是吗？ - 是的
- Are they? - Oh, yeah.
庆祝会结束了
Party's over.
晚安
Good night.
庆祝会结束了
The party's over.
- 他们说散场了 - 什么意思？咱们才刚到啊
- They're asking us to leave. - What do you mean? We just got here.
怎么门口不拦还让我们进？
They should've stopped us at the door. Why'd they let us in?
完了 聚会没了
It's done, the party's gone.
打扰下 请问凯在哪儿？
Excuse me. Do you know where Kay is?
- 她在楼上卧室里 - 好的
- She's upstairs in her bedroom. - Okay.
嗨 凯在屋里吗？
Hi. Is Kay in there?
现在不方便
This is not a good time.
明白 能让我跟她说下吗
Okay, but can I just speak to her?
我都说了 现在真不方便
As I said, it's really not a good time.
年底结账 能赚钱的就留着
At the end of the year, if the guy made you money, you keep him.
不赚钱的就踢出去呗
And if not, you throw the bum out.
打扰下
Excuse me.
- 您好 - 开啥玩笑啊
- Hi. - You gotta be kidding me.
- 抱歉登门打扰了 - 你怎么混进我家的？
- I'm sorry to disturb you in your home. - How did you fuck get in my house?
求您再给我一次机会 我求您了
Please give me another chance. I am on my hands and knees.
我得去日本 还需要1500块才能参加世锦赛
I need a ride to Japan and I need $1,500 so I can compete in the championship.
这活对我太重要了
I need this job very, very badly.
我求您了
I'm begging you.
我完全听您安排 输球也行
I'll work for you however you want. I will lose.
我唯一目标就是把您的活动办成功
I'll have no personal point of view apart from making your event a success.
马蒂 人生没有第二次机会
Marty, there are no second chances in life.
- 为什么不行？ - 我给过你机会 你当时拒绝了
- Why not? - I offered you the job and you said no!
我知道 我当时太冲动了 我很后悔
I know, because I was impulsive. And I regret it.
除了后悔呢？
And?
我还没礼貌 还自负
And I was rude and overconfident.
我得意忘形 还耍架子
And I was cocky, and I copped an attitude.
还有呢？
And?
我保证不会再犯了 对不起
And it won't happen again. I'm sorry.
求您再给我一回机会 罗克韦尔先生
Please just give me another chance, Mr. Rockwell.
我任您发落 您吩咐什么我就做什么
I'm throwing myself at your mercy. I'll do whatever you want.
你们怎么看？该给这小混蛋一次机会吗？
What do you guys think? Should I give this little asshole a second chance?
- 是的 求您了 - 别问我
- Yes, please! - Don't ask me.
这对我太重要了 求求您了
You don't know how important this is to me. Please. I'm begging you.
求您让我跟您上飞机去日本
Just let me go on your plane, and let me join you there.
求求您了 我正跪着求您
Please, I'm humbling myself before you.
- 你这副模样真恶心 - 对不起
- You're making me sick. - I'm sorry.
- 站起来! - 好的 行
- Stand up! - Okay. All right.
求您了 让我做什么都行
Please. Okay? I'll do anything.
- 什么都行？ - 对 什么都行
- Anything? - Yes. Anything.
好
Okay.
顺着走廊走 右手边第二间是我办公室
Go down the hall. Second door on the right is my office.
去把球拍拿来
Grab the paddle and bring it back here.
这要比刚才那出戏还精彩了
This is more dramatic than the play.
- 好的 - 可不是吗
- Okay. - That's true.
（罗克韦尔墨业）
马蒂 把球拍给我
Oh, Marty. Give me the paddle.
照我说的做
So here's what I want you to do.
我要你趴那椅子上 把裤子脱了
I want you to bend over that chair and drop your pants.
你认真的吗？
Are you for real?
你这小子调皮过头了 得好好打屁股了
You've been a really bad boy. Now you're gonna get a spanking.
别这样 你认真的吗？
Come on. Are you serious?
想去日本吗？
You wanna get to Japan, don't you?
是的 我想去日本 可这真是你想要的？
Yeah, I wanna go to Japan. But this is what you want?
这就是代价 趴好
That's what it's gonna take. Now bend over.
好吧 先说好
Okay, so to be clear,
你会带我去日本 然后还给我钱吗？
you're gonna bring me to Japan and then you're gonna compensate me?
明早八点半 拉瓜迪亚机场 我们就动身去日本
Tomorrow morning, 8:30, LaGuardia. We're on our way to Japan.
- 还要买票吗？ - 飞机是我的
- Do I need a ticket? - I own the plane.
我怎么知道你说话算数？
How do I know you're gonna honor this?
你不知道 你没资格跟我讨价还价
You don't. Because you have no power here.
趴好
Now bend over.
手放这儿 弧度要漂亮点
Put your hands over here. I want a nice arc.
趴好
Let's go.
噢 天呐
Oh, my God.
行了 我准备好了
Okay, I'm ready.
这一下是替我儿子打的
This one is for my son.
好
Okay.
这一下是给我解气的
This one is for me.
哎呦
God!
下面是加赛环节
Now the bonus round.
多好的球拍 一面是木头 一面是海绵
Beautiful paddle. One side's wood and the other is foam.
- 嘿 马蒂 怎么样？ - 你好 泰德 你好 劳伦斯
- Hey, Marty, how you doin'? - Hey, Ted. Hey, Lawrence.
嘿 近来可好？
Aw, damn. Hey, man. How you doin'?
你看我今晚能住后屋吗？
You think I could stay in the back room tonight?
- 真不巧 后屋今晚给布赖恩了 - 好吧
- Wow, man. I got Brian staying there tonight. - I get it. All right.
我真想让你到我家歇 但我老婆不答应
I would let you stay at the house, man, but the wife ain't havin' it.
没事 我就在这儿晃悠到起飞吧
No, It's all right. I'm just gonna hang around until my flight.
你要去哪?
Where you goin'?
去日本 明早八点出发
Going to Japan. Tomorrow morning, 8:00 a.m.
- 太好了 - 好样的小伙子
- Oh, yeah! - My man!
- 哟 你真要去啦 弄到钱了 - 是啊 是啊
- Yo, you goin'! You got that money. - Yeah, yeah, yeah.
祝贺你 小伙计
Good for you, man.
你表情怎么这么沉啊
You ain't even look like you excited.
没事 我...挺好的 我挺好的
No, I'm-- I'm good. I'm good.
你那哥们沃利在后头 他一直在等你
You know your boy back there, Wally, he's been waitin' on you.
- 沃利在这儿吗？ - 沃利在啊
- Wally's here? - Wally, yeah.
- 他怎么样？ - 沃利挺好 挺淡定的 伙计
- How'd he seem? - Wally's good. He cool, man.
他就在里面
He's back there somewhere.
- 他很看好你 - 当时大家都在掏钱
- He believes in you. - He has a dollar. She has a dollar.
嘿 你好
Hey. How you doing?
噢 哇 见到你真好
Oh, wow! How you doing? Nice to see you!
我一直想联系你
I've been trying to get in touch with you.
- 真的？ - 是啊 你家狗怎样了 摩西怎么样？
- Oh, really? - Yeah. How's your dog? How's Moses doing?
你能别扯了吗？
You wanna cut the bullshit?
没胡扯 我是真关心那狗的
No bullshit. I'm genuinely concerned about him.
- 马蒂 马蒂 有麻烦吗？ - 没事 没事
- Marty, Marty, Marty. You good, man? - Yeah, I'm good.
听着 听着 听着
Now, listen to me. Listen. Listen. Listen.
你那小妞就在楼下车里 她正等你呢
I got your girl downstairs in the car. She's waiting for you.
你扯什么呢？你抓了瑞秋？
What the fuck are you telling me? You got Rachel?
对
Yeah.
她跟我说狗在新泽西某处 你知道地址
She told me my dog's in Jersey somewhere. And you got the address.
- 好 - 咱们走
- Okay. - Let's go.
行吧 好吧 让我...
Okay. All right. Let me, uh...
额 行吧 让我先...
Um, okay, let me just...
给我两秒钟 我就跟我哥们说句话
Give me two seconds. I just wanna say one thing to my friend.
给你两秒钟行 但老子可不等你
Give you two seconds, yeah, but I'm not gonna be here.
- 不等我你干嘛？ - 我干嘛？
- Where you gonna be? - Where am I gonna be?
我这就下楼用锤子敲烂她那肚子
I'm gonna be downstairs taking a hammer to your girl's stomach.
这就是我要干的事
That's where I'm gonna be.
好 好 好
Okay. All right. All right.
喂 小毛毛
Yo, Mouse!
- 走 别磨蹭 - 好吧
- Come on. Let's go. - Okay.
他的遗产大部分也被我拿了
Well, I took most of his share of the money that our parents left us.
- 你拿了你弟那份？ - 是的
- You spent your brother's money? - Yes, I did.
呵 看来你挺疼你弟的
Yeah, you love your brother?
疼啊 要不你给我弟安排个差事 他人不错
Yeah. Maybe you could give my brother a job. You know he's a good man.
让他取代你 行了吧？米奇 帮个忙
I'll give him your job, okay? Mitch, do me a favor.
干嘛？
What?
闭嘴 行吗？
Stop talking. Okay?
好了 看到那加油站没？
Okay. See the gas station there?
往左那个房子就是
it's the house to the left.
- 前面左转？ - 对
- Next left? - Yeah.
知道了
I got it.
下车 赶紧的
Get out of the car. Come on.
米奇 下来
Mitch, come.
- 鲁本 你留下看着她 - 好的
- Reuben, you wait with her. - Oh, okay.
老实坐着
Sit tight.
快点 使劲敲
Come on. Louder.
使劲敲
Knock louder.
那是我的狗
That's my dog.
摩西 喂
Moses! Yo!
赶紧开门
Open up!
真黑 摩西
Fuck. Moses.
- 开门 - 我讨厌死那狗了
- Come on. - I hate that fuckin' mutt.
摩西
Moses!
那是我的狗 摩西
That's my dog. Moses!
摩西
Moses!
里头看见啥没？
See anything in there?
没 没看到什么
No, not really.
- 马蒂 - 该死
- Marty! - Shit.
马蒂 快跑
Marty! Go!
马蒂
Marty!
趴下 趴下
Get down! Get down!
该死
Fuck!
马蒂 马蒂 我中弹了
Marty! Marty! I got shot!
救命
Help!
救命 马蒂 快帮帮我
Help, Marty! Please help!
帮帮我
Help!
你没事吧？噢不 你没事吧？
Are you okay? Oh, no! Are you okay?
- 你没事吧？ - 这他妈是怎么回事？
- Are you okay? - What the fuck's going on?
好了 没事的
Okay. It's okay.
我流血了 流血了
I'm bleeding, I'm bleeding.
好了 没事的 没事的 没事的
Okay. It's okay. It's okay. It's okay.
- 真对不起 - 对不起
- I'm so sorry. - I'm sorry.
- 快去拿钱 - 什么钱？
- Go get the money. - What money?
快去拿钱 就在他口袋里 在他兜里
Go get the money. It's in his pocket. It's in his pocket.
你确定？
Are you sure?
- 钱 就在他口袋里 - 好的 知道了 知道了
- The money! It's in the inside pocket! - Okay, okay, okay.
该死
Oh, fuck.
这都是什么啊
What is this?
噢 你个王八蛋...
Oh, you motherfucker...
好了 好了 没事了 没事了
Okay. Okay. Okay. Okay.
该死
Fuck!
放手 你要去哪儿？
Get off me! Where do you think you're going?
没事的
it's okay.
好了
Okay.
- 拿到了吗？拿到了吗？ - 嗯 拿到了 拿到了
- You got it? You got it? - Yeah. I got it, I got it.
- 钱拿到了吗？ - 嗯 拿到了 拿到了
- You got the money? - Yeah. I got it, I got it.
- 钱多吗？ - 很多 很多
- Is there a lot of money? - There's a lot.
- 你能去日本了 - 我知道 你做得真棒
- You can go now. - I know. You did amazing.
- 你可以去参赛了 - 我就知道你行 太棒了
- You can go on your trip now. - I knew you could do this. So good.
你帮了大忙
You did such a good job.
我爱你
I love you.
- 你预产期什么时候？ - 怎么了？孩子没事吧？
- Honey, when is your due date? - Why? Is the baby okay?
孩子没事 你得冷静下来
The baby is fine. I just need you to calm down.
- 你是她丈夫吗？ - 不是 我是她朋友
- Are you the husband? - No. I'm her friend.
她还有四周就生 孩子会没事吧？
She's due in four weeks. The baby will be okay?
孩子没事 你不能进了
The baby is okay. It's time to say goodbye.
- 我不能进？ - 手术室只允许家属进去
- I can't go? - Only family in the operating room.
不 不 不 不 不
No, no, no, no, no!
会没事的 瑞秋 都会没事的 放心
It's gonna be fine. Rachel, it's fine. It's fine.
不 不 不 马蒂 别走
No, no, no! Marty, no.
他就在外面等着
He'll be right outside.
马蒂 别走
Marty, no!
瑞秋 我进不去 他们不让我进
Rachel, I can't go. They're telling me I can't go.
- 我不想让你... - 冷静下来
- I don't want you to-- - Please calm down.
- 马蒂 别走 求你别走 - 冷静点
- Marty, don't go, please! - Please try calm down.
求你别走 马蒂
Please don't go! Marty!
不要
No!
罗克韦尔先生 欢迎来到日本 祝您愉快
Thank you very much. Welcome to Japan, Mr. Rockwell.
- 谢谢 - 谢谢
- Thank you. - Thank you.
（行李领取处）
日本 东京
（罗克韦尔 原子笔）
（日语）好了 下一轮比赛
（日语）马上就要开始了
赢一分
得一笔
i
j
用罗克韦尔书写传奇
- （日语）这位挑战者是早川先生 大家掌声欢迎
- （日语）远藤加油
（日语）你有信心吗？
（日语）有
（日语）加油 加油
（日语）让我们拭目以待
（日语）那么接下来有请
（日语）远藤出场
k
（日语）有点可惜
- （日语）远藤加油
- （日语）下面请下一位挑战者上场
毛瑟先生 毛瑟先生
Mr. Mauser. Mr. Mauser.
罗克韦尔说让你排到最后
Ah. Mr. Rockwell says the back of the line.
他还不想让你上场
He doesn't want to begin yet.
（挑战者在此排队）
（日语）这位才11岁...
世锦赛售票处
（日语）谢谢
- 跟我学 日语管啤酒叫“比鲁” - 来 干杯
- Practice beer "biiru". - Okay, kanpai.
塞西先生 塞西先生
Mr. Sethi? Mr. Sethi.
嘿 是我 马蒂·毛瑟
Hey. It's me. It's Marty Mauser.
你好啊 真没想到能在这碰到您
How you doing? I'm surprised to see you here, actually.
- 此话怎讲？ - 我不知道 我...
- Why's that? - I don't know. I--
我们来这里宣传锦标赛
We do have a tournament to promote.
嗯 当然 当然
No, of course, of course.
好吧
Yeah.
我想给您道个歉 伦敦的事
I think I owe you an apology for the way I acted in London.
那确实不像话
I was a jackass.
做人要有分寸 毛瑟先生
There is such a thing as a code of courtesy, Mr. Mauser.
对 我知道 我知道 只是...
No, I know, I know. It's just--
我出身的环境
It's every man for himself where I come from.
为了混口饭谁都不讲究 懂吗？
That's just how I grew up. Okay?
有时候我老毛病也会犯...
And sometimes I feel like I don't even have control--
我不想听这些借口
I'm really not interested in your excuses.
不 不 知道 这不是借口
No, no, I know. It's not an excuse.
我会改掉那些做派
Look, the point is I'm gonna proceed with a much better attitude.
要是今天我上台表现粗鲁
And by the way, if you see me acting rude up there today,
那是演的 事先安排好的 我会以21比14输掉
that's a character. This is scripted. I'm gonna lose 21-14.
这不代表我 下周赛场上你们会看到规规矩矩的我
This isn't a real thing. The real me, the polite me, you'll see next week.
- 下周？ - 世锦赛上
- Next week? - At the championship.
世锦赛跟你没关系
You're not playing in the championship.
- 什么？ - 你今年被禁赛了
- What? - You're not participating this year.
不 不 不 您搞错了
No, no, no. I think you're confused.
我就是借这活动来凑齐罚款的
That's what I'm doing the event for, so I can pay off the rest of my fine.
跟我去找罗克韦尔谈谈
Come talk to Mr. Rockwell right now.
比赛还有不到两周就开始了
The tournament is less than two weeks away.
- 对阵表都排好了 - 不 咱们可以重排
- All the bracketing has been set. - No, but we'll redo the bracketing.
我不会为个自以为是的美国人把整个安排打乱
I'm not gonna tear up the entire schedule on behalf of one entitled American.
不 塞西先生 塞西先生 你看...
No, Mr. Sethi. Mr. Sethi. Look...
我已经来了
I'm here.
我千里迢迢赶来的 您根本想象不到有多难
I don't think you know how difficult that was, for me to come here.
我现在可真到日本了
I'm in Japan right now.
恐怕你走得还不够远
You haven't come far enough, I'm afraid.
- 什么意思？ - 你来这儿就是徒劳
- What? - You have wasted your time coming here.
真荒唐啊
This is unbelievable.
（日语）来看看这位挑战者
用罗克韦尔书写传奇
j
i
（日语）哎呀 真可惜啊
（日语）请两位选手互相握手
（日语）友谊第一 比赛第二
- （日语）下面请出下一位挑战者
- （日语）下一位
（日语）请站到这里来
（日语）请问您叫什么名字？
（日语）哎呦
（日语）太意外了
（日语）他是马蒂·毛瑟 美国的顶尖选手
（日语）大家掌声欢迎
我千里迢迢跑到日本
I've traveled many miles here to Japan
就是为了挑战我的死对头远藤
to challenge my great nemesis, Endo!
加油 马蒂
Come on, Marty!
（日语）你要怎么做 远藤选手？
他说什么？
What's he say?
他不想让你再丢脸了
He doesn't want to embarrass you anymore.
让我丢脸？我的脸早没了
Embarrass me? I am beyond embarrassment.
跟他说...你们的冠军就是个冒牌货 还是个怂包
Tell him he's a-- Your champion is a fraud and a chicken.
他就是个怂包
He's chicken!
远藤先生同意比赛
Mr. Endo agrees to the match.
很好
Great.
不过有个条件...
On the condition that...
输的人得当着全场观众亲一头猪
the loser has to kiss a pig in front of the entire audience.
- 亲猪？ - 是的
- A pig? - Yes.
亲猪？开什么玩笑？
A pig? What?
他说你要是摆出猪样
He said if you are going to act like a pig,
他很乐意帮你配个种
he will happily mate you with one.
这话什么意...
What does that--
（日语）大家或许没听懂
（日语）输了的人要当众亲一头猪
（日语）现在比分19比14
（日语）轮到远藤发球
（日语）这一球至关重要
（日语）毛瑟已经走投无路了
（日语）好险
这根该死的电线绊着我了
It's this cord in the fucking way.
- 绊着我了 把线挪开 - （日语）他说输是被电线害的
I'm stepping on the cord. Move the cord.
快把线挪走 别害的我再被绊倒
Move the cord over there so I don't slip on it next time!
- 对不起 对不起 - 我可不想被绊倒摔断腿
- I'm sorry. I'm sorry. - So I don't break my ankle!
（日语）20比14 远藤的赛点
（日语）决定性一球
（日语）远藤发球
（日语）远藤加油 远藤加油
（日语）比赛结束
（日语）胜负已分
（日语）本场获胜的是...
（日语）更强的远藤选手
（日语）请给他热烈掌声
（日语）这场比赛真是激烈
（日语）不过好戏还在后头
（日语） 现在有请一位特邀嘉宾上台
- 你会说英语吗？ - 会
- You speak English? - Yeah.
他在说什么？
What's he saying?
“有请一位特邀嘉宾上台”
"We are welcoming a special guest."
“有请 拉姆·塞西先生”
"Mr. Ram Sethi. Come on up."
谢谢大家
Thank you.
同时感谢罗克韦尔先生主办这场难忘的盛会
And thank you, Mr. Rockwell, for hosting such an unforgettable event.
刚才不过是下周精彩对决的开胃菜
What we have just witnessed is a mere taste of what is to come next week
下周世界顶尖选手将与
when the finest players in the world will be competing
你们的英雄远藤功人一较高下
against your hometown hero, Koto Endo-san.
（日语）远藤加油
（日语）可一定要赢
我就不多说了 现在请小猪阿古上台
No more words from me. Let's bring on Agu the pig
让这位美国人来个亲猪表演
and see the American plant a kiss on him.
“现在把猪请上台”
"Now we bring the pig onto the stage."
等一下 等一下 等一下
Wait, wait, wait.
嘿 嘿
Hey. Hey.
我要求先打一场真比赛 然后再亲猪
I want to play him in a real game first before I kiss the pig.
打一场真刀真枪的比赛
I want to play him in a real game.
告诉他 我想来场不掺水的比赛
Tell him I want to play him in a game that's not a sham.
告诉他
Tell him!
你 告诉观众 刚才是假的 掺水的
You, tell the audience that was a fake game, and was a sham.
告诉他们是在演戏 我想跟他来场真的
Tell them it was a sham and I want to play a real game against him.
- 我不能说 - 凭什么不能？
- I cannot do that for you. - Why can't you do that?
刚才是场假比赛 是提前安排好的
That was a fake game. That was staged.
没一点是真的
No part of that was real.
我根本没拿出实力来
I was not playing to the best of my ability.
这是对大家的侮辱
It was an enormous form of disrespect to everyone here.
大家听着 你们想不想看真比赛？
Hey, listen, who wants a real game?
要看真比赛的举个手 举手
Show of hands. Come on.
等等 有人举手 有人举手
Wait, this man. This man.
（日语）要打就真打
马蒂 你说得对 我们要看真比赛
Marty, you're right. We want to see the real game!
太好了
Yes!
（日语）要真打
远藤 你要跟他们同流合污吗？
En-do, you're gonna side with them?
翻译 赶快翻译这句
Translate. Translate this.
问他要跟他们同流合污吗？
He's gonna side with them, really?
问他是不是真想给美国公司当摆设？
An American company selling their product off of his back like he's a mascot?
你又不是人家的玩物
You're not a mascot.
- 布莱恩 把他弄走 - 你是冠军你有权
- Brian, get him down. - You can throw that 'cause you're the winner.
咱们来场真的 观众想看真比赛
Let's give them a real game. They want a real game.
行了行了
Okay, okay.
谢谢 谢谢 该下一个环节了
Thank you, thank you. We need to move it along.
我下周没法去打世锦赛
I'm not gonna be at the championship next week
就是因为这混蛋作梗 我去不了了
'cause of this asshole. I'm not gonna be at the championship.
给我个机会 你已经让我丢脸了 丢大脸了
Give me a chance. You humiliated me. You roasted me.
求你了 求你了 远藤 求你
Please, please, Endo. Please.
- 拜托了 就当帮我 行吗？ - 好吧
- Please, for me. Yes? - Okay.
- 好 他同意了 - 好？他答应了？
- Yes. Okay. - Good? He says yes?
他同意了
He says yes.
谢谢你 远藤 谢谢
Thank you, Endo. Thank you.
他答应了 太好了
He said yes. Yes.
（日语）想不到
（日语）比赛竟然还要继续
（日语）欢呼过后 比赛再度开打
（日语）远藤再度对决
（日语）美国选手马蒂·毛瑟
- （日语）两位冠军的真刀真枪对决现在开始 - 这小畜生
This little fuck.
明白
Let's do this.
（日语）远藤先发球
（日语）比赛开打
该死
Fuck.
（日语）太好了
（日语）远藤 得分
（日语）1比0
马蒂 振作起来
Okay, Marty. All right.
别输给他 马蒂
Don't let him beat you, Marty.
（日语）拉锯战开始了
（日语）远藤好样的
i
（日语）又得一分
（日语）2比0
（日语）远藤发球
（日语）毛瑟也不甘示弱
（日语）马蒂·毛瑟 得分
（日语）远藤领先只剩一分
（日语）比分2比1
- （日语） 马蒂·毛瑟 再次得分 - 太好了
Yeah!
- （日语）目前比分2比2 平局 - 加油 马蒂 加油 小伙子
Yeah, Marty! Go boy!
（日语）毛瑟毫不退让
（日语）远藤加油 远藤加油 远藤加油
（日语）现在轮到毛瑟发球
（日语）远藤和马蒂都在全力以赴
（日语）现在比分是17比17 平局
（日语）比赛已经白热化
（日语）马蒂·毛瑟 得分
（日语）远藤失分了
（日语）被对手追上来了
（日语）追上来了一分
（日语）毛瑟领先一分
（日语）现在比分是18比17
- （日语）这才是真正的对决 大家给点掌声加油吧
- （日语）借过 借过
省省吧 我知道钱没戏了
You can save your breath. I know I'm not getting paid.
赢不赢都别想拿到钱 我倒是好奇你怎么回家
Win or lose, you get nothing. I wonder how you're gonna get home.
- 你别想坐我的飞机 - 无所谓
- You're not getting on my plane. - It doesn't matter, okay?
除非你打算叫停这活动 否则没有什么好说的
Unless you're planning on shutting down the event, we got nothing to discuss.
- 你真觉得这么简单吗？ - 对 我就这么觉得
- You think it's that simple? - Yeah, I do.
我来给你讲明白
Let me explain to you.
我生在1601年 是个吸血鬼 我活得太久了
I was born in 1601. I'm a vampire. I've been around forever.
我见过太多像你这样的马蒂
I've met many Marty Mausers over the centuries.
有人顶撞过我 有人不守规矩
Some of them crossed me, some weren't straight. They weren't honest.
而那些人我让他们永远受罪
And those are the ones that are still here.
你要是赢了 我会让你永远受罪
You go out and win that game, you're gonna be here forever too.
让你求生不得 求死不能
And you'll never be happy. You will never be happy.
好吧
All right.
好了 罗克韦尔先生
Okay, Mr. Rockwell.
（日语）休息结束 比赛继续
（日语）目前比分18比17
（日语）毛瑟领先一分
（日语）远藤加油 远藤加油 远藤加油
（日语）现在由远藤发球
（日语）开局不错
（日语）又是一轮拉锯战
（日语）漂亮
（日语）远藤 得一分
（日语）远藤终于把比分扳平
（日语）远藤加油 远藤加油 远藤加油
（日语）欢呼声越来越响亮了
（日语）目前比分是18比18
（日语）精彩继续
来吧
There we go!
（日语）可惜了 毛瑟得分
（日语）现在比分19比18
（日语）毛瑟毫不让步
（日语）又要发球了
（日语）打过去了
（日语）又被打回来了
（日语）打回去了
（日语）这球...远藤进攻成功
（日语）远藤又追平了
（日语）比分19比19
（日语）现场气氛越来越热闹了
（日语）比赛继续
（日语）远藤发球
（日语）击出
（日语）接得好
（日语）打得好
（日语）太精彩了
（日语）太惊心动魄了
（日语）20比19
（日语）远藤到达了赛点
（日语）日本观众们 一起为他加油吧
（日语）进入赛点 比赛更紧张精彩了
- （日语） 远藤能再得一分吗？ - 到赛点了
Match point.
（日语）大家拭目以待
（日语）远藤必胜
（日语）加油吧 毛瑟
（日语）加油吧
（日语）能接住吗？
（日语）仍在僵持
（日语）又是猛攻
（日语）天呐
（日语）马蒂·毛瑟
（日语）再次得分
（日语）再次扳回比分的是马蒂·毛瑟
（日语）20比20
（日语）20分后 远藤必须连拿两分才能获胜
（日语）现在由毛瑟发球
（日语）球差点擦网
（日语）双方都在用正手击球
（日语）现在换到反手了
（日语）马蒂·毛瑟正手得分
（日语）毛瑟拿到赛点
（日语）双方你追我赶
（日语）日本观众陷入了沉默
（日语）马蒂只要一分就能战胜远藤
（日语）远藤被逼到了绝境
（日语）毛瑟能撑住吗？
（日语）毛瑟撑住就能赢
（日语）接下来会发生什么？
- 别输给他 马蒂 - 马蒂 加油 加油
- Don't let him getcha, Marty! - Yeah, Marty! Go boy!
（日语）这是最后一球吗？
（日语）谁能笑到最后？
（日语）是毛瑟还是远藤？
（日语）最后一局了
（日语）远藤能撑住吗？
（日语）别眨眼
（日语）拉锯战又开始了
（日语）远藤处于劣势
（日语）要是毛瑟得分 远藤就输了
（日语）打回去了
（日语）打得异常激烈
（日语）胜负已分
（日语）获胜者是马蒂·毛瑟
（日语）精彩的对决
（日语）多么精彩的致胜一击
（日语）马蒂·毛瑟创造了历史
谢谢你
Thank you.
谢谢你 打得好 打得好
Thank you. Good game. Good game.
你真是个可敬的对手
You're a great player.
世锦赛你一定要加油 我真心希望你赢
Good luck at the championship, okay? I hope you win.
（日语）本场比赛获胜者是马蒂·毛瑟
贝尔维尤医院 有什么可以帮您？
Bellevue Hospital. May I help you?
喂 是的
Hi, yes.
请帮我转接瑞秋·米兹勒 谢谢
I was hoping to be connected with Rachel Mizler, please?
请问她在几楼？
Do you know what floor she's on?
她应该刚做完手术
Well, she would have gotten out of surgery.
应该待在安置术后病人的地方吧
So wherever you keep people like that.
我查一下
Okay.
这写着她昨晚被转到了产科病房
So it looks like she was moved to the maternity ward last night.
- 产科病房？ - 是的
- The maternity ward? - Yes.
- 为什么要去产科？ - 抱歉 我不清楚细节
- What do you mean, "the maternity ward"? - I'm sorry, I don't know the details.
她没事吧？她生了吗？预产期还有四周啊
Is she okay? Did she have the baby? She's not due for four weeks.
我只知道 她是被急送过去的...
This is all the information that I have, that she was rushed--
急送？什么意思？还转到了产科
"Rushed"? What are you saying, "rushed"? First you said, "moved,"
- 又急送 什么意思？ - 先生 请您冷静一下
- now you're saying, "rushed"? - Sir, can you please calm down?
直接帮我把电话转到产科 谢谢
Just put me through to the maternity ward, please.
- 爸爸 - 嘿
- Daddy! - Hey!
打扰一下 产科的病房在哪儿？
Excuse me. Maternity ward's here?
- 对 往前走 - 好 往前走 谢谢
- Yes, down the hall. - Down the hall. Thank you.
- 别走 先签名登记 - 不 不用 我是孩子他爸
- Sir, you need to sign in. - No, no. I'm the father.
嗨
Hi.
没事 睡吧 我在这 我在这 没事的
It's okay, sleep. I'm here. I'm here. It's okay.
别怕 我不会走的 我哪儿也不去
I'm right here. Don't worry, I'm not going anywhere.
继续睡吧
Go back to sleep.
我爱你
I love you.
米兹勒的
Mizler.
四号箱 对吧？
You said four, right?
要我抱起来给您看看吗？
Do you want me to pick him up?
跟爸爸打个招呼吧
Say hi to Daddy.
看那是爸爸 叫爸爸
Yeah, there he is. Say hi.
对 爸爸
Yes. Yeah.
♪ 欢迎来到这场人生 ♪
♪ Welcome to your life ♪
♪ 没有回头的路可走 ♪
♪ There's no turning back ♪
♪ 即使你在梦中沉睡 ♪
♪ Even while we sleep ♪
♪ 坏事也会不约而至 ♪
♪ We will find you ♪
字 幕 译 制
蒙太奇字幕组
翻译/校对/时间轴
小p
后期/翻译/时间轴
NickCollect
校对
Charlie
校对/技术支持
Frank
校对
十三
字 幕 许 可
CC BY‑NC‑SA 4.0
♪ 表面上装得彬彬有礼 ♪
♪ Acting on your best behaviour ♪
提莫西·查拉梅
格温妮斯·帕特洛
敖德萨·阿锡安
凯文·奥利里
泰勒·奥康马
主 演
一饰一
马蒂·毛瑟
退休女演员凯·斯通
已婚女性伴侣瑞秋
富商罗克韦尔
出租车司机沃利
♪ 却背弃了良知的呼唤 ♪
♪ Turn your back on Mother Nature ♪
♪ 人人都想主宰这世界 ♪
♪ Everybody wants to rule the world ♪
♪ 都怪我的选择 ♪
♪ It's my own design ♪
♪ 我是自作自受 ♪
♪ It's my own remorse ♪
♪ 帮我去决定 ♪
♪ Help me to decide ♪
♪ 帮我去得到 ♪
♪ Help me make the ♪
♪ 那自由和欢乐 ♪
♪ Most of freedom and of pleasure ♪
♪ 没什么能永远长存 ♪
♪ Nothing ever lasts forever ♪
♪ 人人都想主宰这世界 ♪
♪ Everybody wants to rule the world ♪
♪ 总有阳光照不到的黑暗 ♪
♪ There's a room where the light won't find you ♪
♪ 高墙总有崩塌的一天 ♪
♪ Holding hands while the walls come tumbling down ♪
♪ 当这一切发生时 我会站在你身后 ♪
♪ When they do, I'll be right behind you ♪
♪ 庆幸我们走到这一步 ♪
♪ So glad we've almost made it ♪
♪ 遗憾他们必须要放弃 ♪
♪ So sad they had to fade it ♪
♪ 人人都想主宰这世界 ♪
♪ Everybody wants to rule the world ♪
♪ 我受不了这动荡的人生 ♪
♪ I can't stand this indecision ♪
♪ 也受不了被命运套牢 ♪
♪ Married with a lack of vision ♪
♪ 人人都想主宰... ♪
♪ Everybody wants to rule the— ♪
♪ 说你永远 永远 永远不会需要 ♪
♪ Say that you'll never, never, never, never need it ♪
♪ 一个头条 凭什么去相信？ ♪
♪ One headline, why believe it? ♪
♪ 人人都想主宰这世界 ♪
♪ Everybody wants to rule the world ♪
♪ 为了享尽自由和欢乐 ♪
♪ All for freedom and for pleasure ♪
♪ 没什么能永远长存 ♪
♪ Nothing ever lasts forever ♪
♪ 人人都想主宰这世界 ♪
♪ Everybody wants to rule the world ♪
纽约中央影业
蒙太奇字幕组 (MontageSubs)
用爱发电 ♥ Powered by Love
A24影业